<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>衷深学习</title>
  <icon>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/1a78ec769217974f51d40169d81d53e1</icon>
  <subtitle>石晓强的小站</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-03-20T09:08:09.121Z</updated>
  <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>石晓强</name>
    <email>2583551979@qq.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -94</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/19/MY-100-Day-English-94/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/19/MY-100-Day-English-94/</id>
    <published>2021-03-19T06:42:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T09:08:09.121Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/images/cc_careers_highlighting-lines-16x9.jpg?itok=uq7Q68Gu"  alt="img"></p><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.sciencemag.org/careers/2016/03/how-seriously-read-scientific-paper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to (seriously) read a scientific paper</a></p></blockquote><p>Adam Ruben&#x2019;s tongue-in-cheek column about <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/careers/2016/01/how-read-scientific-paper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the common difficulties and frustrations of reading a scientific paper</a> broadly <strong>resonated</strong> (&#x5171;&#x9E23;&#xFF1B;&#x5171;&#x632F;) among <em>Science</em> Careers readers. Many of you have come to us asking for more (and more serious) advice on how to <u><strong>make sense of</strong></u> (&#x7406;&#x89E3;) the scientific literature, so we&#x2019;ve asked a dozen scientists at different career stages and in a broad range of fields to tell us how they do it. Although it is clear that reading scientific papers becomes easier with experience, the <strong>stumbling</strong> (&#x969C;&#x788D;&#x7684;) blocks are real, and it is up to each scientist to identify and apply the techniques that work best for them. The responses have been edited for clarity and brevity.</p><h2 id="How-do-you-approach-reading-a-paper"><a href="#How-do-you-approach-reading-a-paper" class="headerlink" title="How do you approach reading a paper?"></a>How do you approach reading a paper?</h2><p>I start by reading the abstract. Then, I skim the introduction and flip through the article to look at the figures. I try to identify the most prominent one or two figures, and I really make sure I understand what&#x2019;s going on in them. Then, I read the conclusion/summary. Only when I have done that will I go back into the technical details to clarify any questions I might have.<br>- <a href="http://enceladosaur.us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Jesse Shanahan</em></a><em>,</em> <u><em>master&#x2019;s candidate in astronomy</em></u> (&#x5929;&#x6587;&#x5B66;&#x7855;&#x58EB;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x751F;) <em>at Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut</em></p><p>I first get a general idea by reading the abstract and conclusions. The conclusions help me understand if the goal summarized in the abstract has been reached, and if the described work can be of interest for my own study. I also always look at plots/figures, as they help me get a first impression of a paper. Then I usually read the entire article from beginning to end, going through the sections in the order they appear so that I can follow the flow of work that the authors want to communicate.</p><p>If you want to make it a productive exercise, you need to have a clear idea of which kind of information you need to get in the first place, and then focus on that aspect. It could be to compare your results with the ones presented by the authors, put your own analysis into context, or extend it using the newly published data. Citation lists can help you decide why the paper may be most relevant to you by giving you a first impression of how colleagues that do similar research as you do may have used the paper.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      How to (seriously) read a scientific paper-1
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="Science" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/Science/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -93</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/18/MY-100-Day-English-93/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/18/MY-100-Day-English-93/</id>
    <published>2021-03-17T16:44:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T08:08:12.217Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210320144653.png"  alt></p><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><h3 id="Background"><a href="#Background" class="headerlink" title="Background"></a>Background</h3><p>Observational studies have identified height as a strong risk factor for <u>atrial fibrillation</u> (&#x623F;&#x98A4;), but this finding may be limited by <strong>residual</strong> (&#x6B8B;&#x4F59;&#x7684;) confounding. We aimed to examine genetic variation in height within the Mendelian randomization (MR) framework to determine whether height has a causal effect on risk of atrial fibrillation.</p><h3 id="Methods-and-findings"><a href="#Methods-and-findings" class="headerlink" title="Methods and findings"></a>Methods and findings</h3><p>In summary-level analyses, MR was performed using summary statistics from genome-wide association studies of height (GIANT/UK Biobank; 693,529 individuals) and atrial fibrillation (AFGen; 65,446 cases and 522,744 controls), finding that each 1-SD increase in genetically predicted height increased the odds of atrial fibrillation (odds ratio [OR] 1.34; 95% CI 1.29 to 1.40; <em>p</em> = 5 &#xD7; 10&#x2212;42). This result remained consistent in sensitivity analyses with MR methods that make different assumptions about the presence of pleiotropy, and when accounting for the effects of traditional cardiovascular risk factors on atrial fibrillation. Individual-level phenome-wide association studies of height and a height genetic risk score were performed among 6,567 European-ancestry participants of the Penn Medicine Biobank (median age at enrollment 63 years, interquartile range 55&#x2013;72; 38% female; recruitment 2008&#x2013;2015), confirming prior observational associations between height and atrial fibrillation. Individual-level MR confirmed that each 1-SD increase in height increased the odds of atrial fibrillation, including adjustment for clinical and echocardiographic confounders (OR 1.89; 95% CI 1.50 to 2.40; <em>p</em> = 0.007). The main limitations of this study include potential bias from pleiotropic effects of genetic variants, and lack of generalizability of individual-level findings to non-European populations.</p><h3 id="Conclusions"><a href="#Conclusions" class="headerlink" title="Conclusions"></a>Conclusions</h3><p>In this study, we observed evidence that height is likely a positive causal risk factor for atrial fibrillation. Further study is needed to determine whether risk prediction tools including height or anthropometric risk factors can be used to improve screening and primary prevention of atrial fibrillation, and whether biological pathways involved in height may offer new targets for treatment of atrial fibrillation.</p><p>&#x79C1;&#x7528;&#x5B5F;&#x5FB7;&#x5C14;&#x968F;&#x673A;&#x5316;&#x5206;&#x6790;&#x8BC1;&#x660E;&#xFF1A;&#x8EAB;&#x9AD8;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x662F;&#x5BFC;&#x81F4;&#x623F;&#x98A4;&#x7684;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x5371;&#x9669;&#x56E0;&#x7D20;&#x3002;</p><h2 id="Author-summary"><a href="#Author-summary" class="headerlink" title="Author summary"></a>Author summary</h2><h3 id="Why-was-this-study-done"><a href="#Why-was-this-study-done" class="headerlink" title="Why was this study done?"></a>Why was this study done?</h3><ul><li>Studies have identified height as a risk factor for atrial fibrillation, a common abnormal heart rhythm.</li><li>Whether being taller actually elevates risk of atrial fibrillation, or if this association is an artifact of prior study designs, remains unclear.</li></ul><h3 id="What-did-the-researchers-do-and-find"><a href="#What-did-the-researchers-do-and-find" class="headerlink" title="What did the researchers do and find?"></a>What did the researchers do and find?</h3><ul><li>We examined randomly allocated genetic variants associated with height within the Mendelian randomization framework to study the effects of height on risk of atrial fibrillation.</li><li>Genetic variants associated with taller stature were also associated with increased risk of atrial fibrillation. This finding was consistent across multiple analysis methods, including when accounting for other known atrial fibrillation risk factors.</li></ul><h3 id="What-do-these-findings-mean"><a href="#What-do-these-findings-mean" class="headerlink" title="What do these findings mean?"></a>What do these findings mean?</h3><ul><li>Taller individuals are likely to be at increased risk of atrial fibrillation.</li><li>Future research is needed to better define the pathways connecting height to atrial fibrillation.</li></ul><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Genetics of height and risk of atrial fibrillation - A Mendelian randomization study
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="MR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/MR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -92</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/17/MY-100-Day-English-92/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/17/MY-100-Day-English-92/</id>
    <published>2021-03-16T16:44:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T06:41:32.830Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>It&#x2019;s crucial to take a sense of humility into the world. By the time you make it to a top graduate school, almost all your learning has come from people who are smarter and more experienced than you: parents, teachers, bosses. But once you&#x2019;ve finished at Harvard Business School or any other top academic institution, the vast majority of people you&#x2019;ll interact with on a day-to-day basis may not be smarter than you. And if your attitude is that only smarter people have something to teach you, your learning opportunities will be very limited. But if you have a humble eagerness to learn something from everybody, your learning opportunities will be unlimited. Generally, you can be humble only if you feel really good about yourself&#x2014;and you want to help those around you feel really good about themselves, too. When we see people acting in an <strong>abusive</strong> (&#x8FB1;&#x9A82;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x6EE5;&#x7528;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x8650;&#x5F85;&#x7684;), arrogant, or <strong>demeaning</strong> (&#x8D2C;&#x4F4E;) manner toward others, their behavior almost always is a symptom of their lack of self-esteem. They need to put someone else down to feel good about themselves.</p><h2 id="Choose-the-Right-Yardstick-&#x5C3A;&#x5EA6;"><a href="#Choose-the-Right-Yardstick-&#x5C3A;&#x5EA6;" class="headerlink" title="Choose the Right Yardstick (&#x5C3A;&#x5EA6;)"></a>Choose the Right Yardstick (&#x5C3A;&#x5EA6;)</h2><p>This past year I was diagnosed with cancer and faced the possibility that my life would end sooner than I&#x2019;d planned. Thankfully, it now looks as if I&#x2019;ll be <strong>spared</strong> (&#x5E78;&#x514D;,&#x5907;&#x4EFD;&#x7684;). But the experience has given me important insight into my life.</p><p>I have a pretty clear idea of how my ideas have generated enormous revenue for companies that have used my research; I know I&#x2019;ve had a substantial impact. But as I&#x2019;ve confronted this disease, it&#x2019;s been interesting to see how unimportant that impact is to me now. I&#x2019;ve concluded that the metric by which God will assess my life isn&#x2019;t dollars but the individual people whose lives I&#x2019;ve touched (&#x53D7;&#x611F;&#x52A8;&#x7684;).</p><p>I think that&#x2019;s the way it will work for us all. Don&#x2019;t worry about the level of individual <strong>prominence</strong> (&#x5353;&#x8D8A;) you have achieved; worry about the individuals you have helped become better people. This is my final recommendation: Think about the metric by which your life will be judged, and make a <strong>resolution</strong> (&#x51B3;&#x5FC3;,&#x89E3;&#x51B3;) to live every day so that in the end, your life will be judged a success.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-11
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -91</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/16/MY-100-Day-English-91/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/16/MY-100-Day-English-91/</id>
    <published>2021-03-15T16:44:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T06:29:14.129Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>I&#x2019;m a deeply religious man, so I went away and prayed about what I should do. I got a very clear feeling that I shouldn&#x2019;t break my commitment&#x2014;so I didn&#x2019;t play in the championship game.</p><p>In many ways that was a small decision&#x2014;involving one of several thousand Sundays in my life. In theory, surely I could have crossed over the line just that one time and then not done it again. But looking back on it, resisting the <strong>temptation</strong> (&#x5F15;&#x8BF1;&#xFF1B;&#x8BF1;&#x60D1;&#x7269;) whose logic was &#x201C;In this <strong>extenuating</strong> (&#x60C5;&#x6709;&#x53EF;&#x539F;&#x7684;) circumstance, just this once, it&#x2019;s OK&#x201D; has proven to be one of the most important decisions of my life. Why? My life has been one <strong>unending</strong> (&#x65E0;&#x5C3D;&#x7684;) stream of extenuating circumstances. Had I crossed the line that one time, I would have done it over and over in the years that followed.</p><p>The lesson I learned from this is that it&#x2019;s easier to hold to your principles 100% of the time than it is to hold to them 98% of the time. If you give in to &#x201C;just this once,&#x201D; based on a marginal cost analysis, as some of my former classmates have done, you&#x2019;ll regret where you end up. You&#x2019;ve got to define for yourself what you stand for and draw the line in a safe place.</p><h2 id="Remember-the-Importance-of-Humility"><a href="#Remember-the-Importance-of-Humility" class="headerlink" title="Remember the Importance of Humility"></a>Remember the Importance of Humility</h2><p>I got this insight when I was asked to teach a class on humility at Harvard College. I asked all the students to describe the most humble person they knew. One characteristic of these humble people stood out: They had a high level of self-esteem. They knew who they were, and they felt good about who they were. We also decided that humility was defined not by <u>self-deprecating</u> (&#x81EA;&#x8D2C;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x8C26;&#x865A;&#x7684;) behavior or attitudes but by the esteem with which you regard others. Good behavior flows naturally from that kind of humility. For example, you would never steal from someone, because you respect that person too much. You&#x2019;d never lie to someone, either.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-10
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -90</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/15/MY-100-Day-English-90/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/15/MY-100-Day-English-90/</id>
    <published>2021-03-14T16:18:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T04:21:26.474Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h2 id="Avoid-the-&#x201C;Marginal-Costs&#x201D;-Mistake"><a href="#Avoid-the-&#x201C;Marginal-Costs&#x201D;-Mistake" class="headerlink" title="Avoid the &#x201C;Marginal Costs&#x201D; Mistake"></a>Avoid the &#x201C;Marginal Costs&#x201D; Mistake</h2><p>We&#x2019;re taught in finance and economics that in evaluating alternative investments, we should ignore <u>sunk and fixed costs</u> (&#x6C89;&#x6CA1;&#x548C;&#x56FA;&#x5B9A;&#x6210;&#x672C;), and instead base decisions on the marginal costs and marginal revenues that each alternative <strong>entails</strong> (&#x5F15;&#x8D77;&#xFF0C;&#x9700;&#x8981;). We learn in our course that this <strong>doctrine</strong> (&#x4E3B;&#x4E49;&#xFF1B;&#x5B66;&#x8BF4;&#xFF1B;&#x6559;&#x4E49;) biases companies to leverage what they have put in place to succeed in the past, instead of guiding them to create the capabilities they&#x2019;ll need in the future. If we knew the future would be exactly the same as the past, that approach would be fine. But if the future&#x2019;s different&#x2014;and it almost always is&#x2014;then it&#x2019;s the wrong thing to do.</p><p>This theory addresses the third question I discuss with my students&#x2014;how to live a life of integrity (stay out of jail). Unconsciously, we often employ the marginal cost doctrine in our personal lives when we choose between right and wrong. A voice in our head says, &#x201C;Look, I know that as a general rule, most people shouldn&#x2019;t do this. But in this particular <u>extenuating circumstance,</u> (&#x60C5;&#x6709;&#x53EF;&#x539F;&#x7684;&#x60C5;&#x51B5;) just this once, it&#x2019;s OK.&#x201D; The marginal cost of doing something wrong &#x201C;just this once&#x201D; always seems <strong>alluringly</strong> (&#x8BF1;&#x4EBA;&#x5730;) low. It suckers (&#x5438;) you in, and you don&#x2019;t ever look at where that path ultimately is headed and at the full costs that the choice entails. Justification for <strong>infidelity</strong> (&#x65E0;&#x4FE1;&#x4EF0;) and dishonesty in all their <strong>manifestations</strong> (&#x8868;&#x73B0;) lies in the marginal cost economics of &#x201C;just this once.&#x201D;</p><p>I&#x2019;d like to share a story about how I came to understand the potential damage of &#x201C;just this once&#x201D; in my own life. I played on the Oxford University <strong>varsity</strong> (&#x5927;&#x5B66;&#xFF1B;&#x5927;&#x5B66;&#x8FD0;&#x52A8;&#x4EE3;&#x8868;&#x961F;) basketball team. <u><strong>We worked our tails off</strong> and finished the season undefeated</u> (&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x7AED;&#x5C3D;&#x5168;&#x529B;&#xFF0C;&#x5B8C;&#x6210;&#x4E86;&#x4E0D;&#x8D25;&#x7684;&#x8D5B;&#x5B63;). The guys on the team were the best friends I&#x2019;ve ever had in my life. We got to the British <strong>equivalent</strong> (&#x76F8;&#x7B49;&#x7684;) of the NCAA <strong>tournament</strong> (&#x9526;&#x6807;&#x8D5B;&#xFF0C;&#x8054;&#x8D5B;)&#x2014;and made it to the final four. It turned out the championship game was scheduled to be played on a Sunday. I had made a personal commitment to God at age 16 that I would never play ball on Sunday. So I went to the coach and explained my problem. He was <strong>incredulous</strong> (&#x6000;&#x7591;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x96BE;&#x4EE5;&#x7F6E;&#x4FE1;&#x7684;). My teammates were, too, because I was the starting center. Every one of the guys on the team came to me and said, &#x201C;You&#x2019;ve got to play. Can&#x2019;t you break the rule just this one time?&#x201D;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-9
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -89</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/14/MY-100-Day-English-89/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/14/MY-100-Day-English-89/</id>
    <published>2021-03-14T13:17:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T04:05:32.842Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>The theory arrays these tools along two dimensions&#x2014;the extent to which members of the organization agree on what they want from their participation in the enterprise, and the extent to which they agree on what actions will produce the desired results. When there is little agreement on both axes, you have to use &#x201C;power tools&#x201D;&#x2014;<strong>coercion</strong> (&#x5F3A;&#x5236;&#xFF1B;&#x5F3A;&#x8FEB;), threats, punishment, and so on&#x2014;to secure cooperation. Many companies start in this <strong>quadrant</strong> (&#x8C61;&#x9650;), which is why <u>the founding executive team</u> (&#x521B;&#x59CB;&#x6267;&#x884C;&#x56E2;&#x961F;) must play such an <strong>assertive</strong> (&#x72EC;&#x65AD;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x80AF;&#x5B9A;&#x7684;) role in defining what must be done and how. If employees&#x2019; ways of working together to address those tasks succeed over and over, consensus begins to form. MIT&#x2019;s Edgar Schein has described this process as the mechanism by which a culture is built. Ultimately, people don&#x2019;t even think about whether their way of doing things yields success. They embrace priorities and follow procedures by instinct and assumption rather than by explicit decision&#x2014;which means that they&#x2019;ve created a culture. Culture, in <strong>compelling</strong> (&#x5F15;&#x4EBA;&#x6CE8;&#x76EE;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x4EE4;&#x4EBA;&#x4FE1;&#x670D;&#x7684;) but unspoken ways, <strong>dictates</strong> (&#x89C4;&#x5B9A;) the proven (&#x88AB;&#x9A8C;&#x8BC1;&#x7684;), acceptable methods by which members of the group address recurrent problems. And culture defines the priority given to different types of problems. It can be a powerful management tool.</p><p>In using this model to address the question, How can I be sure that my family becomes an enduring source of happiness?, my students quickly see that the simplest tools that parents can wield to elicit cooperation from children are <u>power tools</u> (&#x7535;&#x52A8;&#x5DE5;&#x5177;). But there comes a point during the teen years when power tools no longer work. At that point parents start wishing that they had begun working with their children at a very young age to build a culture at home in which children instinctively behave respectfully toward one another, <strong>obey</strong> (&#x670D;&#x4ECE;) their parents, and choose the right thing to do. Families have cultures, just as companies do. Those cultures can be built consciously or evolve (&#x8FDB;&#x5316;) <strong>inadvertently</strong> (&#x65E0;&#x610F;&#x5730;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0D;&#x7ECF;&#x610F;&#x5730;).</p><p>If you want your kids to have strong self-esteem and confidence that they can solve hard problems, those qualities won&#x2019;t magically materialize in high school. You have to design them into your family&#x2019;s culture&#x2014;and you have to think about this very <strong><u>early on</u></strong> (&#x5728;&#x65E9;&#x671F;). Like employees, children build self-esteem by doing things that are hard and learning what works.</p><p>*<em>inadvertently: *</em> &#x65E0;&#x610F;&#x5730;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0D;&#x7ECF;&#x610F;&#x5730; (unconsciousness)</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-8
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -88</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/13/MY-100-Day-English-88/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/13/MY-100-Day-English-88/</id>
    <published>2021-03-13T13:17:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T03:46:35.450Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>When people who have a high need for achievement&#x2014;and that includes all Harvard Business School graduates&#x2014;have an extra half hour of time or an extra ounce of energy, they&#x2019;ll unconsciously allocate it to activities that yield the most <strong>tangible</strong> (&#x6709;&#x578B;&#x7684;) accomplishments (&#x9020;&#x8BE3;&#xFF0C;&#x6210;&#x5C31;). And our careers provide the most <strong><u>concrete evidence</u></strong> (&#x786E;&#x51FF;&#x7684;&#x8BC1;&#x636E;&#xFF1B;&#x5177;&#x4F53;&#x7684;&#x8BC1;&#x636E;) that we&#x2019;re moving forward. You ship a product, finish a design, complete a presentation, <u>close a sale</u> (&#x6210;&#x4EA4;), teach a class, publish a paper, get paid, get promoted. In contrast, investing time and energy in your relationship with your spouse and children typically doesn&#x2019;t offer that same immediate sense of achievement. Kids <strong>misbehave</strong> (&#x884C;&#x4E3A;&#x4E0D;&#x7AEF;&#xFF0C;&#x4E3E;&#x6B62;&#x5931;&#x793C;) every day. It&#x2019;s really not until 20 years <u>down the road</u> (&#x5728;&#x8DEF;&#x8FB9;&#xFF1B;&#x4E00;&#x6BB5;&#x65F6;&#x95F4;&#x4E4B;&#x540E;) that you can put your hands on your <strong>hips</strong> (&#x81C0;&#x90E8;) and say, &#x201C;I raised a good son or a good daughter.&#x201D; You can neglect your relationship with your spouse, and on a day-to-day basis, it doesn&#x2019;t seem as if things are <strong>deteriorating</strong> (&#x9000;&#x5316;&#xFF0C;&#x6076;&#x5316;). People who are driven to excel have this unconscious <strong>propensity</strong> (&#x503E;&#x5411;&#xFF0C;&#x4E60;&#x6027;) to underinvest in their families and overinvest in their careers&#x2014;even though intimate and loving relationships with their families are the most powerful and enduring source of happiness.</p><p>If you study the root causes of business disasters, over and over you&#x2019;ll find this predisposition (&#x503E;&#x5411;&#xFF1B;&#x7D20;&#x8D28;&#xFF1B;&#x6613;&#x67D3;&#x75C5;&#x4F53;&#x8D28;) toward endeavors (&#x52AA;&#x529B;) that offer <strong><u>immediate gratification</u></strong> (&#x5373;&#x65F6;&#x6EE1;&#x8DB3;). If you look at personal lives through that lens, you&#x2019;ll see the same stunning (&#x9707;&#x60CA;&#x7684;) and <strong>sobering</strong> (&#x4F7F;&#x6E05;&#x9192;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x4F7F;&#x51B7;&#x9759;&#x7684;) pattern: people allocating fewer and fewer resources to the things they would have once said mattered most.</p><h2 id="Create-a-Culture"><a href="#Create-a-Culture" class="headerlink" title="Create a Culture"></a>Create a Culture</h2><p>There&#x2019;s an important model in our class called the Tools of Cooperation, which basically says that being a visionary manager isn&#x2019;t all it&#x2019;s <u><strong>cracked up</strong></u> (&#x5439;&#x6367;&#xFF0C;&#x8D5E;&#x626C;) to be. It&#x2019;s one thing to see into the foggy future with <strong>acuity</strong> (&#x654F;&#x9510;) and <strong>chart</strong> (&#x7ED8;&#x5236;&#xFF0C;&#x8BA1;&#x5212;&#xFF0C;&#x56FE;&#x8868;) the <u>course corrections</u> (&#x8FDB;&#x7A0B;&#x4FEE;&#x6B63;&#xFF0C;&#x822A;&#x7EBF;&#x4FEE;&#x6B63;) that the company must make. <u>But it&#x2019;s quite another</u> (&#x4F46;&#x8FD9;&#x5B8C;&#x5168;&#x662F;&#x53E6;&#x4E00;&#x56DE;&#x4E8B;) to persuade employees who might not see the changes ahead to line up and work cooperatively to take the company in that new direction. Knowing what tools to <strong>wield</strong> (&#x4F7F;&#x7528;&#xFF1B;&#x884C;&#x4F7F;) to <strong>elicit</strong> (&#x5F15;&#x51FA;) the needed cooperation is a critical managerial skill.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-7
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -87</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/12/MY-100-Day-English-87/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/12/MY-100-Day-English-87/</id>
    <published>2021-03-12T15:11:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T13:42:09.408Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>Had I instead spent that hour each day learning the latest techniques for mastering the problems of autocorrelation in regression analysis, I would have badly misspent (&#x6EE5;&#x7528;&#xFF1B;&#x865A;&#x5EA6;&#xFF1B;&#x6D6A;&#x8D39;) my life. I apply the tools of econometrics a few times a year, but I apply my knowledge of the purpose of my life every day. It&#x2019;s the single most useful thing I&#x2019;ve ever learned. <strong><u>I promise my students that if they take the time to figure out their life purpose, they&#x2019;ll look back on it as the most important thing they discovered at HBS</u></strong> (&#x6211;&#x5411;&#x6211;&#x7684;&#x5B66;&#x751F;&#x4EEC;&#x4FDD;&#x8BC1;&#xFF0C;&#x5982;&#x679C;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x82B1;&#x65F6;&#x95F4;&#x53BB;&#x601D;&#x8003;&#x81EA;&#x5DF1;&#x7684;&#x4EBA;&#x751F;&#x76EE;&#x6807;&#xFF0C;&#x5F53;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x56DE;&#x5934;&#x770B;&#x65F6;&#xFF0C;&#x4F1A;&#x8BA4;&#x4E3A;&#x8FD9;&#x662F;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x5728;&#x54C8;&#x4F5B;&#x5546;&#x5B66;&#x9662;&#x53D1;&#x73B0;&#x7684;&#x6700;&#x91CD;&#x8981;&#x7684;&#x4E8B;&#x60C5;&#x3002;). If they don&#x2019;t figure it out, they will just <u>sail off</u> (&#x51FA;&#x6D77;&#xFF0C;&#x822A;&#x884C;) without a <strong>rudder</strong> ( &#x8239;&#x8235;) and get <strong>buffeted</strong> (&#x88AB;&#x51B2;&#x51FB;&#x7684;) in the very rough seas of life. <u>Clarity about their purpose will <strong>trump</strong> (&#x80DC;&#x8FC7;) knowledge of activity-based costing, balanced scorecards, core competence, disruptive innovation (&#x98A0;&#x8986;&#x5F0F;&#x521B;&#x65B0;), the four Ps, and the five forces.</u> &#x660E;&#x786E;&#x4EBA;&#x751F;&#x76EE;&#x6807;&#x662F;&#x6700;&#x503C;&#x5F97;&#x82B1;&#x65F6;&#x95F4;&#xFF0C;&#x6700;&#x91CD;&#x8981;&#x7684;&#x3002;</p><p>My purpose grew out of my religious faith, but faith isn&#x2019;t the only thing that gives people direction. For example, one of my former students decided that his purpose was to bring honesty and economic prosperity to his country and to raise children who were as <strong>capably</strong> (&#x53C8;&#x80FD;&#x529B;&#x7684;) <u>committed to</u> (&#x81F4;&#x529B;&#xFF0C;&#x4ECE;&#x4E8B;) this <strong>cause</strong> (&#x4E8B;&#x4E1A;&#xFF0C;&#x76EE;&#x6807;), and to each other, as he was. His purpose is focused on family and others&#x2014;as mine is.<br>The choice and successful pursuit of a profession is but one tool for achieving your purpose. But without a purpose, life can become <strong>hollow</strong> (&#x7A7A;&#x6D1E;&#x7684;).</p><h2 id="Allocate-Your-Resources"><a href="#Allocate-Your-Resources" class="headerlink" title="Allocate Your Resources"></a>Allocate Your Resources</h2><p><strong><u>Your decisions about allocating your personal time, energy, and talent ultimately shape your life&#x2019;s strategy</u></strong>.</p><p>I have a bunch of &#x201C;businesses&#x201D; that compete for these resources: I&#x2019;m trying to have a rewarding relationship with my wife, raise great kids, contribute to my community, succeed in my career, contribute to my church, and so on. And I have exactly the same problem that a corporation does. I have a limited amount of time and energy and talent. How much do I devote to each of these pursuits?</p><p>Allocation choices can make your life turn out to be very different from what you intended. Sometimes that&#x2019;s good: Opportunities that you never planned for emerge. But if you misinvest your resources, the outcome can be bad. As I think about my former classmates who <strong>inadvertently</strong> (&#x65E0;&#x610F;&#x5730;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0D;&#x7ECF;&#x610F;&#x5730;) invested for <u>lives of hollow unhappiness</u> (&#x7A7A;&#x6D1E;&#x7684;&#x4E0D;&#x5FEB;&#x4E50;&#x7684;&#x751F;&#x6D3B;), I can&#x2019;t help believing that their troubles relate right back to a short-term perspective.</p><p>&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x95EE;&#x9898;&#x4E0E;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x77ED;&#x89C6;&#x6709;&#x5173;&#x3002;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-6
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -86</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/11/MY-100-Day-English-86/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/11/MY-100-Day-English-86/</id>
    <published>2021-03-10T18:09:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T13:16:52.820Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>Over the years I&#x2019;ve watched the fates of my HBS classmates from 1979 unfold; I&#x2019;ve seen more and more of them come to reunions unhappy, divorced, and <strong>alienated</strong> (&#x758F;&#x8FDC;) from their children. I can guarantee you that not a single one of them graduated with the <strong>deliberate</strong> (&#x6545;&#x610F;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x6DF1;&#x601D;&#x719F;&#x8651;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x4ECE;&#x5BB9;&#x7684;) strategy of getting divorced and raising children who would become <strong>estranged</strong> (&#x758F;&#x8FDC;&#x7684;) from them. And yet a shocking number of them implemented that strategy. The reason? They didn&#x2019;t keep the purpose of their lives front and center as they decided how to spend their time, talents, and energy.</p><p>It&#x2019;s quite startling that a significant fraction of the 900 students that HBS <strong>draws</strong> (&#x5438;&#x5F15;&#xFF0C;&#x62DB;&#x751F;) each year from the world&#x2019;s best have given little thought to the purpose of their lives. I tell the students that HBS might be one of their last chances to reflect deeply on that question. If they think that they&#x2019;ll have more time and energy to reflect later, they&#x2019;re <strong>nuts</strong> (&#x75AF;&#x4E86;&#xFF0C;&#x575A;&#x679C;), because life only gets more demanding: You take on a mortgage; you&#x2019;re working 70 hours a week; you have a spouse and children.</p><p>For me, having a clear purpose in my life has been essential. But it was something I had to think long and hard about before I understood it. When I was a Rhodes scholar, I was in a very <strong>demanding</strong> (&#x82DB;&#x523B;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x8981;&#x6C42;&#x9AD8;&#x7684;) academic program, trying to <strong>cram</strong> (&#x586B;&#x6EE1;&#xFF0C;&#x585E;&#x6EE1;) an extra year&#x2019;s worth of work into my time at Oxford. I decided to spend an hour every night reading, thinking, and <u>praying about</u> (&#x7948;&#x7977;) why God put me on this earth. That was a very challenging commitment to keep, because every hour I spent doing that, I wasn&#x2019;t studying <u>applied econometrics</u> (&#x5E94;&#x7528;&#x8BA1;&#x91CF;&#x7ECF;&#x6D4E;&#x5B66;). I was conflicted about whether I could really afford to take that time away from my studies, but I <u>stuck with</u> (&#x88AB;&#x8FEB;&#x63A5;&#x53D7;&#xFF1B;&#x65E0;&#x6CD5;&#x6446;&#x8131;) it&#x2014;and ultimately figured out the purpose of my life.</p><p><strong>Doing deals (&#x8FBE;&#x6210;&#x4EA4;&#x6613;) doesn&#x2019;t yield the deep rewards that come from building up people.</strong></p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-5
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -85</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/10/MY-100-Day-English-85/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/10/MY-100-Day-English-85/</id>
    <published>2021-03-09T17:15:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T13:16:48.335Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>One of the theories that gives great insight on the first question&#x2014;how to be sure we find happiness in our careers&#x2014;is from Frederick Herzberg, who asserts that the powerful motivator in our lives isn&#x2019;t money; it&#x2019;s the opportunity to learn, grow in responsibilities, contribute to others, and be recognized for achievements. I tell the students about <u>a vision of sorts</u> (&#x5404;&#x79CD;&#x5404;&#x6837;&#x7684;&#x613F;&#x666F;) I had while I was running the company I founded before becoming an academic. In my mind&#x2019;s eye I saw one of my managers leave for work one morning with a relatively strong level of self-esteem. Then I pictured her driving home to her family 10 hours later, feeling unappreciated, frustrated, underutilized, and <strong>demeaned</strong> (&#x8D2C;&#x4F4E;&#x2026;&#x7684;&#x8EAB;&#x4EFD;&#xFF1B;&#x4F7F;&#x2026;&#x5931;&#x53BB;&#x5C0A;&#x4E25;). I imagined how profoundly her lowered self-esteem affected the way she interacted with her children. The vision in my mind then <strong>fast-forwarded</strong> (&#x5FEB;&#x8FDB;) to another day, when she drove home with greater self-esteem&#x2014;feeling that she had learned a lot, been recognized for achieving valuable things, and played a significant role in the success of some important <strong>initiatives</strong> (&#x4E3E;&#x63AA;&#xFF0C;&#x65B9;&#x6848;). I then imagined how positively that affected her as a spouse and a parent. My conclusion: Management is the most noble of professions if it&#x2019;s practiced well. No other occupation offers as many ways to help others learn and grow, take responsibility and be recognized for achievement, and contribute to the success of a team. More and more MBA students come to school thinking that a career in business means buying, selling, and investing in companies. That&#x2019;s unfortunate. Doing deals doesn&#x2019;t yield the deep rewards that come from <u>building up people</u> (&#x57F9;&#x517B;&#x4EBA;).</p><p>I want students to leave my classroom knowing that.</p><h2 id="Create-a-Strategy-for-Your-Life"><a href="#Create-a-Strategy-for-Your-Life" class="headerlink" title="Create a Strategy for Your Life"></a>Create a Strategy for Your Life</h2><p>A theory that is helpful in answering the second question&#x2014;How can I ensure that my relationship with my family proves to be an enduring source of happiness?&#x2014;concerns how strategy is defined and implemented. Its primary insight is that a company&#x2019;s strategy is determined by the types of initiatives that management invests in. If a company&#x2019;s resource allocation process is not managed masterfully, what emerges from it can be very different from what management intended. Because companies&#x2019; decision-making systems are designed to <strong>steer</strong> (&#x63A7;&#x5236;&#xFF0C;&#x5F15;&#x5BFC;&#xFF0C;&#x638C;&#x8235;) investments to initiatives that offer the most tangible and immediate returns, companies <strong>shortchange</strong>  (&#x5C11;&#x652F;&#x4ED8;) investments in initiatives that are crucial to their long-term strategies.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-4
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -84</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/09/MY-100-Day-English-84/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/09/MY-100-Day-English-84/</id>
    <published>2021-03-08T17:15:20.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T13:16:42.413Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>My class at HBS is structured to help my students understand what good management theory is and how it is built. To that backbone I attach different models or theories that help students think about the various dimensions of a general manager&#x2019;s job in stimulating innovation and growth. In each session we look at one company through the lenses of those theories&#x2014;using them to explain how the company got into its situation and to examine what managerial actions will yield the needed results.</p><p>On the last day of class, I ask my students to turn those theoretical <strong>lenses</strong> (&#x955C;&#x5934;) on themselves, to find <strong>cogent</strong> (&#x6709;&#x8BF4;&#x670D;&#x529B;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x4EE4;&#x4EBA;&#x4FE1;&#x670D;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x6E05;&#x6670;&#x7684;) answers to three questions: First, how can I be sure that I&#x2019;ll be happy in my career? Second, how can I be sure that my relationships with my spouse and my family become an enduring source of happiness? Third, how can I be sure I&#x2019;ll stay out of <strong>jail</strong> (&#x76D1;&#x72F1;&#xFF1B;&#x76D1;&#x7262;)? Though the last question sounds <strong>lighthearted</strong> (&#x8F7B;&#x677E;&#xFF0C;&#x8F7B;&#x5FEB;), it&#x2019;s not. Two of the 32 people in my Rhodes scholar class spent time in jail. Jeff Skilling of Enron fame was a classmate of mine at HBS. These were good guys&#x2014;but something in their lives sent them off in the wrong direction.</p><p>As the students discuss the answers to these questions, I open my own life to them as a case study <u>of sorts</u> (&#x5404;&#x79CD;&#x5404;&#x6837;&#x7684;), to illustrate how they can use the theories from our course to guide their life decisions.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-3
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -83</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/08/MY-100-Day-English-83/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/08/MY-100-Day-English-83/</id>
    <published>2021-03-07T17:14:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T11:48:09.619Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><strong>Before I published The Innovator&#x2019;s</strong> Dilemma, I got a call from Andrew Grove, then the chairman of Intel. He had read one of my early papers about disruptive (&#x7834;&#x574F;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x5206;&#x88C2;&#x6027;&#x7684;) technology, and he asked if I could talk to his <u><strong>direct reports</strong></u> (&#x76F4;&#x63A5;&#x4E0B;&#x5C5E;) and explain my research and what it implied for Intel. Excited, I flew to Silicon Valley and showed up at the appointed time, only to have Grove say, &#x201C;Look, stuff has happened. We have only 10 minutes for you. Tell us what your model of disruption means for Intel.&#x201D; I said that I couldn&#x2019;t&#x2014;that I needed a full 30 minutes to explain the model, because only with it as context would any comments about Intel make sense. Ten minutes into my explanation, Grove interrupted: &#x201C;Look, I&#x2019;ve got your model. Just tell us what it means for Intel.&#x201D;</p><p>I insisted that I needed 10 more minutes to describe how the process of disruption had worked its way through a very different industry, steel, so that he and his team could understand how disruption worked. I told the story of how Nucor and other steel minimills had begun by attacking the lowest end of the market&#x2014;steel reinforcing bars, or <strong>rebar</strong> (&#x94A2;&#x7B4B;)&#x2014;and later moved up toward the high end, undercutting (&#x51FB;&#x8D25;) the traditional steel mills.</p><p>When I finished the minimill story, Grove said, &#x201C;OK, I get it. What it means for Intel is&#x2026;,&#x201D; and then went on to articulate what would become the company&#x2019;s strategy for going to the bottom of the market to launch the Celeron processor.</p><p>I&#x2019;ve thought about that a million times since. If I had <u>been suckered into</u> (&#x88AB;&#x8FF7;&#x60D1;&#x4F4F;&#xFF0C;&#x9677;&#x5165;) telling Andy Grove what he should think about the microprocessor business, I&#x2019;d have been killed. But instead of telling him what to think, I taught him how to think&#x2014;and then he reached what I felt was the correct decision on his own.</p><p>That experience had a profound influence on me. When people ask what I think they should do, I rarely answer their question directly. Instead, I run the question aloud through one of my models. I&#x2019;ll describe how the process in the model worked its way through an industry quite different from their own. And then, more often than not, they&#x2019;ll say, &#x201C;OK, I get it.&#x201D; And they&#x2019;ll answer their own question more insightfully than I could have.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -82</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/07/MY-100-Day-English-82/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/07/MY-100-Day-English-82/</id>
    <published>2021-03-07T03:07:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-13T04:26:21.472Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2008/01/05Jul10_Christensen_measure-your-life.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><strong>Summary.</strong>  Harvard Business School&#x2019;s Christensen teaches aspiring MBAs how to apply management and innovation theories to build stronger companies. But he also believes that these models can help people lead better lives. In this article, he explains how, exploring questions everyone needs to ask: How can I be happy in my career? How can I be sure that my relationship with my family is an enduring source of happiness? And how can I live my life with <strong>integrity</strong> (&#x6B63;&#x76F4;)?</p><p>The answer to the first question comes from Frederick Herzberg&#x2019;s assertion that the most powerful motivator isn&#x2019;t money; it&#x2019;s the opportunity to learn, grow in responsibilities, contribute, and be recognized (&#x8BA4;&#x53EF;). That&#x2019;s why management, if practiced well, can be the noblest (&#x6700;&#x9AD8;&#x8D35;&#x7684;) of occupations; no others offer as many ways to help people find those opportunities. It isn&#x2019;t about buying, selling, and investing in companies, as many think. </p><p>The principles of resource allocation can help people attain happiness at home. If not managed masterfully, what emerges from a firm&#x2019;s resource allocation process can be very different from the strategy management intended to follow. That&#x2019;s true in life too: If you&#x2019;re not guided by a clear sense of purpose, you&#x2019;re likely to <u>fritter away</u> (&#x6D6A;&#x8D39;) your time and energy on obtaining the most <strong>tangible</strong> (&#x6709;&#x578B;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x5207;&#x5B9E;&#x7684;), short-term signs of achievement, not what&#x2019;s really important to you.</p><p>And just as a focus on marginal costs can cause bad corporate decisions, it can lead people <strong>astray</strong> (&#x8BEF;&#x5165;&#x6B67;&#x9014;&#x5730;&#xFF1B;&#x8FF7;&#x9014;&#x7684;). The marginal cost of doing something wrong &#x201C;just this once&#x201D; always seems <strong>alluringly</strong> (&#x8BF1;&#x4EBA;&#x5730;&#xFF1B;&#x59A9;&#x5A9A;&#x5730;) low. You don&#x2019;t see the end result to which that path leads. The key is to define what you stand for and draw the line in a safe place.</p><p><em>Editor&#x2019;s Note: When the members of the class of 2010 entered business school, the economy was strong and their post-graduation ambitions could be limitless (&#x65E0;&#x9650;&#x5236;&#x7684;). Just a few weeks later, the economy went into a <strong>tailspin</strong> ( &#x6DF7;&#x4E71;&#xFF1B;&#x65CB;&#x5C3E;&#x964D;&#x843D;). They&#x2019;ve spent the past two years recalibrating their worldview and their definition of success.</em></p><p><em>The students seem highly aware of how the world has changed (as the sampling of views in this article shows). In the spring, Harvard Business School&#x2019;s graduating class asked HBS professor Clay Christensen to <strong>address</strong> (&#x6F14;&#x8BB2;&#xFF0C;&#x81F4;&#x8F9E;) them&#x2014;but not on how to apply his principles and thinking to their post-HBS careers. The students wanted to know how to apply them to their personal lives. He shared with them a set of guidelines that have helped him find meaning in his own life. Though Christensen&#x2019;s thinking comes from his deep <u>religious faith</u> (&#x5B97;&#x6559;&#x4FE1;&#x4EF0;), we believe that these are strategies anyone can use. And so we asked him to share them with the readers of HBR.</em></p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How Will You Measure Your Life?-1
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -81</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/06/MY-100-Day-English-81/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/06/MY-100-Day-English-81/</id>
    <published>2021-03-06T08:48:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-06T11:38:38.373Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/02/Feb21_24_77661438.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><em>Continuous</em></p><p><strong>Don&#x2019;t just champion new ideas; strengthen personal relationships.</strong></p><p>In times of unprecedented <strong>turmoil</strong> (&#x6DF7;&#x4E71;), there is an understandable temptation for leaders to bet the future on game-changing ideas: digital disruption, product reinvention, organizational transformation. All too often, though, leaders who champion futuristic ideas overlook the human and emotional connections that keep colleagues <strong>upbeat</strong> today.</p><p>Sharon Salzberg, a central <strong>figure</strong> (&#x4EBA;&#x7269;&#xFF0C;&#x6570;&#x5B57;) in the field of meditation, works with <strong>caregivers</strong> (&#x770B;&#x62A4;&#x4EBA;), educators, and social-change activists &#x2014; <strong>well-meaning</strong> (&#x5584;&#x610F;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x597D;&#x5FC3;&#x7684;) people with <strong>aspirations</strong> (&#x5FD7;&#x5411;) to make a big difference. She urges these leaders to tend first to their &#x201C;<a href="https://www.sharonsalzberg.com/on-being-column-your-three-feet-of-influence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">three feet of influence</a>&#x201D; &#x2014; the clients, patients, people and teams closest to them. &#x201C;Few people are powerful enough, persuasive, persistent, and <strong>charismatic</strong> (&#x8D85;&#x51E1;&#x9B45;&#x529B;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x795E;&#x8D50;&#x80FD;&#x529B;&#x7684;) enough to change the world all at once,&#x201D; she argues. &#x201C;The world we can most try to affect is the one immediately around us.&#x201D;</p><p><strong>To counter so much bad news, share every piece of good news.</strong></p><p>Experts on human psychology don&#x2019;t agree on very much, but nearly all agree that people respond more <strong>viscerally</strong> (&#x672C;&#x80FD;&#x5730;,&#x53D1;&#x81EA;&#x5185;&#x5FC3;&#x7684;) to bad news than good. To keep people optimistic, they advise, leaders should emphasize (even over-emphasize) hopeful stories and positive developments.</p><p>Research psychologist Robert F. Baumeister <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/313665/the-power-of-bad-by-john-tierney-and-roy-f-baumeister/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimates</a> that it &#x201C;takes four good things to overcome one bad thing.&#x201D; So pop a (virtual) cork whenever a team hits an important milestone. Hold a department-wide Zoom <strong>bash</strong> (&#x76DB;&#x5927;&#x7684;&#x805A;&#x4F1A;&#xFF0C;&#x76DB;&#x5178;) when you land a new client. Distribute a newsletter that highlights what&#x2019;s going well, to help people <u>compensate for</u> (&#x8865;&#x507F;) what&#x2019;s gone poorly. And treat yourself the same way: &#x201C;Instead of obsessing about a <strong>snarky</strong> (&#x5C16;&#x523B;&#x7684;) comment on social media, scroll down and reread four <strong>compliments</strong> (&#x606D;&#x7EF4;&#xFF0C;&#x9053;&#x8D3A;),&#x201D; Baumeister recommends.</p><p>These are challenging times to stay energized and upbeat. Hopefully, applying these four pieces of advice will make you and your colleagues more optimistic. If that&#x2019;s not enough, you can always join <a href="https://www.optimist.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Optimist International</a>. I hear the organization has open spots for new members.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How to Stay Optimistic (When Everything Is Awful)-3
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -80</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/05/MY-100-Day-English-80/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/05/MY-100-Day-English-80/</id>
    <published>2021-03-04T17:49:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-06T11:21:53.231Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/02/Feb21_24_77661438.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><em>Continuous</em></p><p> <strong>Insist on crisp execution, but make room for &#x201C;organizational foolishness.&#x201D;</strong></p><p>In times as demanding as these, it&#x2019;s impossible to succeed without embracing the <strong>grind</strong> (&#x6298;&#x78E8;) &#x2014; the day-to-day struggle to meet the needs of anxious customers, collaborate with stressed-out colleagues, balance work and family.</p><p>But this organizational attention to detail can&#x2019;t come at the expense of imagination and brainstorming &#x2014; what celebrated Stanford Business School professor James G. March calls &#x201C;organizational foolishness.&#x201D; In his <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2392340?seq=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>seminal</strong> (&#x6709;&#x521B;&#x9020;&#x529B;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x91CD;&#x5927;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x751F;&#x6B96;&#x7684;) paper</a>, &#x201C;Footnotes to Organizational Change,&#x201D; March describes how the best leaders balance &#x201C;explicitly sensible processes of change,&#x201D; such as careful planning and <strong>sound</strong> (&#x826F;&#x597D;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x58F0;&#x97F3;) project management, with slack time, experiments, <strong><u>blue-sky thinking</u></strong> (&#x5929;&#x9A6C;&#x884C;&#x7A7A;&#x7684;&#x60F3;&#x8C61;&#x529B;) &#x2014; &#x201C;certain elements of foolishness&#x201D; that can be &#x201C;difficult to justify&#x201D; but are &#x201C;important to the broader system&#x201D; of innovation.</p><p>Achieving that balance <u>has never been more important</u> (&#x4ECE;&#x672A;&#x5982;&#x6B64;&#x91CD;&#x8981;&#x8FC7;), not just for the healthy performance of the organization, but for the mental health of your colleagues. It&#x2019;s hard for people to be positive if they don&#x2019;t get a chance to play.</p><p><strong>Invite everyone to become a problem-solver, then give them room to fix things.</strong></p><p>More than a decade ago, Sara D. Sarasvathy published an influential <a href="https://www.effectuation.org/sites/default/files/research_papers/what-makes-entrepreneurs-entrepreneurial-sarasvathy_0.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">study</a> of how innovators and entrepreneurs actually <u>get stuff done</u> (&#x5B8C;&#x6210;&#x5DE5;&#x4F5C;). The <strong>mythology</strong> (&#x795E;&#x8BDD;), she argued, is that successful innovators predict a future others can&#x2019;t see, develop a finely tuned plan to turn that future into reality, and attract the financial and human resources to back their efforts.</p><p>In reality, most change agents start with &#x201C;who they are&#x201D; (their &#x201C;traits, tastes, and abilities&#x201D;); use &#x201C;what they know&#x201D; (their &#x201C;training, expertise, and experience&#x201D;); and add &#x201C;whom they know&#x201D; (their &#x201C;social and professional networks&#x201D;). She calls this approach the &#x201C;bird-in-the-hand principle.&#x201D; Guided by this principle, she argues, starting a new venture or making things better &#x201C;is no longer an incredibly risky act of heroism. It is something you can do within the constraints and possibilities of your normal life.&#x201D;</p><p>By encouraging their colleagues to do, in the words of Theodore Roosevelt, &#x201C;what you can, with what you&#x2019;ve got, where you are,&#x201D; leaders create a spirit of agency that leads to optimism.</p><p>&#x5929;&#x9A6C;&#x884C;&#x7A7A;&#x7684;&#x60F3;&#x8C61;&#x529B;&#xFF1A; blue-sky thinking</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How to Stay Optimistic (When Everything Is Awful)-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -79</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/04/MY-100-Day-English-79/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/04/MY-100-Day-English-79/</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T17:49:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-06T11:08:24.902Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/02/Feb21_24_77661438.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><strong>Summary.</strong>  These are challenging times to stay energized and <strong>upbeat</strong> (&#x4E50;&#x89C2;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x79EF;&#x6781;&#x5411;&#x4E0A;&#x7684;). The author offers four pieces of advice to help make you and your colleagues more optimistic: 1) Insist on <u>crisp execution</u> (&#x5E72;&#x8106;&#x5229;&#x843D;&#x7684;&#x6267;&#x884C;), but make room for &#x201C;organizational foolishness (&#x7EC4;&#x7EC7;&#x4E0A;&#x7684;&#x611A;&#x8822;)&#x201D;; 2) Invite everyone to become a problem-solver, then give them room to fix things (&#x7ED9;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x89E3;&#x51B3;&#x95EE;&#x9898;&#x7684;&#x7A7A;&#x95F4;); 3) Don&#x2019;t just champion new ideas; strengthen personal relationships; and 4) To counter so much bad news, share every piece of good news.</p><hr><p>These are trying times for optimists. Covid deaths <a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#datatracker-home" target="_blank" rel="noopener">remain tragically high</a>. Job growth <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/02/05/january-jobs-report-2021-unemployment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">remains <strong>stubbornly</strong> (&#x987D;&#x56FA;&#x5730;&#xFF1B;&#x5014;&#x5F3A;&#x5730;) low</a>. So many of our colleagues and kids are feeling stressed, exhausted, angry &#x2014; &#x201C;<a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/coronavirus-pandemic-wall-mental-health_l_601b3c9dc5b6c0af54d09ccb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hitting the pandemic wall</a>.&#x201D; No wonder a recent <strong>front-page</strong> (&#x5934;&#x7248;&#x7684;,&#x5934;&#x6761;) article in the <em>Wall Street Journal</em>, which has <strong>chronicled</strong> (&#x7F16;&#x5E74;&#x53F2;&#xFF0C;&#x5E74;&#x4EE3;&#x8BB0;) the Covid-driven struggles of companies and universities, highlighted <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/optimist-clubs-see-glass-half-full-even-in-pandemic-11612539409" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a crisis at a different kind of organization </a>&#x2014; Optimist International, a 110-year-old club with <strong>chapters</strong> (&#x5206;&#x4F1A;&#xFF0C;&#x7AE0;&#x8282;) around the world. Membership is now at 60,000, down from a high of 190,000, although club leaders remain true to their guiding spirit. &#x201C;When you hit rock bottom, the only direction you can go is up,&#x201D; said one chapter head, who declared she was &#x201C;getting my optimistic groove back.&#x201D;</p><p>It&#x2019;s important for all of us to get our optimistic groove back. John Gardner, the <strong>[fabled</strong> (&#x4F20;&#x8BF4;&#x4E2D;&#x7684;) scholar of leadership](<a href="https://stanfordmag.org/contents/an-uncommon-man" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://stanfordmag.org/contents/an-uncommon-man</a>) whose insights have influenced generations of executives, argued that positive change rarely starts from blind faith or na&#xEF;vet&#xE9;, but it also doesn&#x2019;t start from despair or <strong>defeatism</strong> (&#x5931;&#x8D25;&#x4E3B;&#x4E49;). &#x201C;The first and last task of a leader is to keep hope alive,&#x201D; <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2681873?seq=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">he wrote in 1968</a>, another period of <strong>turmoil</strong> (&#x6DF7;&#x4E71;&#xFF0C;&#x9A9A;&#x52A8;) and struggle. &#x201C;We need to believe in ourselves and our future but not to believe that life is easy.&#x201D;</p><p>In other words, leaders help their colleagues be realists &#x2014; and optimists. But whether you&#x2019;re running a company or managing a team, how do you keep your colleagues upbeat <a href="https://hbr.org/2020/03/how-to-reassure-your-team-when-the-news-is-scary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">when the whole world is feeling down</a>? How do you keep hope alive when things seem pretty hopeless? Here are four pieces of advice, drawn from renowned thinkers on organizational life, innovation, even meditation, that I&#x2019;m optimistic will help you shape a more positive future.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-How to Stay Optimistic (When Everything Is Awful)-1
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -78</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/03/MY-100-Day-English-78/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/03/MY-100-Day-English-78/</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T07:03:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T09:26:09.260Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33175090/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prescription Opioid Use and Risk for Major Depressive Disorder and Anxiety and Stress-Related Disorders: A Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Analysis</a></p></blockquote><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p><strong>Importance:</strong> Growing evidence suggests that prescription <strong>opioid</strong> (&#x9E26;&#x7247;&#x6837;&#x7269;&#x8D28;&#xFF0C;&#x7C7B;&#x9E26;&#x7247;) use affects depression and anxiety disorders; however, observational studies are subject to confounding, making causal inference and determining the direction of these associations difficult.</p><p><strong>Objective:</strong> To investigate the potential bidirectional associations between the genetic liability for prescription opioid and other nonopioid pain medications and both major depressive disorder (MDD) and anxiety and stress-related disorders (ASRD) using genetically based methods.</p><p><strong>Design, setting, and participants:</strong> We performed 2-sample mendelian randomization (MR) using summary statistics from genome-wide association studies (GWAS) to assess potential associations of self-reported prescription opioid and nonopioid analgesics, including nonsteroidal anti-inflammatories (NSAIDs) and acetaminophen-like derivatives use with MDD and ASRD. The GWAS data were derived from participants of predominantly European ancestry included in observational cohorts. Data were analyzed February 20, 2020, to May 4, 2020.</p><p><strong>Main outcomes and measures:</strong> Major depressive disorder, ASRD, and self-reported pain medications (opioids, NSAIDs, anilides, and salicylic acid).</p><p><strong>Results:</strong> The GWAS data were derived from participants of predominantly European ancestry included in the population-based UK Biobank and Lundbeck Foundation Initiative for Integrative Psychiatric Research studies: approximately 54% of the initial UK Biobank sample and 55.6% of the Lundbeck Foundation Initiative for Integrative Psychiatric Research sample selected for the ASRD GWAS were women. In a combined sample size of 737 473 study participants, single-variable MR showed that genetic liability for increased prescription opioid use was associated with increased risk of both MDD (odds ratio [OR] per unit increase in log odds opioid use, 1.14; 95% CI, 1.06-1.22; P &lt; .001) and ASRD (OR, 1.24; 95% CI, 1.07-1.44; P = .004). Using multivariable MR, these opioid use estimates remained after accounting for other nonopioid pain medications (MDD OR, 1.14; 95% CI, 1.04-1.25; P = .005; ASRD OR, 1.30; 95% CI, 1.08-1.46; P = .006), and in separate models, accounting for comorbid pain conditions. Bidirectional analyses showed that genetic liability for MDD but not ASRD was associated with increased prescription opioid use risk (OR, 1.18; 95% CI, 1.08-1.30; P &lt; .001). These estimates were generally consistent across single-variable and multivariable inverse variance-weighted (MV-IVW) and MR-Egger sensitivity analyses. Pleiotropy-robust methods did not indicate bias in any MV-IVW estimates.</p><p><strong>Conclusions and relevance:</strong> The findings of this mendelian randomization analysis suggest evidence for potential causal associations between the genetic liability for increased prescription opioid use and the risk for MDD and ASRD. While replication studies are necessary, these findings may inform prevention and intervention strategies directed toward the opioid epidemic and depression.</p><p>&#x8D8A;&#x6765;&#x8D8A;&#x591A;&#x7684;&#x8BC1;&#x636E;&#x8868;&#x660E;&#xFF0C;&#x5904;&#x65B9;&#x963F;&#x7247;&#x7C7B;&#x836F;&#x7269;&#x7684;&#x4F7F;&#x7528;&#x4F1A;&#x5F71;&#x54CD;&#x6291;&#x90C1;&#x75C7;&#x548C;&#x7126;&#x8651;&#x75C7;&#x3002;&#x4F46;&#x662F;&#xFF0C;&#x89C2;&#x5BDF;&#x6027;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x5BB9;&#x6613;&#x6DF7;&#x6DC6;&#xFF0C;&#x5BFC;&#x81F4;&#x56E0;&#x679C;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x7684;&#x63A8;&#x8BBA;&#x548C;&#x786E;&#x5B9A;&#x8FD9;&#x4E9B;&#x8054;&#x7CFB;&#x7684;&#x65B9;&#x5411;&#x5F88;&#x56F0;&#x96BE;&#x3002;</p><p>&#x4E3A;&#x4E86;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x5904;&#x65B9;&#x963F;&#x7247;&#x7C7B;&#x836F;&#x7269;&#x548C;&#x5176;&#x4ED6;&#x975E;&#x963F;&#x7247;&#x7C7B;&#x836F;&#x7269;&#x6B62;&#x75DB;&#x836F;&#x4F7F;&#x7528;&#x7684;&#x9057;&#x4F20;&#x503E;&#x5411;&#x4E0E;&#x6291;&#x90C1;&#x75C7;&#xFF08;MDD&#xFF09;&#x3001;&#x7126;&#x8651;&#x548C;&#x538B;&#x529B;&#x76F8;&#x5173;&#x6027;&#x75BE;&#x75C5;&#xFF08;ASRD&#xFF09;&#x4E4B;&#x95F4;&#x7684;&#x6F5C;&#x5728;&#x53CC;&#x5411;&#x5173;&#x8054;&#xFF0C;&#x91C7;&#x7528;&#x57FA;&#x4E8E;&#x5B5F;&#x5FB7;&#x5C14;&#x968F;&#x673A;&#x5316;&#x9057;&#x4F20;&#x7684;&#x65B9;&#x6CD5;&#x3002;</p><p>&#x5B5F;&#x5FB7;&#x5C14;&#x968F;&#x673A;&#x5206;&#x6790;&#x7684;&#x7ED3;&#x679C;&#x4E3A;&#x589E;&#x52A0;&#x5904;&#x65B9;&#x963F;&#x7247;&#x7C7B;&#x836F;&#x7269;&#x4F7F;&#x7528;&#x7684;&#x9057;&#x4F20;&#x503E;&#x5411;&#x4E0E;MDD&#x548C;ASRD&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x4E4B;&#x95F4;&#x7684;&#x5B58;&#x5728;&#x6F5C;&#x5728;&#x56E0;&#x679C;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x63D0;&#x4F9B;&#x4E86;&#x8BC1;&#x636E;&#x3002;&#x8FD9;&#x4E9B;&#x53D1;&#x73B0;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x4E3A;&#x963F;&#x7247;&#x7C7B;&#x836F;&#x7269;&#x6D41;&#x884C;&#x548C;&#x6291;&#x90C1;&#x75C7;&#x7684;&#x9884;&#x9632;&#x548C;&#x5E72;&#x9884;&#x7B56;&#x7565;&#x63D0;&#x4F9B;&#x4FE1;&#x606F;&#x3002;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Prescription Opioid Use and Risk for Major Depressive Disorder and Anxiety and Stress-Related Disorders A Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Analysis
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -77</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/02/MY-100-Day-English-77/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/02/MY-100-Day-English-77/</id>
    <published>2021-03-02T08:35:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T08:44:35.132Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33413940/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Diet-Derived Circulating Antioxidants and Risk of Coronary Heart Disease: A Mendelian Randomization Study</a></p></blockquote><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p><strong>Background:</strong> Previously, observational studies have identified associations between higher levels of dietary-derived <strong>antioxidants</strong> (&#x6297;&#x6C27;&#x5316;&#x5242;) and lower risk of coronary heart disease (CHD), whereas randomized clinical trials showed no reduction in CHD risk following antioxidant supplementation.</p><p><strong>Objectives:</strong> The purpose of this study was to investigate possible causal associations between dietary-derived circulating antioxidants and primary CHD risk using 2-sample Mendelian randomization (MR).</p><p><strong>Methods:</strong> Single-nucleotide polymorphisms for circulating antioxidants (vitamins E and C, <strong>retinol</strong> (&#x89C6;&#x9EC4;&#x9187;&#xFF1B;&#x7EF4;&#x751F;&#x7D20;A), &#x3B2;-<strong>carotene</strong> (&#x80E1;&#x841D;&#x535C;&#x7D20;), and <strong>lycopene</strong> (&#x756A;&#x8304;&#x7EA2;&#x7D20;)), assessed as absolute levels and metabolites, were <strong>retrieved</strong> (&#x6062;&#x590D;&#xFF1B;&#x91CD;&#x65B0;&#x53D6;&#x56DE;&#xFF1B;&#x8865;&#x507F;) from the published data and were used as genetic instrumental variables. Summary statistics for gene-CHD associations were obtained from 3 databases: the CARDIoGRAMplusC4D consortium (60,801 cases; 123,504 control subjects), UK Biobank (25,306 cases; 462,011 control subjects), and FinnGen study (7,123 cases; 89,376 control subjects). For each exposure, MR analyses were performed per outcome database and were subsequently meta-analyzed.</p><p><strong>Results:</strong> Among an analytic sample of 768,121 individuals (93,230 cases), genetically predicted circulating antioxidants were not causally associated with CHD risk. For absolute antioxidants, the odds ratio for CHD ranged between 0.94 (95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.63 to 1.41) for retinol and 1.03 (95% CI: 0.97 to 1.10) for &#x3B2;-carotene per unit increase in ln-transformed antioxidant values. For metabolites, the odds ratio ranged between 0.93 (95% CI: 0.82 to 1.06) for &#x3B3;-tocopherol and 1.01 (95% CI: 0.95 to 1.08) for ascorbate per 10-fold increase in metabolite levels.</p><p><strong>Conclusions:</strong> Evidence from our study did not support a protective effect of genetic predisposition to high dietary-derived antioxidant levels on CHD risk. Therefore, it is unlikely that taking antioxidants to increase blood antioxidants levels will have a clinical benefit for the prevention of primary CHD.</p><p>&#x4E34;&#x5E8A;&#x4E0A;&#x7684;&#x968F;&#x673A;&#x5BF9;&#x7167;&#x5B9E;&#x9A8C;&#x8868;&#x660E;&#xFF0C;&#x8865;&#x5145;&#x6297;&#x6C27;&#x5316;&#x5242;&#x5E76;&#x4E0D;&#x80FD;&#x4FDD;&#x62A4;&#x964D;&#x4F4E;&#x51A0;&#x5FC3;&#x75C5;&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x3002;&#x672C;&#x6587;&#x4F7F;&#x7528;&#x4E24;&#x6837;&#x672C;&#x5B5F;&#x5FB7;&#x5C14;&#x968F;&#x673A;&#x5316;&#x7684;&#x65B9;&#x6CD5;&#x63A2;&#x7A76;&#x81B3;&#x98DF;&#x6765;&#x6E90;&#x7684;&#x5FAA;&#x73AF;&#x6297;&#x6C27;&#x5316;&#x5242;&#x548C;&#x539F;&#x53D1;&#x6027;&#x51A0;&#x5FC3;&#x75C5;&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x4E4B;&#x95F4;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x7684;&#x56E0;&#x679C;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x3002;&#x672C;&#x6587;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x7684;&#x8BC1;&#x636E;&#x5E76;&#x4E0D;&#x652F;&#x6301;&#x9AD8;&#x996E;&#x98DF;&#x6765;&#x6E90;&#x6297;&#x6C27;&#x5316;&#x5242;&#x6C34;&#x5E73;&#xFF08;&#x9057;&#x4F20;&#x6613;&#x611F;&#x6027;&#xFF09;&#x5BF9;&#x51A0;&#x5FC3;&#x75C5;&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x7684;&#x4FDD;&#x62A4;&#x4F5C;&#x7528;&#x3002;&#x56E0;&#x6B64;&#xFF0C;&#x670D;&#x7528;&#x6297;&#x6C27;&#x5316;&#x5242;&#x6765;&#x589E;&#x52A0;&#x8840;&#x6DB2;&#x6297;&#x6C27;&#x5316;&#x5242;&#x6C34;&#x5E73;&#x4E0D;&#x592A;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x5BF9;&#x9884;&#x9632;&#x539F;&#x53D1;&#x6027;&#x51A0;&#x5FC3;&#x75C5;&#x6709;&#x4E34;&#x5E8A;&#x76CA;&#x5904;&#x3002;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Diet-Derived Circulating Antioxidants and Risk of Coronary Heart Disease A Mendelian Randomization Study
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -76</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/01/MY-100-Day-English-76/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/03/01/MY-100-Day-English-76/</id>
    <published>2021-03-01T09:19:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:29:21.053Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-20368-w" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A comprehensive re-assessment of the association between vitamin D and cancer susceptibility using Mendelian randomization</a></p></blockquote><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p>Previous Mendelian randomization (MR) studies on 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and cancer have typically adopted a handful of variants and found no relationship between 25(OH)D and cancer; however, issues of horizontal pleiotropy cannot be reliably addressed. Using a larger set of variants associated with 25(OH)D (74 SNPs, up from 6 previously), we perform a unified MR analysis to re-evaluate the relationship between 25(OH)D and ten cancers. Our findings are broadly consistent with previous MR studies indicating no relationship, apart from ovarian cancers (OR 0.89; 95% C.I: 0.82 to 0.96 per 1&#x2009;SD change in 25(OH)D concentration) and basal cell carcinoma (OR 1.16; 95% C.I.: 1.04 to 1.28). However, after adjustment for pigmentation related variables in a multivariable MR framework, the BCC findings were attenuated. Here we report that lower 25(OH)D is unlikely to be a causal risk factor for most cancers, with our study providing more precise confidence intervals than previously possible.</p><p>&#x4E4B;&#x524D;&#x6709;&#x5173;&#x7EF4;&#x751F;&#x7D20;D&#x548C;&#x764C;&#x75C7;&#x7684;&#x5B5F;&#x5FB7;&#x5C14;&#x968F;&#x673A;&#x5316;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x4F7F;&#x7528;&#x7684;&#x5DE5;&#x5177;&#x53D8;&#x91CF;SNP&#x5F88;&#x5C11;&#xFF0C;&#x5B83;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x90FD;&#x53D1;&#x73B0;&#x7EF4;&#x751F;&#x7D20;D&#x548C;&#x764C;&#x75C7;&#x6CA1;&#x6709;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x3002;&#x7136;&#x800C;&#x6C34;&#x5E73;&#x591A;&#x6548;&#x6027;&#x7684;&#x95EE;&#x9898;&#x4E00;&#x76F4;&#x6CA1;&#x6709;&#x5F97;&#x5230;&#x53EF;&#x9760;&#x7684;&#x89E3;&#x51B3;&#xFF0C;&#x672C;&#x6587;&#x4F7F;&#x7528;&#x66F4;&#x591A;&#x7684;&#x4E0E;&#x7EF4;&#x751F;&#x7D20;D&#x76F8;&#x5173;&#x7684;SNP&#xFF08;74&#x4E2A;SNP&#xFF0C;&#x4E4B;&#x524D;&#x662F;6&#x4E2A;&#xFF09;&#xFF0C;&#x501F;&#x52A9;&#x5B5F;&#x5FB7;&#x5C14;&#x968F;&#x673A;&#x5316;&#x7684;&#x65B9;&#x6CD5;&#x6765;&#x63A2;&#x7A76;&#x7EF4;&#x751F;&#x7D20;D&#x548C;&#x59CB;&#x7EC8;&#x764C;&#x75C7;&#x4E4B;&#x95F4;&#x7684;&#x56E0;&#x679C;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#xFF0C;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x6700;&#x7EC8;&#x53D1;&#x73B0;&#x7EF4;&#x751F;&#x7D20;D&#x548C;&#x5927;&#x591A;&#x6570;&#x7684;&#x764C;&#x75C7;&#x53D1;&#x75C5;&#x6CA1;&#x6709;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#xFF0C;&#x672C;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x63D0;&#x4F9B;&#x4E86;&#x6BD4;&#x4EE5;&#x524D;&#x66F4;&#x7CBE;&#x786E;&#x7684;&#x7F6E;&#x4FE1;&#x533A;&#x95F4;&#x3002;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      A comprehensive re-assessment of the association between vitamin D and cancer susceptibility using Mendelian randomization
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -75</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/28/MY-100-Day-English-75/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/28/MY-100-Day-English-75/</id>
    <published>2021-02-28T09:18:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:31:33.450Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33542229/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Obesity and atypical depression symptoms: findings from Mendelian randomization in two European cohorts</a></p></blockquote><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p>Studies considering the causal role of body mass index (BMI) for the <strong>predisposition</strong> (&#x503E;&#x5411;&#xFF1B;&#x7D20;&#x8D28;&#xFF1B;&#x6613;&#x67D3;&#x75C5;&#x4F53;&#x8D28;) of major depressive disorder (MDD) based on a Mendelian Randomization (MR) approach have shown contradictory (&#x77DB;&#x76FE;&#x7684;) results. These inconsistent findings may be attributable to the heterogeneity of MDD; in fact, several studies have documented associations between BMI and mainly the <strong>atypical</strong> (&#x975E;&#x5178;&#x578B;&#x7684;) subtype of MDD. Using a MR approach, we investigated the potential causal role of obesity in both the atypical subtype and its five specific symptoms assessed according to the Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM), in two large European cohorts, CoLaus|PsyCoLaus (n = 3350, 1461 cases and 1889 controls) and NESDA|NTR (n = 4139, 1182 cases and 2957 controls). We first tested general obesity measured by BMI and then the body fat distribution measured by waist-to-hip ratio (WHR). Results suggested that BMI is potentially causally related to the symptom increase in appetite, for which inverse variance weighted, simple median and weighted median MR regression estimated slopes were 0.68 (SE = 0.23, p = 0.004), 0.77 (SE = 0.37, p = 0.036), and 1.11 (SE = 0.39, p = 0.004). <u>No causal effect of BMI or WHR was found on the risk of the atypical subtype or for any of the other atypical symptoms</u>. Our findings show that <u>higher obesity is likely causal for the specific symptom of increase in appetite in depressed participants</u> and <strong>reiterate</strong> (&#x91CD;&#x7533;&#xFF1B;&#x53CD;&#x590D;&#x5730;&#x505A;) the need to study depression at the <strong>granular</strong> (&#x9897;&#x7C92;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x7C92;&#x72B6;&#x7684;) level of its symptoms to further <strong>elucidate</strong> (&#x9610;&#x660E;&#xFF1B;&#x8BF4;&#x660E;) potential causal relationships and gain additional insight into its biological <strong>underpinnings</strong> (&#x57FA;&#x7840;&#xFF0C;&#x652F;&#x67F1;).</p><p>&#x6CA1;&#x6709;&#x53D1;&#x73B0;BMI&#x6216;WHR&#x5BF9;&#x975E;&#x5178;&#x578B;&#x4E9A;&#x578B;&#x6216;&#x4EFB;&#x4F55;&#x5176;&#x4ED6;&#x975E;&#x5178;&#x578B;&#x6291;&#x90C1;&#x75C7;&#x72B6;&#x7684;&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x6709;&#x56E0;&#x679C;&#x5F71;&#x54CD;</p><p>&#x8F83;&#x9AD8;&#x7684;&#x80A5;&#x80D6;&#x6C34;&#x5E73;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x662F;&#x5BFC;&#x81F4;&#x6291;&#x90C1;&#x8005;&#x98DF;&#x6B32;&#x589E;&#x52A0;&#x7684;&#x5177;&#x4F53;&#x75C7;&#x72B6;&#x7684;&#x539F;&#x56E0;</p><p>&#x6613;&#x611F;&#xFF1A;predisposition</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Obesity and atypical depression symptoms findings from Mendelian randomization in two European cohorts
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
