<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>衷深学习</title>
  <icon>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/1a78ec769217974f51d40169d81d53e1</icon>
  <subtitle>石晓强的小站</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-01-18T16:23:29.204Z</updated>
  <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>石晓强</name>
    <email>2583551979@qq.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -34</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/18/MY-100-Day-English-34/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/18/MY-100-Day-English-34/</id>
    <published>2021-01-18T04:00:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-18T16:23:29.204Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="Building-a-Support-System"><a href="#Building-a-Support-System" class="headerlink" title="Building a Support System"></a>Building a Support System</h3><p><code>&#x5EFA;&#x7ACB;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x652F;&#x6491;&#x4F60;&#x7684;&#x4F53;&#x7CFB;</code></p><p>The final step in leading through anxiety is making sure you have ongoing support. This means not only surrounding yourself with the right people but also developing routines that help you deal with <strong>bouts</strong> (&#x53D1;&#x4F5C;) of anxiety and lay the groundwork for maintaining your mental health.</p><h3 id="SCHEDULE-STRUCTURE-AND-SCENARIO-PLAN"><a href="#SCHEDULE-STRUCTURE-AND-SCENARIO-PLAN" class="headerlink" title="SCHEDULE, STRUCTURE, AND SCENARIO PLAN"></a>SCHEDULE, STRUCTURE, AND SCENARIO PLAN</h3><p>When you have anxiety, you need to be intentional about what your days look like, as I discussed earlier. The methods are basic: making lists, prioritizing, and breaking work into manageable chunks. <strong>Chop</strong> (&#x5241;&#x788E;&#xFF0C;&#x780D;) tasks that make you extremely anxious into <strong>bearable</strong> (&#x53EF;&#x5FCD;&#x53D7;&#x7684;) pieces. I learned this trick from my own psychiatrist, Carol Birnbaum.</p><p>Also use the detective work you did about your triggers to prepare for situations or events you know will cause you anxiety. If public speaking stresses you out, make sure you leave plenty of time to <strong>rehearse</strong> presentations. If you&#x2019;re afraid of flying, mentally rehearse a business trip from &#x201C;I&#x2019;m going to pack&#x201D; to &#x201C;I&#x2019;m going to order a cab and call my friend while I&#x2019;m on my way to the airport&#x201D; to &#x201C;I&#x2019;ll buy M&amp;M&#x2019;s when I get there because they make me happy.&#x201D; And finally, once on the plane: &#x201C;I&#x2019;m going to take a Xanax, do a calming meditation, and survive.&#x201D;</p><p>I get anxious when I&#x2019;m working far from home and haven&#x2019;t heard from my <strong>nanny</strong> (&#x4FDD;&#x59C6;) or husband. I worry something bad has happened and get distracted from what I&#x2019;m supposed to be doing. To counter this I ask my husband or the <strong>babysitter</strong> (&#x4FDD;&#x59C6;&#xFF0C;&#x4E34;&#x65F6;&#x7167;&#x987E;&#x5E7C;&#x513F;&#x8005;) to text me with an update every three hours. That way I don&#x2019;t <strong>pester</strong> (&#x7EA0;&#x7F20;,&#x70E6;&#x6270;) them when they might be driving with the kids in the car, for example. And knowing that they will keep me updated allows me to <u><strong>sink into</strong></u> (&#x9677;&#x5165;) my work.</p><h3 id="KNOW-WHO-YOUR-&#x201C;SAFE-TEAM&#x201D;-IS"><a href="#KNOW-WHO-YOUR-&#x201C;SAFE-TEAM&#x201D;-IS" class="headerlink" title="KNOW WHO YOUR &#x201C;SAFE TEAM&#x201D; IS"></a>KNOW WHO YOUR &#x201C;SAFE TEAM&#x201D; IS</h3><p>Since you want to <strong>spare</strong> (&#x4E0D;&#x4F24;&#x5BB3;&#xFF1B;&#x4E0D;&#x6BC1;&#x574F;&#xFF1B;&#x4F7F;&#x907F;&#x514D;) your employees the messy details of your anxiety, you need a place for those emotions to go. Make sure you have a &#x201C;safe team&#x201D; of people to whom you can <strong>confess</strong> (&#x627F;&#x8BA4;&#xFF0C;&#x5766;&#x767D;) scary thoughts. They can include a therapist, a coach, a mentor, a spouse or partner, and friends. It could be an intimate group of fellow leaders, online or off-line, who commit to sharing in <strong>confidence</strong> (&#x4FE1;&#x4EFB;&#xFF0C;&#x79D8;&#x5BC6;) and making space for one another&#x2019;s difficult emotions.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-10
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -33</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/17/MY-100-Day-English-33/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/17/MY-100-Day-English-33/</id>
    <published>2021-01-17T02:59:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-18T16:07:24.910Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="PRACTICE-HEALTHY-COMMUNICATION"><a href="#PRACTICE-HEALTHY-COMMUNICATION" class="headerlink" title="PRACTICE HEALTHY COMMUNICATION"></a>PRACTICE HEALTHY COMMUNICATION</h3><p><code>&#x5B9E;&#x8DF5;&#x5065;&#x5EB7;&#x7684;&#x4EA4;&#x6D41;</code></p><p>&#x5728;&#x5408;&#x9002;&#x7684;&#x65F6;&#x95F4;&#xFF0C;&#x4E5F;&#x8981;&#x5411;&#x4F60;&#x7684;&#x5458;&#x5DE5;&#x8892;&#x9732;&#x4F60;&#x7684;&#x7126;&#x8651;&#xFF0C;&#x4F46;&#x4E5F;&#x4E0D;&#x662F;&#x4E8B;&#x65E0;&#x5DE8;&#x7EC6;&#x3002;</p><p>One of the most dangerous aspects of anxiety is that it&#x2019;s <a href="https://hbr.org/2020/03/the-contagion-we-can-control" target="_blank" rel="noopener">contagious</a> (&#x611F;&#x67D3;&#x6027;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x4F20;&#x67D3;&#x6027;&#x7684;), and leaders set the tone. Daniel Goleman, the renowned psychologist and author of <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/69105/emotional-intelligence-by-daniel-goleman/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Emotional Intelligence</em></a>, calls this &#x201C;neural Wi-Fi,&#x201D; in which humans pick up on others&#x2019; unspoken feelings.</p><p>If you&#x2019;re not admitting that you&#x2019;re anxious but instead emitting irritability (&#x6613;&#x6012;) or distraction, you&#x2019;re not doing your staff any favors. But how can you be honest with your people in a way that doesn&#x2019;t strike fear in them? What degree of emotion is appropriate to express?</p><p>Ultimately, how much you disclose is a personal decision. As an owner of a business and the host of a podcast about anxiety and mental health, <u>I tend to be an open book</u> (&#x6211;&#x503E;&#x5411;&#x4E8E;&#x5F00;&#x8BDA;&#x5E03;&#x516C;). But I know that most leaders don&#x2019;t share their demons. Few feel comfortable starting a staff meeting with &#x201C;Wow, I&#x2019;m anxious today.&#x201D;</p><p>But self-aware leaders know when it&#x2019;s appropriate to be vulnerable. And here&#x2019;s the thing: Your staff needs you to be transparent and honest about anxiety and mental health, especially when the future of your company and their livelihoods are uncertain.</p><p>Amelia Ransom, the senior director of engagement and diversity at Avalara, says that she wants her leaders to admit when they&#x2019;re not doing OK, because it <strong>affirms</strong> (&#x80AF;&#x5B9A;&#xFF0C;&#x7533;&#x660E;) her experience. &#x201C;It makes me feel normal if someone I respect and trust admits they aren&#x2019;t all right. I think, &#x2018;Thank you for being human,&#x2019; and I want to follow that person.&#x201D; Ransom <strong>recounts</strong> (&#x8BB2;&#x8FF0;&#xFF0C;&#x91CD;&#x65B0;&#x53D9;&#x8FF0;) a powerful moment when a senior executive in her company brought the staff together on a videoconference and said, &#x201C;I can&#x2019;t tell you, &#x2018;You got this.&#x2019; What I can do is hold space for us to be together right now, to talk and figure some things out.&#x201D;</p><p>Admitting &#x201C;I&#x2019;m anxious today&#x201D; or &#x201C;I didn&#x2019;t sleep well&#x201D; lets everyone else in the room breathe a little easier. (&#x201C;Phew, it&#x2019;s not my fault he is so tense.&#x201D;) And remember, you don&#x2019;t have to share details; just share the state you&#x2019;re in.</p><p>The social psychologist Amy Cuddy tells us we need leaders who exhibit both warmth and strength. &#x201C;Most leaders today tend to emphasize their strength, competence, and <strong>credentials</strong> (&#x51ED;&#x8BC1;&#xFF0C;&#x8BC1;&#x4E66;) in the workplace, but that is exactly the wrong approach,&#x201D; she writes. &#x201C;Leaders who project strength before establishing trust run the risk of eliciting fear, and along with it <u>a host of</u> (&#x8BB8;&#x591A;&#xFF0C;&#x5927;&#x91CF;) dysfunctional behaviors.&#x201D; Nothing establishes trust more effectively than the emotional connection fostered through empathy and shared humanity. This is why being open about your own anxiety can be so powerful. It builds trust when you can ask teammates, &#x201C;How are you?&#x201D; and they don&#x2019;t feel as if they have to lie or put on a happy face, because they know you feel the strain, too.</p><p>This doesn&#x2019;t mean that you fall into a <strong>puddle</strong> (&#x6C34;&#x5751;&#xFF0C;&#x6CE5;&#x6F6D;) of tears during a videoconference, of course, or visibly lose control. And while your workers might want to know that you&#x2019;re closely monitoring cash flow to make sure bills get paid, they don&#x2019;t need to know that your anxiety is deeply rooted in your parents&#x2019; money troubles during your childhood. It&#x2019;s possible to model taking care of your mental health without making people lose confidence in your competence.</p><p>Imagine you&#x2019;re in an anxiety spiral from reading news about Covid-19, but you need to lead a staff meeting in 10 minutes. You could open the meeting by saying, &#x201C;Obviously, the news is getting more upsetting by the minute, but I want us to put that aside for the next half hour while we go through this call.&#x201D; Or you could be even more vulnerable and share that you&#x2019;re working to contain your scary thoughts by giving yourself what Glass calls a &#x201C;worry hour,&#x201D; when you allow yourself to indulge your biggest concerns before putting them away again and <strong>forging</strong> (&#x7A33;&#x6B65;&#x524D;&#x8FDB;) on.</p><p>If you want to encourage people to share but don&#x2019;t want the conversation to slip into an anxiety <strong>fest</strong> (&#x96C6;&#x4F1A;&#xFF0C;&#x8282;&#x65E5;), you can use a red-yellow-green exercise. (Here are <a href="https://www.reboot.io/2017/09/07/murmuration/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some tips</a> from Reboot.) Team members individually indicate where their moods are that day with one of the three colors, and they can expand on why if they wish. This allows people to share if they feel comfortable doing so and gives you useful information about the emotions of the group. You can then adjust your communication style and messaging accordingly.</p><p>And remember, while being positive is important to prevent emotional contagion, you don&#x2019;t want to give anyone false hope. If you get tough questions like &#x201C;Is my job safe?&#x201D; or &#x201C;Will we be in business in six months?&#x201D; it&#x2019;s not your job to <strong>divine</strong> (&#x5360;&#x535C;&#xFF0C;&#x9884;&#x8A00;) the future. No one has a <strong>crystal</strong> (&#x6C34;&#x6676;) ball, and so you can say what you know to be true in this moment and <strong>affirm</strong> (&#x65AD;&#x8A00;) the importance of working together and focusing on what each person can control.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-10
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -32</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/16/MY-100-Day-English-32/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/16/MY-100-Day-English-32/</id>
    <published>2021-01-16T03:34:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-17T07:31:26.462Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="DEVELOP-TECHNIQUES-FOR-SITUATIONS-YOU-CAN&#x2019;T-CONTROL"><a href="#DEVELOP-TECHNIQUES-FOR-SITUATIONS-YOU-CAN&#x2019;T-CONTROL" class="headerlink" title="DEVELOP TECHNIQUES FOR SITUATIONS YOU CAN&#x2019;T CONTROL"></a>DEVELOP TECHNIQUES FOR SITUATIONS YOU CAN&#x2019;T CONTROL</h3><p><code>&#x4E3A;&#x4F60;&#x4E0D;&#x80FD;&#x63A7;&#x5236;&#x7684;&#x60C5;&#x51B5;&#x5F00;&#x53D1;&#x6280;&#x5DE7;</code></p><p><strong>Make a connection.</strong> Connecting with others can break the negative thought loop that often accompanies anxiety. Instead of focusing on yourself, you turn your attention outward. When I asked my friend and colleague Cheryl Contee, the CEO and cofounder of the digital agency Do Big Things, how she was staying motivated during the crisis, she said that she was trying to &#x201C;be a good neighbor,&#x201D; something she learned from her grandfather, William G. Contee, who has a park dedicated to him in his Baltimore neighborhood. &#x201C;Being a good neighbor is surprisingly simple &#x2014; it&#x2019;s just about connecting on the human level,&#x201D; she told me. &#x201C;Do you say hello to your neighbors? Have you asked <u>how they&#x2019;re doing</u> (&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x8FC7;&#x5F97;&#x600E;&#x4E48;&#x6837;) or if they need anything?&#x201D;</p><p>Contee also connects digitally with people in her field, who support one another and contribute to <strong>causes</strong> (&#x4E8B;&#x4E1A;) they care about. At her company she and her colleagues are <strong>leaning into</strong> (&#x503E;&#x5411;&#x4E8E;) talking about their feelings and families, doing a lot of checking about how to balance homeschooling with work. &#x201C;We&#x2019;re all <strong>veteran</strong> (&#x5BCC;&#x6709;&#x7ECF;&#x9A8C;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x8001;&#x5175;) virtual knowledge workers, but having kids around and being responsible for their education is a new challenge we&#x2019;re facing together,&#x201D; she said.</p><p>In your own life, think about performing a quick, generous act. You might check in on a former colleague via text message. Or ask a family member <u>how you might help</u> (&#x4F60;&#x80FD;&#x5E2E;&#x5F97;&#x4E0A;&#x4EC0;&#x4E48;&#x5FD9;). When I&#x2019;m feeling anxious, I sometimes go to LinkedIn and &#x201C;like&#x201D; articles written by my colleagues or write up an <strong>endorsement</strong> (&#x652F;&#x6301;&#xFF0C;&#x8BA4;&#x53EF;) of their work. This gets me out of my head and focused on something more positive.</p><p>Finally, if anxiety is persistent and <strong>hampering</strong> (&#x59A8;&#x788D;&#xFF0C;&#x675F;&#x7F1A;) your days, you might consider consulting a therapist or mental health professional. Talking to someone trained in helping others manage anxiety may give you additional coping mechanisms to address <strong>debilitating</strong> (&#x4F7F;&#x8870;&#x5F31;&#x7684;) symptoms.</p><h3 id="Limiting-Anxiety&#x2019;s-Impact-on-Your-Leadership"><a href="#Limiting-Anxiety&#x2019;s-Impact-on-Your-Leadership" class="headerlink" title="Limiting Anxiety&#x2019;s Impact on Your Leadership"></a>Limiting Anxiety&#x2019;s Impact on Your Leadership</h3><p><code>&#x51CF;&#x5C11;&#x7126;&#x8651;&#x5BF9;&#x9886;&#x5BFC;&#x529B;&#x7684;&#x5F71;&#x54CD;</code></p><p>Once you have a better sense of how you experience anxiety and how you can manage it daily, it&#x2019;s time to turn to how it affects your leadership and management abilities.</p><h3 id="MAKE-GOOD-DECISIONS"><a href="#MAKE-GOOD-DECISIONS" class="headerlink" title="MAKE GOOD DECISIONS"></a>MAKE GOOD DECISIONS</h3><p><code>&#x505A;&#x51FA;&#x597D;&#x7684;&#x51B3;&#x5B9A;</code></p><p>Anxiety can impair our judgment. It can cause us to focus on the wrong things, distort the facts, or <u>rush to conclusions</u> (&#x5306;&#x5306;&#x4E0B;&#x7ED3;&#x8BBA;). Ideally, we could <strong>postpone</strong> (&#x5EF6;&#x671F;) critical decisions until we&#x2019;re in a better frame of mind, but that&#x2019;s not always possible.</p><p>In anxious times it&#x2019;s important to <strong>proactively</strong> (&#x4E3B;&#x52A8;&#x5730;) <u>set yourself up to make good choices</u>. Much as you do when separating the possible from the probable, start by acknowledging that your emotions can make you an unreliable narrator and that you will likely <strong><u>be prone to</u></strong> (&#x503E;&#x5411;&#x4E8E;&#xFF0C;&#x6613;&#x4E8E;) negative thoughts. Let&#x2019;s say you&#x2019;re prepping for a speech and the last time you spoke to a group of a similar size, you felt that you bombed. You may even have a long-held belief that you&#x2019;re a terrible public speaker because a middle school <strong>recitation</strong> (&#x80CC;&#x8BF5;&#xFF0C;&#x6717;&#x8BF5;) drew snickers (&#x5077;&#x7B11;). Ask yourself: Are you being objective? If you&#x2019;re not sure, check whether your memory is correct, perhaps by asking a colleague who was in the room for feedback.</p><p>Of course, you need to ask the right people. Boyes suggests you find a trusted adviser with a decision-making style that differs from your own. If you&#x2019;re <strong>impulsive</strong> (&#x51B2;&#x52A8;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x4EFB;&#x6027;&#x7684;), consult someone who is <strong>methodical</strong> (&#x6709;&#x6761;&#x7406;&#x7684;) and conservative, for example.</p><p>Ultimately, every leader should develop a team of &#x201C;real talk&#x201D; peers (&#x540C;&#x4E8B;): people who will provide their <strong>unvarnished</strong> (&#x672A;&#x6D82;&#x6F06;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x65E0;&#x88C5;&#x9970;&#x7684;) opinions. You can fill this role for others, too. You can still offer them clarity and insight even if you&#x2019;re an unreliable narrator of your own experience.</p><p>set up: &#x88C5;&#x5907;&#xFF0C;&#x5EFA;&#x7ACB;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-9
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -31</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/15/MY-100-Day-English-31/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/15/MY-100-Day-English-31/</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T14:02:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-17T07:31:23.731Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="DEVELOP-TECHNIQUES-FOR-SITUATIONS-YOU-CAN&#x2019;T-CONTROL"><a href="#DEVELOP-TECHNIQUES-FOR-SITUATIONS-YOU-CAN&#x2019;T-CONTROL" class="headerlink" title="DEVELOP TECHNIQUES FOR SITUATIONS YOU CAN&#x2019;T CONTROL"></a>DEVELOP TECHNIQUES FOR SITUATIONS YOU CAN&#x2019;T CONTROL</h3><p><code>&#x4E3A;&#x4F60;&#x4E0D;&#x80FD;&#x63A7;&#x5236;&#x7684;&#x60C5;&#x51B5;&#x5F00;&#x53D1;&#x6280;&#x5DE7;</code></p><p>Of course, it&#x2019;s not always possible to turn off the future. What if your <strong>board</strong> (&#x8463;&#x4E8B;&#x4F1A;) needs those cash flow projections in the next 30 minutes and you&#x2019;re in a downward spiral? Here you&#x2019;ll want to have tools that help you calm down quickly so that you can get your job done.</p><p><strong>Find a mindfulness (&#x5173;&#x6CE8;, &#x6B63;&#x5FF5;) technique that eases your acute anxiety.</strong> Neurologist Victor Frankl famously said, &#x201C;Between stimulus and response there is a space. In that space is our power to choose our response. In our response lies our growth and our freedom.&#x201D; This is mindfulness <strong>in a nutshell</strong> (&#x7B80;&#x800C;&#x8A00;&#x4E4B;&#xFF0C;&#x603B;&#x800C;&#x8A00;&#x4E4B;). Even if you are high on anxiety and short on time, you can claim the space in between.</p><p>There are lots of ways to do this; the key is to find what&#x2019;s most effective for you. One option is to focus on your breathing. <a href="https://www.uofmhealth.org/health-library/uz2255" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Belly (&#x8179;&#x90E8;) breaths</a> are a classic technique. Others prefer what&#x2019;s called &#x201C;the <a href="https://www.drweil.com/videos-features/videos/breathing-exercises-4-7-8-breath/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4-7-8</a> method.&#x201D; Either is simple to memorize and <strong>subtle</strong> (&#x5FAE;&#x5999;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x7CBE;&#x5DE7;&#x7684;) enough to do at your desk. When you <strong>deliberately</strong> (&#x6545;&#x610F;&#x7684;) slow your breath, it sends a message to your brain to calm down, and your brain then sends the message to your body so that many of the physical symptoms of anxiety &#x2014; such as increased heart rate and higher blood pressure &#x2014; decrease.</p><ol><li>&#x8179;&#x5F0F;&#x547C;&#x5438;&#xFF0C;&#x6DF1;&#x547C;&#x5438;</li><li>&#x51CF;&#x6162;&#x547C;&#x5438;</li></ol><p>You can also shift your attention. Glass says this technique is &#x201C;great for someone who doesn&#x2019;t want to meditate but gets maladaptively (&#x9002;&#x5E94;&#x4E0D;&#x826F;) anxious and cannot focus on anything else.&#x201D; Focus first on your anxiety, and then slowly turn your attention to something <strong>tangible</strong> (&#x6709;&#x5F62;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x5177;&#x4F53;&#x7684;), something you hold in your hand, like a book. By concentrating on an object in the present moment, you can turn <u>the volume of your worry</u> down until it&#x2019;s background noise.</p><p>If I&#x2019;m full of anxious energy and unable to sit still, or if quiet breathing exercises don&#x2019;t work, I like to loudly blast a favorite song and dance for five minutes. Some people like to sing instead. Experiment with what works for you and then <u>keep that tactic in your back pocket for when you need it</u>.</p><p><strong>Compartmentalize (&#x5212;&#x5206;&#xFF0C;&#x533A;&#x5206;) or postpone (&#x5EF6;&#x540E;) your worry.</strong> Sometimes I talk out loud to my anxiety, saying, &#x201C;Sorry, I&#x2019;m going to deal with you after I finish my work.&#x201D; You may want to write the worry down and save it for a specific time &#x2014; maybe later that day or your next session with your therapist.</p><p>In times of crisis you may actually find that things that worried you in the past fade into the background. The urgency of what&#x2019;s happening in the moment takes over. To stop your anxiety from sneaking into the foreground (&#x524D;&#x666F;&#xFF1B;&#x6700;&#x663E;&#x8457;&#x7684;&#x4F4D;&#x7F6E;), you might tell it, &#x201C;You can stay where you are. I&#x2019;m part of the solution here, and I need to get this task done.&#x201D;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-8
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -30</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/14/MY-100-Day-English-30/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/14/MY-100-Day-English-30/</id>
    <published>2021-01-13T16:36:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-17T07:31:20.822Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="Taking-Action-to-Manage-Your-Anxiety"><a href="#Taking-Action-to-Manage-Your-Anxiety" class="headerlink" title="Taking Action to Manage Your Anxiety"></a>Taking Action to Manage Your Anxiety</h3><p><code>&#x91C7;&#x53D6;&#x884C;&#x52A8;&#x63A7;&#x5236;&#x7684;&#x4F60;&#x7684;&#x7126;&#x8651;</code></p><p>Once you make your way through these three steps, you can start to manage your anxiety daily in ways that allow you to grow as a leader and be more resourceful and productive.</p><p>The following <strong>tactics</strong> (&#x7B56;&#x7565;) can help ground you (&#x5E2E;&#x4F60;&#x6253;&#x4E0B;&#x57FA;&#x7840;).</p><h3 id="CONTROL-WHAT-YOU-CAN"><a href="#CONTROL-WHAT-YOU-CAN" class="headerlink" title="CONTROL WHAT YOU CAN"></a>CONTROL WHAT YOU CAN</h3><p><code>&#x63A7;&#x5236;&#x4F60;&#x80FD;&#x63A7;&#x5236;&#x7684;</code></p><p>Many faith traditions teach us to accept what we cannot control, without <strong>preoccupation</strong> (&#x5168;&#x795E;&#x8D2F;&#x6CE8;) or panic. But in the middle of an anxiety attack at work, you probably don&#x2019;t have time for philosophy. So here&#x2019;s what to do when things feel completely <strong>off the rails</strong> (&#x8131;&#x79BB;&#x6B63;&#x5E38;&#x8F68;&#x9053;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x6DF7;&#x4E71;&#x7684;).</p><p><strong>Structure your time.</strong> <strong>A solid <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6379615/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">body</a> of research</strong> (&#x5927;&#x91CF;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x8868;&#x660E;) shows that improved &#x201C;time management <strong>disposition</strong> (&#x5904;&#x7F6E;)&#x201D; &#x2014; meaning your attitude toward how you organize and value your time &#x2014; has a positive impact on mental health. And it&#x2019;s especially crucial when you&#x2019;re gripped by anxiety.</p><p>First thing in the morning, create a to-do list and a detailed schedule for your day. I like to do it while having my coffee. You might use 30-minute increments to <strong>spell out</strong> (&#x8BE6;&#x7EC6;&#x8BF4;&#x660E;&#xFF0C;&#x5C06;&#x6E05;&#x695A;) when you&#x2019;ll shower, take a lunch break, make a phone call, or tackle that report that needs to get done. This is what many experts call &#x201C;<a href="https://hbr.org/2018/12/how-timeboxing-works-and-why-it-will-make-you-more-productive" target="_blank" rel="noopener">timeboxing</a>.&#x201D; While you&#x2019;re at it, try to avoid what cognitive behavioral therapy terms &#x201C;<a href="https://positivepsychology.com/cbt-cognitive-behavioral-therapy-techniques-worksheets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cognitive distortions (&#x7578;&#x53D8;&#xFF0C;&#x626D;&#x66F2;)</a>.&#x201D; These are the catastrophic thoughts, self-judgments, and all-or-nothing ideas that often accompany anxiety.</p><p>Be careful not to overschedule or <a href="https://hbr.org/2019/11/5-mental-mistakes-that-kill-your-productivity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">overestimate your productivity</a>; instead focus on the critical work and leave time to take care of yourself.</p><p><strong>Take small, meaningful actions.</strong> During the first few weeks of the coronavirus shutdown, traffic dropped drastically where I live. The local department of public works took that time to repaint (&#x91CD;&#x65B0;&#x7C89;&#x5237;) all the crosswalks (&#x4EBA;&#x884C;&#x6A2A;&#x9053;). For a week, roads were halfway blocked off as DPW crews painted. It wasn&#x2019;t a big deal because our normally bustling town was quiet. And each time I slowed down to drive past one of the crews, I smiled because it <strong><u>struck me</u></strong> (&#x6253;&#x52A8;&#x4E86;&#x6211;): This is their small, meaningful action. </p><p>When you feel anxious, an immediate task can easily become overwhelming. Take running a cash flow analysis for your business. When you open up the accounting software, your mind might go to a dark place, and all of a sudden a month&#x2019;s worth of figures have spiraled into the business tanking and your losing your home. To break that mental <strong>spiral</strong> (&#x87BA;&#x65CB;&#xFF1B;&#x65CB;&#x6DA1;), take a small, meaningful action. If running a cash flow <strong>projection</strong> (&#x9884;&#x6D4B;) terrifies you, organize some receipts (&#x6536;&#x636E;) or clean up some file folders until the panic <strong>subsides</strong> (&#x5E73;&#x606F;&#xFF0C;&#x8865;&#x8D34;).</p><p>In general, focus on the near term whenever you can. You may not be able to tell your employees what will happen next year &#x2014; or even three months from now. You can&#x2019;t promise everything will be OK. But you <em>can</em> help your people be safe this week. Focus on that, and then deal with the big questions when you feel calmer or when you can <strong>get input</strong> (&#x542C;&#x53D6;&#x5EFA;&#x8BAE;) from trusted colleagues. Sometimes you have to turn off the future for a little while and just manage through the present.</p><p><mark>A solid body of research shows that</mark>: &#x5927;&#x91CF;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x8868;&#x660E;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-7
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -29</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/13/MY-100-Day-English-29/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/13/MY-100-Day-English-29/</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T16:24:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-17T07:31:17.886Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="SORT-OUT-THE-PROBABLE-FROM-THE-POSSIBLE"><a href="#SORT-OUT-THE-PROBABLE-FROM-THE-POSSIBLE" class="headerlink" title="SORT OUT THE PROBABLE FROM THE POSSIBLE"></a>SORT OUT THE PROBABLE FROM THE POSSIBLE</h3><p><code>&#x4ECE;&#x90A3;&#x4E9B;&#x4F60;&#x9884;&#x60F3;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x53D1;&#x751F;&#x7684;&#x69FD;&#x7CD5;&#x7684;&#x4E8B;&#x4E2D;&#xFF0C;&#x627E;&#x51FA;&#x6700;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x7684;&#x51FA;&#x8DEF;</code></p><p>&#x6709;&#x65F6;&#x5019;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x4F1A;&#x88AB;&#x5F53;&#x524D;&#x69FD;&#x7CD5;&#x7684;&#x5904;&#x5883;&#x8499;&#x853D;&#x4E86;&#x53CC;&#x773C;&#xFF0C;&#x89C9;&#x5F97;&#x4E00;&#x5207;&#x90FD;&#x5B8C;&#x4E86;&#xFF0C;&#x6B63;&#x6240;&#x8C13;&#x5F53;&#x5C40;&#x8005;&#x8FF7;&#xFF0C;&#x8FD9;&#x65F6;&#x5019;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x53EF;&#x4EE5;&#x5C1D;&#x8BD5;&#x627E;&#x4E9B;&#x5408;&#x9002;&#x7684;&#x201C;&#x65C1;&#x89C2;&#x8005;&#x201D; (narrator), &#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x5904;&#x5728;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x76F8;&#x5BF9;&#x8F83;&#x5BA2;&#x89C2;&#x548C;&#x51B7;&#x9759;&#x7684;&#x7ACB;&#x573A;&#xFF0C;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x60C5;&#x51B5;&#x7ECF;&#x7531;&#x4ED6;&#x53D9;&#x8FF0;&#x51FA;&#x6765;&#xFF0C;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x4F60;&#x6216;&#x8005;&#x4ED6;&#x5C31;&#x89C9;&#x5F97;&#x5176;&#x5B9E;&#x4E5F;&#x6CA1;&#x6709;&#x90A3;&#x4E48;&#x7684;&#x69FD;&#x7CD5;&#xFF0C;&#x8BA9;&#x4F60;&#x4E0D;&#x5728;&#x6C89;&#x6EBA;&#x4E0E;&#x90A3;&#x4E2A;&#x7CDF;&#x7CD5;&#x7684;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#xFF0C;&#x800C;&#x662F;&#x53BB;&#x5173;&#x6CE8;&#x6700;&#x6709;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x7684;&#x51FA;&#x8DEF;&#xFF0C;&#x6216;&#x8005;&#x4ED6;&#x80FD;&#x63D0;&#x4F9B;&#x7ED9;&#x4F60;&#x65B0;&#x7684;&#x601D;&#x8DEF;&#xFF0C;&#x8BA9;&#x4F60;&#x627E;&#x5230;&#x65B0;&#x7684;&#x65B9;&#x5411;&#xFF0C;&#x7EE7;&#x7EED;&#x8D70;&#x4E0B;&#x53BB;&#x3002;</p><p>Once you understand your triggers and tells, you can start developing a new relationship with your anxiety.</p><p>Remember, some anxiety is rational and helpful. In an economic downturn it makes sense for a leader to feel anxious. You might have to <strong><u>lay people off</u></strong> (&#x88C1;&#x5458;). Your business might fail. But you might find that you get stuck in a negative thought loop that prevents you from moving forward; you start <strong>obsessing</strong> (&#x56F0;&#x6270;). Boyes points out that some leaders get so focused on the worst-case scenario and overwhelmed by scary possibilities that they become frozen (&#x50F5;&#x5316;).</p><p>So how do you avoid being stuck? Here I turn to advice from Colonna: &#x201C;Differentiate what&#x2019;s possible from what&#x2019;s probable. It is <em>possible</em> that everyone I love will die of a pandemic and I will lose everything I hold dear. But it&#x2019;s not <em>probable</em> that everything that we love and hold dear will disappear.&#x201D; Try to distinguish your worst fears from what is likely to happen. This will help calm you and give you space to move forward. So when a catastrophic thought comes into your head, such as &#x201C;My partner and I are both going to lose our jobs&#x201D; or &#x201C;I&#x2019;m definitely going to get sick,&#x201D; remember that you&#x2019;re an unreliable narrator when you&#x2019;re anxious. Check in with someone else you trust and ask for that person&#x2019;s help in telling what is likely to unfold from what is a long shot.</p><p>Back in early March, when the stock market first <strong>slumped</strong> (&#x4E0B;&#x8DCC;&#xFF0C;&#x9AA4;&#x964D;) and <u>people&#x2019;s fears about Covid-19 <strong>spiked</strong></u> (&#x5C16;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x8FBE;&#x5230;&#x9876;&#x5CF0;) (&#x4EBA;&#x4EEC;&#x5BF9;Covid-19&#x51A0;&#x72B6;&#x75C5;&#x6BD2;&#x75BE;&#x75C5;&#x7684;&#x6050;&#x60E7;&#x8FBE;&#x5230;&#x9876;&#x5CF0;&#x65F6;), one of my biggest clients canceled work with my small business. I quickly convinced myself that our company was <strong>doomed</strong> (&#x52AB;&#x6570;&#x96BE;&#x9003;&#xFF0C;&#x547D;&#x4E2D;&#x6CE8;&#x5B9A;), that it would be only <u>a matter of</u> (&#x5927;&#x7EA6;&#xFF1B;&#x2026;&#x7684;&#x95EE;&#x9898;) months before we had to close up shop. &#x201C;We&#x2019;ll never survive this,&#x201D; I kept telling myself. But then I consulted my business partner &#x2014; a more reliable <strong>narrator</strong> (&#x53D9;&#x8FF0;&#x8005;) than I &#x2014; and she suggested we readjust our forecast, which we did. Now we&#x2019;re projecting that we&#x2019;ll lose half our revenue for the year. This is probable and upsetting, but it&#x2019;s far different from <u>going out of business</u> (&#x7834;&#x4EA7;&#xFF0C;&#x5012;&#x95ED;) completely.</p><p>Focusing on what&#x2019;s probable also takes flexibility &#x2014; the future won&#x2019;t be what you thought, and that hurts. When my preschooler really wants to keep coloring (&#x753B;&#x753B;), but it&#x2019;s time for dinner, I ask her, &#x201C;Please be flexible. You can color later, I promise.&#x201D; I&#x2019;m now trying to do what I&#x2019;ve taught my kids for years: to handle the disappointment of things not going the way I expected or wanted (&#x5904;&#x7406;&#x90A3;&#x4E9B;&#x6CA1;&#x6709;&#x6309;&#x81EA;&#x5DF1;&#x9884;&#x671F;&#x548C;&#x60F3;&#x8981;&#x7684;&#x65B9;&#x5F0F;&#x53D1;&#x5C55;&#x7684;&#x4EE4;&#x4EBA;&#x5931;&#x671B;&#x7684;&#x4E8B;&#x60C5;). These disappointments are real, and sometimes the changes are grave. Acknowledge the <strong>grief</strong> (&#x60B2;&#x75DB;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0D;&#x5E78;) and anger you feel (at least to yourself) and then make adjustments, identifying the aspects of your vision that may still work, and focus on what&#x2019;s probable.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-6
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -28</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/12/MY-100-Day-English-28/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/12/MY-100-Day-English-28/</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T16:22:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-17T07:31:14.952Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="PLAY-DETECTIVE"><a href="#PLAY-DETECTIVE" class="headerlink" title="PLAY DETECTIVE"></a>PLAY DETECTIVE</h3><p><code>&#x505A;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x4FA6;&#x63A2;&#x6E38;&#x620F;</code></p><p>Imagine a CEO who is terrified by the economic news surrounding Covid-19. He jumps into the problem in the way that&#x2019;s worked for him in the past: making detailed <strong>projections</strong> (&#x89C4;&#x5212;) on all aspects of the business. He buries himself in these charts while constantly consuming news about the crisis. Some of his team might wonder what he&#x2019;s up to or feel unsettled by his visible yet unspoken panic. Are the charts he <strong>furiously</strong> (&#x731B;&#x70C8;&#x7684;) creates accurate? Who knows! But the deep dive into worst-case scenario planning gives him the illusion of control.</p><p>Your tells may also be physical. Anxiety can <strong>manifest</strong> (&#x660E;&#x663E;&#x7684;) itself as <u>tightness in the chest</u> (&#x80F8;&#x95F7;), shallow breathing, clenched jaw muscles, frozen shoulders, <strong>gastrointestinal</strong> (&#x80C3;&#x80A0;&#x7684;) symptoms, <u>skin breakouts</u> (&#x76AE;&#x80A4;&#x7834;&#x88C2;), appetite changes, and <strong>radical</strong> (&#x6FC0;&#x8FDB;&#x7684;) shifts in energy. When I recently had a panic attack, for example, I was convinced it was heart failure &#x2014; even though I&#x2019;d had panic attacks before.</p><p>To help you identify the ways anxiety may be physically affecting you, try this two-part exercise:</p><p>First, sit upright in a chair. Put your feet flat on the floor (&#x53CC;&#x811A;&#x5E73;&#x653E;&#x5728;&#x5730;&#x677F;&#x4E0A;), and your hands on your <strong>lap</strong> (&#x819D;&#x90E8;). Keep your <u>chin neutral</u> (&#x4E0B;&#x5DF4;&#x4E2D;&#x7ACB;). Note which part of the body you can immediately feel. Then, with your eyes closed, scan through the following:</p><ul><li>Your head</li><li>Your jaw (&#x4E0B;&#x5DF4;)</li><li>Your neck cords</li><li>Your shoulders</li><li>Your <strong>wrists</strong> (&#x624B;&#x8155;) and forearms</li><li>Your chest</li><li>Your upper back</li><li>Your lower back</li><li>Your stomach</li><li>Your <strong>hips</strong> ( &#x81C0;&#x90E8;)</li><li>Your hamstrings and rear</li><li>Your <strong>calves</strong> (&#x5C0F;&#x817F;), ankles, and feet</li></ul><p>Note which ones feel tight, and to gain some relief, breathe into the areas of tightness or pain.</p><p>You can also pay attention to what&#x2019;s happening with your body at different points during the workday, when specific events occur, or when you make certain decisions:</p><ul><li>How do you feel at 9 AM, noon, and 3 and 6 PM? Does your body change over the course of the day?</li><li>If you get stressed, does a particular part of your body react?</li><li>How often do you rely on a drink, drug, muscle <strong>relaxant</strong> (&#x677E;&#x5F1B;&#x836F;), or <strong>over-the-counter</strong> (&#x975E;&#x5904;&#x65B9;&#x7684;) pain relief over the week?</li><li>Does your body feel different after you exercise? Do your shoulders feel lighter?</li><li>How does your body feel on the weekend or when you&#x2019;re doing something you enjoy?</li></ul><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-5
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -27</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/11/MY-100-Day-English-27/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/11/MY-100-Day-English-27/</id>
    <published>2021-01-10T16:22:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-17T07:31:12.204Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="PLAY-DETECTIVE"><a href="#PLAY-DETECTIVE" class="headerlink" title="PLAY DETECTIVE"></a>PLAY DETECTIVE</h3><p><code>&#x505A;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x4FA6;&#x63A2;&#x6E38;&#x620F;</code></p><p>Once you&#x2019;ve labeled your anxiety, you can start pinpointing when it appears and why. Harley helped me learn to do this. When you feel anxious, take note of your physical reactions &#x2014; what she calls the &#x201C;early warning system&#x201D; that anxiety might be taking over.</p><p>Your triggers might be small. You might notice a stomach flip and a spark of <strong>dread</strong> (&#x6050;&#x60E7;&#xFF0C;&#x5BB3;&#x6015;) when you see someone&#x2019;s name pop up in your <strong>in-box</strong> (&#x6536;&#x4EF6;&#x7BB1;). Or they might be bigger. When unemployment numbers <strong>skyrocket</strong> (&#x4E00;&#x98DE;&#x51B2;&#x5929;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0A;&#x6DA8;), you might feel <strong>nauseous</strong> (&#x6076;&#x5FC3;&#x7684;) and unable to focus even though you still have a job.</p><p>When an interaction or a situation <strong>sets you off</strong> (&#x4EE4;&#x4F60;&#x5931;&#x671B;), examine why. You might be hesitant to <u>delve into</u> (&#x94BB;&#x7814;) issues from your childhood, but &#x201C;unresolved business&#x201D; from your past, as Colonna puts it, is very much <u>present in</u> (&#x51FA;&#x73B0;&#x4E8E;) &#x2014; and relevant to &#x2014; how you lead. He notes it can be a relief to truly understand how your old wounds inform your present behavior. When I realized that my near-constant worry about going broke <strong>stemmed</strong> (&#x8D77;&#x6E90;&#x4E8E;) more from my childhood than from my current financial situation, I was finally able to <strong>proactively</strong> (&#x4E3B;&#x52A8;&#x5730;) manage my money, after years of avoiding it and <u>piling up debt</u> (&#x79EF;&#x7D2F;&#x503A;&#x52A1;). I broke a damaging pattern.</p><p>It&#x2019;s also good to understand how you react when triggered. I call these anxiety &#x201C;tells.&#x201D; Social worker and therapist Carolyn Glass suggests asking yourself, &#x201C;How did I respond to that anxiety in that moment? And were those behaviors helpful or not? Did those behaviors <strong>fuel</strong> (&#x71C3;&#x6599;&#xFF0C;&#x523A;&#x6FC0;) or alleviate my anxiety?&#x201D; Glass says that writing down your fears will help you examine them. <a href="https://hbr.org/2017/07/the-more-senior-your-job-title-the-more-you-need-to-keep-a-journal" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Keeping a journal</a> of your anxiety &#x2014; when it happens, what triggers it, and how you reacted &#x2014; is a great way to develop self-awareness. Your tells may not always be negative behaviors, though; for instance, many of us find ourselves connecting with friends and family more during stressful times. When I&#x2019;m very anxious, I cook and freeze meals!</p><p>Many successful leaders react to anxiety by working harder, holding themselves and others to an impossibly high standard, or trying to control things that are beyond their power. For them, it&#x2019;s hard to imagine <em>not</em> <strong>fussing</strong> (&#x70E6;&#x8E81;) over every project and detail in their work lives, not taking responsibility for everything or always <u>giving their all</u> (&#x5168;&#x529B;&#x4EE5;&#x8D74;). &#x201C;People respond to anxiety by trying to be more perfect and more in control,&#x201D; Boyes says. &#x201C;They not only have a Plan B but Plans C, D, and E.&#x201D; In many societies those behaviors are rewarded. We think of it as a &#x201C;good work ethic,&#x201D; but often <strong>perfectionism</strong> (&#x5B8C;&#x7F8E;&#x4E3B;&#x4E49;) and overwork only cause further anxiety &#x2014; in yourself and others.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-4
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -26</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/10/MY-100-Day-English-26/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/10/MY-100-Day-English-26/</id>
    <published>2021-01-10T06:12:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-10T06:47:44.611Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="Acknowledging-and-Accepting-Your-Emotions"><a href="#Acknowledging-and-Accepting-Your-Emotions" class="headerlink" title="Acknowledging and Accepting Your Emotions"></a>Acknowledging and Accepting Your Emotions</h3><p><code>&#x627F;&#x8BA4;&#x5E76;&#x63A5;&#x53D7;&#x4F60;&#x7684;&#x60C5;&#x7EEA;</code></p><p>A common coping mechanism for leaders is to push through stress, fatigue, and fear. But that&#x2019;s succeeding <em>in spite of</em> your emotions, when it&#x2019;s far better to thrive <em>because of</em> your emotions. You have to learn to accept your anxiety &#x2014; even though this may seem uncomfortable or counterintuitive.</p><h3 id="LABEL-WHAT-YOU&#x2019;RE-FEELING"><a href="#LABEL-WHAT-YOU&#x2019;RE-FEELING" class="headerlink" title="LABEL WHAT YOU&#x2019;RE FEELING"></a>LABEL WHAT YOU&#x2019;RE FEELING</h3><p><code>&#x7ED9;&#x4F60;&#x73B0;&#x5728;&#x7684;&#x611F;&#x53D7;&#x5206;&#x4E2A;&#x7C7B;&#xFF0C;&#x8D34;&#x4E2A;&#x6807;&#x7B7E;</code></p><p>Angela Neal-Barnett, an award-winning psychologist, expert on anxiety among African Americans, and author of <a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/Soothe-Your-Nerves/Angela-Neal-Barnett/9780743225380" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Soothe Your Nerves</em></a>, is a firm believer in being honest with yourself. When you name a feeling &#x2014; by saying to yourself &#x201C;I&#x2019;m anxious&#x201D; &#x2014; you can begin to address it. You can learn how anxiety informs your behavior and your decisions and what causes it to surge, which will equip you to manage it.</p><p>No one has to hear you say it. This is for you. Take the time to wallow in your thoughts. Let yourself experience the discomfort of fear and anxiety. Play out worst-case scenarios in your head. Allow your imagination to go wild with catastrophe. Cry. Grieve. But don&#x2019;t turn away. As Alice Boyes, a former clinical psychologist and author of <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/316156/the-anxiety-toolkit-by-alice-boyes-phd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The Anxiety Toolkit</em></a>, says: The more you try to control your anxiety, the more it fights back.</p><p>Decades of research on emotional intelligence have shown that people who understand their own feelings have <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0263786316300291" target="_blank" rel="noopener">higher job satisfaction</a>, <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/job.714" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stronger job performance</a>, and better<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0191886902002428" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> relationships</a>; are <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/282072988_Emotional_Intelligence_and_Entrepreneurs&apos;_innovativeness_towards_Entrepreneurial_Success_A_Preliminary_Study" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more innovative</a>; and can <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/267368228_Emotional_Intelligence_and_Conflict_Management_Styles" target="_blank" rel="noopener">synthesize diverse opinions and lessen conflict</a>. And all those things make people <a href="https://hbr.org/2004/01/what-makes-a-leader" target="_blank" rel="noopener">better leaders</a>.</p><p>If the word &#x201C;anxiety&#x201D; feels wrong to you, label it whatever you like. Call it &#x201C;unease&#x201D; or &#x201C;temporary uncertainty&#x201D; or even give it a silly name. I think of my own anxiety as a separate character who travels with me. She doesn&#x2019;t have a name or a face, but I know when she&#x2019;s present.</p><p>The leadership coach and CEO of Reboot, Jerry Colonna, says that the best way to deal with uncomfortable feelings is to welcome them in. Think of your thoughts and emotions as trains coming in and out of a station, he advises. Watch them arrive and depart <u>without attachment</u> (&#x65E0;&#x7275;&#x6302;&#xFF0C;&#x65E0;&#x4F9D;&#x604B;). Imagine saying, &#x201C;Hello, anxiety. See you later, fear.&#x201D; This technique actually will help you build distance from the negative feelings in your mind.</p><p>Sometimes it may be impossible to get rid of your anxiety, which can feel <strong>frustrating</strong>. Rebecca Harley, a psychologist at Massachusetts General Hospital and Harvard Medical School, emphasizes, &#x201C;The goal is not to magically make things perfect. The goal is to learn to surf the waves of <strong>distress</strong> (&#x5371;&#x96BE;&#xFF0C;&#x60B2;&#x75DB;&#xFF0C;&#x8D2B;&#x56F0;) successfully. Give yourself credit even if things don&#x2019;t feel all the way better.&#x201D;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-3
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -25</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/09/MY-100-Day-English-25/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/09/MY-100-Day-English-25/</id>
    <published>2021-01-09T08:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-09T12:12:31.649Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>In the United States, anxiety is the most common mental illness, affecting more than 40 million adults each year. Data from the National Institute of Mental Health has indicated that about 30% of Americans experience clinical anxiety at some point in their lives. Globally, according to the Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation, an estimated 284 million people had an anxiety disorder <strong><u>as of</u></strong> (&#x622A;&#x81F3;&#xFF0C;&#x5230;&#x2026;&#x65F6;&#x5019;&#x4E3A;&#x6B62;) 2017, making it the most prevalent mental disorder worldwide. And recent workplace data from Mind Share Partners, SAP, and Qualtrics suggests it&#x2019;s widespread on the job: Nearly 37% of workplace respondents reported symptoms of anxiety in the past year. These numbers will only increase in the wake of the pandemic.</p><p>The good news for those of us who have managed anxiety for a long time is that we were made for this moment. <a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2015/12/151229070643.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data shows</a> that anxious people process threats differently, using regions of the brain responsible for action. We react quickly in the face of danger. We may also be more comfortable with uncomfortable feelings. When channeled thoughtfully, anxiety can motivate us to make our teams more <strong>resourceful</strong> (&#x8DB3;&#x667A;&#x591A;&#x8C0B;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x8D44;&#x6E90;&#x4E30;&#x5BCC;&#x7684;), productive, and creative. It can break down barriers and create new bonds.</p><p>So anxiety isn&#x2019;t useless. In an economic crisis, the anxiety that keeps us up at night may help us <strong>fathom</strong> (&#x5F7B;&#x5E95;&#x4E86;&#x89E3;&#xFF0C;&#x7422;&#x78E8;) a solution to keeping our businesses open. But left unchecked, anxiety distracts us, zaps our energy, and drives us to make poor decisions. Anxiety is a powerful enemy, so we must make it our partner.</p><p>Whether you have a diagnosed anxiety disorder or are having your first dance with this intense emotion, you can still be an effective leader. But I&#x2019;ll be blunt: If you don&#x2019;t look your anxiety in the face at some point, it will take you down. This isn&#x2019;t easy, but doing it will change your life and your ability to lead others for the better.</p><p>So today, in this especially anxious moment, let&#x2019;s begin. The first stage is learning to identify your anxiety: how it <strong>manifests</strong> (&#x51FA;&#x73B0;&#xFF0C;&#x8868;&#x660E;) itself and how it feels. The second stage is taking action to manage it both day-to-day and in challenging moments. The third stage <strong>entails</strong> (&#x9700;&#x8981;&#xFF0C;&#x627F;&#x62C5;) making smart decisions and leading others in anxious times. Finally, the fourth stage involves building a support infrastructure to help you manage your anxiety over the long term.</p><p><mark>as of 2020</mark>: &#x622A;&#x81F3;2020&#x5E74;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -24</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/08/MY-100-Day-English-24/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/08/MY-100-Day-English-24/</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T16:27:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T13:03:23.946Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2020/05/leading-through-anxiety?ab=hero-main-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leading Through Anxiety</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2020/05/ANXIETY_AARONS-MELE_HERO.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><strong>The CEO of a startup</strong> <strong>is sitting</strong> in the office space she recently leased for her fast-growing company. It&#x2019;s <strong>rush hour</strong> (&#x4EA4;&#x901A;&#x62E5;&#x6324;&#x65F6;&#x95F4;&#xFF1B;&#x4E0A;&#x4E0B;&#x73ED;&#x9AD8;&#x5CF0;&#x65F6;&#x95F4;), but the streets outside are quiet, and so are the 600 empty <strong>cubicles</strong> (&#x529E;&#x516C;&#x5BA4;&#x9694;&#x95F4;) outside her office door. Just yesterday her leadership team made the tough but crucial decision to send everyone home to work for the foreseeable future. In 30 minutes she needs to lead a videoconference to reassure her employees. But she&#x2019;s <strong>despondent</strong> (&#x6CAE;&#x4E27;&#x7684;, anxious, and just plain scared.</p><p>Versions of this scene have been playing out across the world over the past few months as Covid-19 cases rise and economies shut down. Founders, executives, managers, and employees have seen how fragile everything they&#x2019;ve built has become &#x2014; almost overnight. One evening back in March, my husband said to me, &#x201C;I&#x2019;m so scared, but I can&#x2019;t let all the people who depend on me see that.&#x201D; He had been on hours of Zoom calls, trying to convince his staff and colleagues that they would get through the crisis. He was supposed to be the face of calm, but he was terrified.</p><p>How can you lead with authority and strength when you feel anxious? How can you inspire and motivate others when your mind and heart are racing? And if you hide the fear in an attempt to be leaderlike, where does it go?</p><p>Anxiety, of course, has a purpose. It protects us from harm. Psychologist <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Meaning-Anxiety-Rollo-May/dp/0393314561" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rollo May first wrote in 1977</a>: &#x201C;We are no longer prey to tigers and mastodons but to damage to our self-esteem, <strong>ostracism</strong> (&#x6392;&#x65A5;) by our group, or the threat of losing out in the competitive struggle. The form of anxiety has changed, but the experience remains relatively the same.&#x201D; In other words, even though humans today aren&#x2019;t chased by predators, we are chased by uncertainty about the health of our loved ones, whether we&#x2019;ll have a job next week or next year, whether our company will go bankrupt &#x2014; worries that provoke the same neurological and physical responses.</p><p>According to the Anxiety and Depression Association of America, &#x201C;Stress is a response to a threat in a situation. Anxiety is a reaction to the stress.&#x201D; Anxiety is fear of what might happen in the future. Sometimes that fear is rational and sometimes not. And sometimes it&#x2019;s about something that will happen in three minutes (stepping onto a stage to make a presentation, for example) or in 30 years (having enough money to retire).</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Leading Through Anxiety
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -23</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/07/MY-100-Day-English-23/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/07/MY-100-Day-English-23/</id>
    <published>2021-01-06T16:49:20.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T07:31:49.746Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/blog/parenting-neuroscience-perspective/202012/7-ways-learn-more-effectively" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7 Ways to Learn More Effectively</a></p></blockquote><h2 id="7-Ways-to-Learn-More-Effectively"><a href="#7-Ways-to-Learn-More-Effectively" class="headerlink" title="7 Ways to Learn More Effectively"></a>7 Ways to Learn More Effectively</h2><p><code>&#x63A5;&#x7740;&#x4E0A;&#x4E00;&#x7BC7;</code></p><h3 id="5-Take-notes-in-class-or-while-watching-an-online-course-video-but-work-on-expanding-on-those-notes-immediately-after-the-lesson"><a href="#5-Take-notes-in-class-or-while-watching-an-online-course-video-but-work-on-expanding-on-those-notes-immediately-after-the-lesson" class="headerlink" title="5. Take notes in class (or while watching an online course video), but work on expanding on those notes immediately after the lesson"></a>5. Take notes in class (or while watching an online course video), but work on expanding on those notes immediately after the lesson</h3><p>In his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IlU-zDU6aQ0&amp;t=34s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">extremely popular lecture</a> on how to study smart, Marty Lobdell tells his students how important it is to take notes in class. There is no way to remember something you have learned in class (no matter how attentive you think you were) if you weren&#x2019;t jotting (&#x7B80;&#x77ED;&#x7684;&#x7B14;&#x8BB0;&#xFF0C;&#x8BB0;&#x7B14;&#x8BB0;) down notes.</p><p>But here is what he says is even more important &#x2014; as soon as class is over, go back to your notes and expand on them based on the lecture you just listened to. If this is not done, you run the risk of your notes seeming <strong>incomprehensible</strong> (&#x4E0D;&#x80FD;&#x7406;&#x89E3;&#x7684;) when you look back at them after a few days.</p><h3 id="6-Couple-facts-with-concepts-in-order-to-maximize-learning"><a href="#6-Couple-facts-with-concepts-in-order-to-maximize-learning" class="headerlink" title="6. Couple facts with concepts in order to maximize learning"></a>6. Couple facts with concepts in order to maximize learning</h3><p><code>&#x5C06;&#x4E8B;&#x5B9E;&#x4E0E;&#x6982;&#x5FF5;&#x7ED3;&#x5408;&#x8D77;&#x6765;&#xFF0C;&#x4EE5;&#x6700;&#x5927;&#x5316;&#x7A0B;&#x5EA6;&#x7684;&#x5B66;&#x4E60;</code></p><p>&#x50CF;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x5E38;&#x8BF4;&#x7684;&#x5C06;&#x7406;&#x8BBA;&#x4E0E;&#x5B9E;&#x9645;&#x7ED3;&#x5408;</p><p>It is <strong>inevitable</strong> (&#x5FC5;&#x7136;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0D;&#x53EF;&#x907F;&#x514D;&#x7684;), during learning, to have to memorize certain facts. Medical students, for instance, need to learn the names of all the muscles in the human body. Lobdell suggests, in the same lecture I mentioned previously, that the students would do better to learn the function of each muscle when they are learning its name.</p><p>Human memory is essentially an <strong>associative</strong> (&#x8054;&#x60F3;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x8054;&#x5408;&#x7684;) process, so we have a better chance of learning and remembering something well if we learn it <u>in context</u> (&#x5728;&#x4E0A;&#x4E0B;&#x6587;&#x4E2D;&#xFF0C;&#x8FDE;&#x8D2F;). Rather than just memorizing, for instance, that Mahatma Gandhi was assassinated in the year 1948, I&#x2019;d do better if I knew already that India attained its independence in the year 1947 and he was killed just a year later.</p><h3 id="7-Use-tests-as-a-way-to-learn-rather-than-an-assessment-tool"><a href="#7-Use-tests-as-a-way-to-learn-rather-than-an-assessment-tool" class="headerlink" title="7. Use tests as a way to learn, rather than an assessment tool"></a>7. Use tests as a way to learn, rather than an assessment tool</h3><p>Not only are tests useful to understand how much we have learned and how well we have learned it, but they can also be excellent learning tools. This again goes back to how retrieving information makes it easier to recall it in the future, compared to just being presented with information.</p><p><a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1111/j.1467-9280.2006.01693.x" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Studies have shown</a> that taking a memory test post-learning enhances later <strong>retention</strong> (&#x4FDD;&#x7559;) of the material learned; a phenomenon <strong>termed</strong> (&#x88AB;&#x79F0;&#x4E3A;) the &#x201C;testing effect.&#x201D; This is true even of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19586265/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unsuccessful</a> tests, where a person generates wrong answers before going on to learn the correct ones. Rather than confuse a person (as most people would imagine), it seems to be that merely trying to generate the correct answer activates <strong>semantic</strong> (&#x8BED;&#x4E49;&#x7684;) networks that are used later to remember the learned fact better.</p><p>While it is important to equip ourselves with the tools needed to make ourselves better learners, it is also essential to remember that we are all working with depleting mental resources due to the pandemic and its effects, and to be kind to ourselves at this time.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      7 Ways to Learn More Effectively-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -22</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/06/MY-100-Day-English-22/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/06/MY-100-Day-English-22/</id>
    <published>2021-01-05T16:46:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T06:15:58.048Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/blog/parenting-neuroscience-perspective/202012/7-ways-learn-more-effectively" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7 Ways to Learn More Effectively</a></p></blockquote><h2 id="7-Ways-to-Learn-More-Effectively"><a href="#7-Ways-to-Learn-More-Effectively" class="headerlink" title="7 Ways to Learn More Effectively"></a>7 Ways to Learn More Effectively</h2><p><code>&#x63A5;&#x7740;&#x4E0A;&#x4E00;&#x7BC7;</code></p><h3 id="3-Interleaving-related-skills-is-a-more-effective-technique-than-&#x201C;blocking&#x201D;"><a href="#3-Interleaving-related-skills-is-a-more-effective-technique-than-&#x201C;blocking&#x201D;" class="headerlink" title="3. Interleaving related skills is a more effective technique than &#x201C;blocking&#x201D;"></a>3. Interleaving related skills is a more effective technique than &#x201C;blocking&#x201D;</h3><p>While teaching children new concepts, &#x201C;blocking&#x201D; related or similar skills has been the <strong>norm</strong> (&#x89C4;&#x8303;&#xFF0C;&#x6807;&#x51C6;). For example, when teaching children to write, they are told to first practice writing a bunch of As, followed by a bunch of B&#x2019;s and so on. However, it has been shown that interleaving skills, that is, asking them to write an A followed by a B and then a C, and then go back to writing an A, is far more effective at producing lasting learning.</p><p>Why does this happen? It could be that interleaving helps learners <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10648-012-9201-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">discriminate (&#x533A;&#x522B;) between similar concepts</a> more easily than blocked practice does. <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-interleaving-effect-mixing-it-up-boosts-learning/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Studies</a> have also suggested that interleaving might help strengthen memory associations. Unlike blocking, which requires just the retrieval of one solution set at a time, interleaving requires our brains to be continually engaged, bringing up different solutions into <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/memory" target="_blank" rel="noopener">short term memory</a> and using them.</p><h3 id="4-Teach-a-topic-you&#x2019;re-learning-to-someone-else-or-pretend-to-do-so"><a href="#4-Teach-a-topic-you&#x2019;re-learning-to-someone-else-or-pretend-to-do-so" class="headerlink" title="4. Teach a topic you&#x2019;re learning to someone else (or pretend to do so)"></a>4. Teach a topic you&#x2019;re learning to someone else (or pretend to do so)</h3><p>I don&#x2019;t remember much of what I studied in school, but the topics that I do recall very well are those that I had been assigned to teach my peers. It has been shown that this enhanced learning while teaching could possibly be the result of <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/acp.3410?campaign=wolearlyview" target="_blank" rel="noopener">retrieving</a> what we have previously learned, rather than passively re-reading the material. In other words, it is a way of testing ourselves without actually doing so.</p><p><a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312019002237" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Several studies</a> have shown that children who served as tutors ended up having a greater understanding of the topic themselves. If you don&#x2019;t have the luxury of having a study group or a willing partner to listen to your teachings, simply learning a concept while assuming you have to teach it to others can be a great way to learn more effectively.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      7 Ways to Learn More Effectively-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -21</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/05/MY-100-Day-English-21/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/05/MY-100-Day-English-21/</id>
    <published>2021-01-04T17:42:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-06T16:39:12.051Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/blog/parenting-neuroscience-perspective/202012/7-ways-learn-more-effectively" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7 Ways to Learn More Effectively</a></p></blockquote><h2 id="7-Ways-to-Learn-More-Effectively"><a href="#7-Ways-to-Learn-More-Effectively" class="headerlink" title="7 Ways to Learn More Effectively"></a>7 Ways to Learn More Effectively</h2><p><code>What neuroscience tells us about how to maximize our learning potential.</code></p><h3 id="1-Break-up-your-learning-into-small-chunks"><a href="#1-Break-up-your-learning-into-small-chunks" class="headerlink" title="1. Break up your learning into small chunks"></a>1. Break up your learning into small chunks</h3><p>Studies have shown that rather than studying for long stretches at a time (&#x4E00;&#x6B21;&#x5B66;&#x4E60;&#x5F88;&#x957F;&#x65F6;&#x95F4;), giving ourselves <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21211793/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">small breaks</a> in between can greatly enhance focus. The problem here is not that we have brief <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/attention" target="_blank" rel="noopener">attention</a> spans &#x2014; it is that constantly paying attention to the same stimulus can cause our brains to regard it as potentially unimportant. An optical illusion called &#x201C;Troxler Fading&#x201D; is a good <strong>analogy</strong> (&#x7C7B;&#x6BD4;&#xFF0C;&#x6BD4;&#x55BB;) for this &#x2014; constantly <strong>fixating</strong> (&#x6CE8;&#x89C6;) on a particular point can cause unchanging points in our peripheral vision to &#x201C;fade away.&#x201D;</p><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210106001813.png"  alt></p><p>The scientist who performed this study <a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2011/02/110208131529.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wondered</a> if a similar principle might apply to thoughts as well &#x2014; constant attention to a particular thought or group of thoughts might just cause it to disappear from our awareness. This is where taking little breaks in between learning can be useful.</p><p>One of the most practical and oft-quoted applications of this idea is the <a href="https://todoist.com/productivity-methods/pomodoro-technique" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pomodoro technique</a> (&#x756A;&#x8304;&#x5DE5;&#x4F5C;&#x6CD5;). This technique involves working for <u>a stretch of 25 minutes</u>, followed by a short 5-minute break. This break is important, as we have discussed, to take our minds off the problem and activate different regions of the brain from those we were using while we were focused on the task. This not only provides an opportunity to get more creative, but it also keeps our temptation (&#x5F15;&#x8BF1;&#xFF0C;&#x8BF1;&#x60D1;&#x7269;) to get distracted <strong>in check</strong> (&#x53D7;&#x63A7;&#x5236;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x53D7;&#x68C0;&#x67E5;&#x7684;).</p><h3 id="2-Sleep-is-essential-for-successful-learning"><a href="#2-Sleep-is-essential-for-successful-learning" class="headerlink" title="2. Sleep is essential for successful learning"></a>2. Sleep is essential for successful learning</h3><p>Barbara Oakley, in her excellent <a href="https://talksat.withgoogle.com/talk/learning-how-to-learn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Talk at Google</a> on how the brain learns, coins the term (&#x629B;&#x51FA;&#x672F;&#x8BED;) &#x201C;focused mode&#x201D; for the parts of the brain that are activated when challenged with a familiar problem. In &#x201C;focused mode,&#x201D; she says, many of the neural connections are already made. But when we start to learn something completely new, another mode of the brain, the &#x201C;default mode,&#x201D; <u>comes into play</u>. The <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/default-mode-network" target="_blank" rel="noopener">default mode network</a> <strong>comprises</strong> (&#x5305;&#x542B;) a range of brain regions that are active when a person is at rest. These are probably the regions at work when we say &#x201C;I don&#x2019;t know how that idea came to me while I was washing the dishes. I wasn&#x2019;t even thinking about the problem!&#x201D; Given that it comprises diffuse brain regions, the default mode network can be useful at associating seemingly unrelated concepts or ideas.</p><p>This is one of the reasons why sleep is so important to learning. Studies have shown that sleep is essential for a few reasons &#x2014; for one, the process of consolidating <a href="https://news.mit.edu/2009/memories-0624" target="_blank" rel="noopener">short-term memories to long-term ones</a> happens in part during sleep. It has also been demonstrated in mice that sleep <a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/342/6156/373" target="_blank" rel="noopener">drives clearance of by-products of neural activity</a> from the brain, leading to a possible <strong>restorative</strong> (&#x6062;&#x590D;&#x5065;&#x5EB7;&#x7684;) effect.</p><hr><p>&#x5F53;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x7761;&#x7740;&#x65F6;&#xFF0C;&#x5927;&#x8111;&#x7684;&#x201C;&#x6E05;&#x7406;&#x201D;&#x8FC7;&#x7A0B;&#xFF1A;</p><blockquote><p><a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/366/6465/628" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Coupled electrophysiological, hemodynamic, and cerebrospinal fluid oscillations in human sleep</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://n.sinaimg.cn/translate/130/w600h330/20191102/9eeb-ihuuxut9848241.gif"  alt="img"></p><p><em>&#x56FE;&#x7247;&#x6765;&#x81EA;science&#x6742;&#x5FD7;</em></p><p>&#x77ED;&#x8BED;&#x8BCD;&#x7EC4;&#xFF1A;</p><p><strong>a stretch of 25 minutes</strong></p><p><strong>comes into play</strong> &#xFF1A;&#x5F00;&#x59CB;&#x53D1;&#x6325;&#x4F5C;&#x7528;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      7 Ways to Learn More Effectively
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -20</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/04/MY-100-Day-English-20/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/04/MY-100-Day-English-20/</id>
    <published>2021-01-03T17:36:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-04T17:40:58.201Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/articles/202008/love-what-really-matters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Love: What Really Matters</a></p></blockquote><p><strong>The Vital Importance of Erotic <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/empathy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Empathy</a></strong></p><p>by Joe Kort, Ph.D., LMSW</p><p>One of the most important ways to be sexually fulfilled is through deeper communication. &#x201C;<a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/sex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sexuality</a> is one of those topics that can be awkward to talk about,&#x201D; even for therapists, says psychotherapist Amanda Luterman, the founder of the Centre for Erotic Empathy in Montreal. She urges couples to explore and express erotic empathy by &#x201C;validating and including the unique experience of the person in front of you as a sexual being.&#x201D;</p><p>&#x201C;All too often, couples love each other, but there is noise between them, a feeling that they&#x2019;re not fully acceptable, not fully received, or not able to truly be their authentic erotic self,&#x201D; she says. &#x201C;Both people in a relationship have a <strong>plethora</strong> (&#x8FC7;&#x591A;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x8FC7;&#x5269;&#x7684;) of things that interest them, sexually speaking. In a relationship, we are not necessarily everything that our partners find attractive,&#x201D; but we allow our insecurities to convince us that we need to be, out of <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/fear" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fear</a> of being found inadequate or unappealing.</p><p>&#x201C;Eroticism is about two people wanting to feel desired and desirable with each other,&#x201D; Luterman says. &#x201C;Erotic empathy allows your partner to find you attractive. Even when you don&#x2019;t feel you are, your partner can see you in a way that you do not see yourself, and you have to understand that and allow it to happen. A mistake we make is rejecting our partner&#x2019;s initiative because we don&#x2019;t feel attractive.&#x201D;</p><p>So, if you come home from the gym feeling sweaty and smelly, but your partner is turned on by seeing you, Luterman advises, &#x201C;erotic empathy would say, &#x2018;Let me adjust this moment to include the conditions I require to be able to feel erotically present.&#x2019; Give your partner a kiss, put your hand on them, and say, &#x2018;I love that. Don&#x2019;t move. I need 12 minutes.&#x2019; If you don&#x2019;t feel you can enjoy your own body, it can be a distraction or a difficulty to be present with your partner, so those adjustments are really important.&#x201D;</p><p><em>Joe Kort, Ph.D., LMSW, is a sex and relationship therapist and co-director of Modern Sex Therapy Institutes.</em></p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Love-What Really Matters-5
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -19</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/03/MY-100-Day-English-19/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/03/MY-100-Day-English-19/</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T17:04:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-04T17:31:36.734Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/articles/202008/love-what-really-matters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Love: What Really Matters</a></p></blockquote><p><strong>&#x201C;Say the Thing&#x201D; to Save Your Relationship</strong></p><p>by Assael Romanelli, Ph.D.</p><p>In intimate relationships, ambiguous communication can lead to disaster, <strong>erecting</strong> (&#x5EFA;&#x8BBE;) a buffer between partners. People communicate <strong>obscurely</strong> (&#x6666;&#x6DA9;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x6A21;&#x7CCA;&#x7684;) in intimate relationships&#x2014; <em>It&#x2019;s complicated. I&#x2019;ll get back to you (&#x6211;&#x5C3D;&#x5FEB;&#x7ED9;&#x4F60;&#x56DE;&#x590D;). What do you think?</em> &#x2014;to avoid mistakes, to enable future denial, or to protect themselves from pain or hurt, or from <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/relationships" target="_blank" rel="noopener">intimacy</a> (&#x6027;&#x884C;&#x4E3A;&#xFF1B;&#x4EB2;&#x5BC6;). This can lead to high relational costs, though, such as relationship <strong>stagnation</strong> (&#x505C;&#x6EDE;), a decline of intimacy, and unnecessary pressure on a partner to try to read one&#x2019;s mind.</p><p>In theater <strong>improvisation</strong> (&#x5373;&#x5174;&#x521B;&#x4F5C;), there is a well-known rule: &#x201C;Say the thing.&#x201D; It means you should <strong>verbalize</strong> (&#x8BF4;&#x6E05;&#x695A;&#xFF0C;&#x63CF;&#x8FF0;) the reality of the moment, whether positive or negative. In <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/therapy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">therapy</a>, <strong>articulating</strong> (&#x660E;&#x786E;&#x6709;&#x529B;&#x5730;&#x8868;&#x8FBE;,&#x6E05;&#x695A;&#x7684;&#x8BB2;&#x8BDD;) the here-and-now of the moment is known as an &#x201C;immediacy skill.&#x201D; When you <u>name</u> (&#x8BF4;&#x51FA;) what is happening right now in your relationship, your confidence increases, because you hear yourself speak the truth, increasing your agency, self-respect, and sense of self. You take responsibility, confront your blind spots, and block your exits. Soon, communication becomes easier, as your partner gains a clearer sense of where you stand, becoming more likely to reciprocate (&#x62A5;&#x7B54;&#xFF0C;&#x4E92;&#x6362;) and more willing to join you in initiating repair. The result should be a relationship that is more vital and exciting because its intimacy has <strong>deepened</strong> (&#x52A0;&#x6DF1;).</p><p>Making a habit of saying the thing requires time, practice, and courage. Initially, your partner may respond with surprise, disappointment, or even insult. But with work, communication can improve. Start by reflecting on how your old patterns held your relationship back and aim to establish a fresh common language together, as well as a commitment to building an environment in which saying the thing is welcome. Call yourself out for avoiding an important question because you were embarrassed or surprised by it. And remember that in the long run, the work is worth it, because &#x201C;explicitly uncomfortable&#x201D; is better than &#x201C;implicitly vague.&#x201D;</p><p><em>Assael Romanelli, Ph.D., is a clinical social worker and a licensed couple and family therapist based in Jerusalem. He offers <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/online-therapy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">online counseling</a> for individuals and couples as well as online workshops for professionals.</em></p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Love-What Really Matters-5
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -18</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/02/MY-100-Day-English-18/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/02/MY-100-Day-English-18/</id>
    <published>2021-01-01T16:03:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T17:02:34.765Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/articles/202008/love-what-really-matters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Love: What Really Matters</a></p></blockquote><p><strong>Three Reasons to Be More Vulnerable</strong></p><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210103004729.png"  alt></p><p>&#x5728;&#x522B;&#x4EBA;&#x9762;&#x524D;&#x8868;&#x73B0;&#x51FA;&#x4F60;&#x7684;&#x8106;&#x5F31;&#x4E5F;&#x662F;&#x4E00;&#x79CD;&#x52C7;&#x6562;&#xFF0C;&#x800C;&#x5728;&#x4EB2;&#x8FD1;&#x7684;&#x4EBA;&#x9762;&#x524D;&#x771F;&#x5B9E;&#x7684;&#x8868;&#x73B0;&#x51FA;&#x4F60;&#x8106;&#x5F31;&#x7684;&#x4E00;&#x9762;&#xFF0C;&#x4E5F;&#x6709;&#x52A9;&#x4E8E;&#x5EFA;&#x7ACB;&#x4FE1;&#x4EFB;&#x611F;&#xFF0C;&#x4E5F;&#x53EF;&#x4EE5;&#x6539;&#x5584;&#x4F60;&#x548C;&#x4EB2;&#x5BC6;&#x4E4B;&#x4EBA;&#x6216;&#x662F;&#x548C;&#x81EA;&#x5DF1;&#x7684;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x3002;</p><p>by April Eldemire, LMFT</p><p>Imagine that your partner seems <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/anxiety" target="_blank" rel="noopener">anxious</a> about something. You&#x2019;re not sure what&#x2019;s going on, but you feel the tension in the air. How do you respond? Does part of you perceive this mood as a rejection of you? Do you <u>reach out</u> (&#x63D0;&#x4F9B;&#x63F4;&#x52A9;)? Do you know how?</p><p>The way you respond to such situations is influenced by how you access and express vulnerability. Far from a weakness, vulnerability&#x2014;the willingness to tell the truth and be yourself, even in the face of uncertainty&#x2014;is a resource you can develop to the benefit of your intimate connections. &#x201C;Vulnerability is having the courage to show up and be seen when we have no control over the outcome,&#x201D; psychologist Bren&#xE9; Brown has said. &#x201C;It&#x2019;s our greatest measure of courage.&#x201D; Here are three ways it can enhance a relationship:</p><ol><li>Vulnerability improves your relationship with yourself. By facing and working through uncomfortable situations, rather than <u>turning away</u> (&#x8F6C;&#x8EAB;&#x79BB;&#x5F00;) or shutting down, you teach yourself <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/resilience" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resilience</a> and increase self-confidence. You come to feel less dependent on others&#x2019; <strong>perceptions</strong> (&#x770B;&#x6CD5;&#xFF0C;&#x89C2;&#x5FF5;), promoting a sense of security that provides a solid foundation for connecting meaningfully with a partner.</li><li>Vulnerability establishes trust. We build trust when we speak truthfully about how we feel and what we need and give our partner space to do the same. Can this feel uncomfortable? Absolutely. But when we are willing to be vulnerable, we communicate that our relationship is a safe space to take chances. This trust is essential for discussing sensitive topics like money, sex, and <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/parenting" target="_blank" rel="noopener">parenting</a>.</li><li>Vulnerability strengthens your bond. With deeper trust, we learn that we can show up as ourselves in our relationship without fearing rejection or <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/embarrassment" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shame</a> because we are supported. Such a relationship becomes a powerful container in which to work together to heal past hurts, honor each other&#x2019;s needs, and manage conflict with respect and humility.</li></ol><p><em>April Eldemire, LMFT, is a psychotherapist who specializes in working with couples.</em></p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Love-What Really Matters-4
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -17</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/01/MY-100-Day-English-17/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/01/MY-100-Day-English-17/</id>
    <published>2021-01-01T12:32:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T16:46:41.081Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/articles/202008/love-what-really-matters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Love: What Really Matters</a></p></blockquote><p>Let Your Partner Be There for You</p><p>by Mark D. White, Ph.D.</p><p>We generally should not lie to our partners, but most people would agree that some lies are worse than others. Self-serving lies told to <u>cover up</u> (&#x63A9;&#x76D6;) an affair, for example, compound a betrayal with <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/deception" target="_blank" rel="noopener">deception</a> (&#x6B3A;&#x9A97;), prioritizing the cheater&#x2019;s (&#x9A97;&#x5B50;&#xFF0C;&#x80CC;&#x53DB;&#x8005;&#xFF0C;&#x8FD9;&#x91CC;&#x6307;&#x7B2C;&#x4E09;&#x8005;) interests over the partner&#x2019;s and denying the latter the respect he or she deserves.</p><p>So-called (&#x6240;&#x8C13;&#x7684;) <strong>benevolent</strong> (&#x4EC1;&#x6148;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x6148;&#x5584;&#x7684;) lies are <u>a different matter</u> (&#x4E0D;&#x662F;&#x4E00;&#x56DE;&#x4E8B;&#xFF0C;&#x53E6;&#x5F53;&#x522B;&#x8BBA;). But there is a class of benevolent lies that, however <strong>well-intentioned</strong> (&#x51FA;&#x4E8E;&#x597D;&#x610F;&#x7684;), can be <strong>corrosive</strong> (&#x8150;&#x8680;&#x7684;) to a relationship: lies told to <strong>withhold</strong> (&#x4FDD;&#x7559;&#xFF0C;&#x9690;&#x7792;) or <strong>disguise</strong> (&#x63A9;&#x9970;&#xFF0C;&#x4F2A;&#x88C5;) what partners truly need.</p><p>Suppose Harold and Sally have been married for 10 years, and fairly happily, but recently each has been dealing with different personal issues. Sally suffered medical problems that caused changes in her body she fears have made her less attractive to her husband. Harold has been arguing with his brother about their parents&#x2019; long-term care, which has <strong>dredged up</strong> (&#x8FFD;&#x5FC6;&#xFF0C;&#x56DE;&#x5FC6;) some emotional issues from his past and <strong>eroded</strong> (&#x4FB5;&#x8680;&#xFF0C;&#x524A;&#x5F31;) his <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/confidence" target="_blank" rel="noopener">self-confidence</a>.</p><p>Harold&#x2019;s problems have caused him to withdraw from Sally physically exactly when she needs his attention more than ever, and her feelings about her body have made it harder for her to reach out to Harold just when he needs someone to talk to about his family. Each knows basically what&#x2019;s going on with the other, but they are unwilling to tell the other what they need. Instead, motivated by a <strong>sincere</strong> reluctance to burden their partner, they say, &#x201C;I&#x2019;m fine, don&#x2019;t worry about me.&#x201D;</p><p>When we are suffering, we realize how much we need a partner to be there for us. This essential purpose of relationships is defeated, though, if we withhold our needs from them. We may think we&#x2019;re being kind, but our partner wants to help us, and rejecting that <strong>compassion</strong> (&#x540C;&#x60C5;&#xFF0C;&#x601C;&#x60AF;) can be hurtful and damaging. Although it may feel selfish, opening up about what you need from your partner is a truly benevolent act.</p><p><em>Mark D. White, Ph.D., is the chair of the Department of <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/philosophy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Philosophy</a> at the College of Staten Island/CUNY.</em></p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Love-What Really Matters-3
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -16</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2020/12/31/MY-100-Day-English-16/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2020/12/31/MY-100-Day-English-16/</id>
    <published>2020-12-31T13:49:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T16:46:34.987Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/articles/202008/love-what-really-matters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Love: What Really Matters</a></p></blockquote><p>Researchers haven&#x2019;t figured out yet how to prevent outside forces from affecting relationships, but being aware of their presence, creating rules to minimize their influence, and giving each other the benefit of the doubt are helpful steps in the right direction. When I was a sleep-deprived new mother who kept starting late-night fights, I finally made a rule for myself not to bring up any contentious topics after dinner. Six years later, I still regret it any time I break that rule.</p><p>Many of us spent the spring at home with our families. My colleagues and I surveyed nearly 2,000 people to ask how sheltering in place had changed their relationships. Not surprisingly, couples reported that they&#x2019;d become more <strong>irritated</strong> (&#x6FC0;&#x6012;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x6613;&#x6012;&#x7684;) with each other. But many also reported that they were spending more quality time together and were, overall, more satisfied with their relationships: The <strong>busyness</strong> (&#x5FD9;&#x788C;) of everyday life had been somewhat stripped away, allowing them to truly be together again. People told us about exercising and cooking together and starting new hobbies. They were doing activities they hadn&#x2019;t thought about before, or that they never felt they&#x2019;d have time to try.</p><p>I&#x2019;m curious to see how these couples are doing when we follow up with them this fall. Will they have made a lasting change to how they live their lives together? <u>For better and worse, we adapt quickly to new situations.</u> (&#x65E0;&#x8BBA;&#x597D;&#x574F;&#xFF0C;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x90FD;&#x4F1A;&#x8FC5;&#x901F;&#x9002;&#x5E94;&#x65B0;&#x73AF;&#x5883;) This means that even pandemic life soon becomes normal to us, but it also means we are likely to fall back into our old habits once life <strong>resumes</strong> (&#x6062;&#x590D;&#x5230;) its <strong>hectic pace</strong> (&#x7E41;&#x5FD9;&#x7684;&#x6B65;&#x4F10;). To fight this, we must make a new habit of paying attention. We can do this by asking ourselves each night: Did I pay attention today? Did I talk to my partner and say what I was thinking? Did I listen when my partner was talking? I urge us all to try it for a week and see what happens.</p><p><strong>Why <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/gratitude" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gratitude</a> Leads to Sexual Fulfillment</strong></p><p>by Mark Travers, Ph.D.</p><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20201231192931.png"  alt></p><p>Expressions of gratitude have been shown to have numerous psychological and physical benefits. One study found that keeping a gratitude journal improved <strong>diastolic blood pressure</strong> (&#x6539;&#x5584;&#x8212;&#x5F20;&#x538B;). Another found that focusing on things to be grateful about before bed each night increased pre-sleep calmness. Now, new research suggests there is a connection between gratitude and sexual satisfaction in committed relationships.</p><p>For a study in the journal <em>Social Psychology and <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/personality" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Personality</a> Science</em> , a team led by psychologist Ashlyn Brady of the University of North Carolina at Greensboro found that more-frequent expressions of gratitude increased couples&#x2019; sexual satisfaction by improving the emotional connection they experienced in their relationships.</p><p>&#x201C;Over the course of a relationship, most couples experience declines in sexual, and thus relational, satisfaction,&#x201D; the team posited. &#x201C;We predicted that gratitude would increase &#x2018;sexual communal strength&#x2019;&#x2014;the extent to which people are motivated to be responsive to their partner&#x2019;s sexual needs&#x2014;because gratitude motivates partners to maintain close relationships.&#x201D;</p><p>The researchers asked 118 couples to report the level of gratitude they expressed and received, as well as their degree of sexual satisfaction, over a 21-day period. Three months later, when the team had the couples complete the same measures again, they found that changes in gratitude were closely associated with changes in sexual satisfaction. In other words, people were sexually satisfied to the extent that they and their partner expressed and received a high degree of gratitude.</p><p>These findings, the research team believes, could help therapists design more effective interventions for couples experiencing sexual difficulties. &#x201C;<strong>Practitioners</strong> (&#x5B9E;&#x8DF5;&#x8005;) have often <strong><u>sought to</u></strong> (&#x5BFB;&#x6C42;) identify ways in which couples can maintain, or even improve, sexual satisfaction. The current results suggest that gratitude may be a promising method for achieving that goal,&#x201D; they <strong>concluded</strong> (&#x63A8;&#x65AD;&#xFF0C;&#x603B;&#x7ED3;). &#x201C;These studies suggest that experiencing and receiving gratitude increased the <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/motivation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">motivation</a> to meet a partner&#x2019;s sexual needs.&#x201D;</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Love-What Really Matters-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -15</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2020/12/30/MY-100-Day-English-15/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2020/12/30/MY-100-Day-English-15/</id>
    <published>2020-12-29T16:34:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-31T11:23:15.685Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/articles/202008/love-what-really-matters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Love: What Really Matters</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20201230203650.png"  alt></p><h1 id="Love-What-Really-Matters"><a href="#Love-What-Really-Matters" class="headerlink" title="Love: What Really Matters"></a>Love: What Really Matters</h1><p>A loving relationship can be an <strong>oasis</strong> (&#x7EFF;&#x6D32;) in uncertain times. Nurturing it requires attention, honesty, openness, vulnerability, and gratitude. Here&#x2019;s a guide to important facets (&#x5C0F;&#x5E73;&#x9762;) of intimacy.</p><h2 id="The-Fundamentals-of-a-Strong-Relationship"><a href="#The-Fundamentals-of-a-Strong-Relationship" class="headerlink" title="The Fundamentals of a Strong Relationship"></a>The Fundamentals of a Strong Relationship</h2><p>by Amie M. Gordon, Ph.D.</p><p>&#x7262;&#x56FA;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x7684;&#x57FA;&#x7840;</p><p><code>&#x8FD9;&#x90E8;&#x5206;&#x5185;&#x5BB9;&#x6211;&#x5927;&#x6982;&#x7528;&#x4E2D;&#x6587;&#x6982;&#x62EC;&#x4E00;&#x4E0B;&#xFF0C;&#x539F;&#x6587;&#x5728;&#x5F00;&#x5934;&#x7684;&#x94FE;&#x63A5;&#x5904;</code></p><p>&#x826F;&#x597D;&#x7684;&#x793E;&#x4F1A;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#xFF08;&#x7279;&#x522B;&#x65F6;&#x60C5;&#x4FA3;&#x6216;&#x8005;&#x592B;&#x59BB;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#xFF09;&#x5BF9;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x6765;&#x8BF4;&#x5F88;&#x91CD;&#x8981;&#xFF0C;&#x8FD8;&#x6709;&#x7814;&#x7A76;&#x8868;&#x660E;&#x5176;&#x751A;&#x81F3;&#x80FD;&#x51B3;&#x5B9A;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x201D;&#x751F;&#x6B7B;&#x201D;&#xFF0C;&#x8FD9;&#x4E0D;&#x662F;&#x5F00;&#x5B8C;&#x7B11;&#xFF0C;&#x6709;&#x835F;&#x8403;&#x5206;&#x6790;&#x6307;&#x51FA;&#xFF0C;&#x826F;&#x597D;&#x7684;&#x793E;&#x4F1A;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x6BD4;&#x6212;&#x70DF;&#x6216;&#x8005;&#x8FD0;&#x52A8;&#x8FD9;&#x79CD;&#x4EBA;&#x4EEC;&#x719F;&#x77E5;&#x7684;&#x80FD;&#x964D;&#x4F4E;&#x6B7B;&#x4EA1;&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x7684;&#x56E0;&#x7D20;&#xFF0C;&#x5BF9;&#x907F;&#x514D;&#x6B7B;&#x4EA1;&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x5177;&#x6709;&#x66F4;&#x5F3A;&#x7684;&#x4FDD;&#x62A4;&#x4F5C;&#x7528;&#xFF0C;&#x4E5F;&#x5C31;&#x662F;&#x8BF4;&#x826F;&#x597D;&#x7684;&#x793E;&#x4F1A;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x6BD4;&#x6212;&#x70DF;&#x6216;&#x8005;&#x8FD0;&#x52A8;&#x66F4;&#x80FD;&#x964D;&#x4F4E;&#x6B7B;&#x4EA1;&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x3002;&#x4F46;&#x8FD9;&#x4E5F;&#x4E0D;&#x662F;&#x8BF4;&#x5176;&#x4ED6;&#x4EBA;&#x7684;&#x5B58;&#x5728;&#x5BF9;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x591A;&#x91CD;&#x8981;&#xFF0C;&#x91CD;&#x8981;&#x7684;&#x662F;&#x90A3;&#x4E9B;&#x652F;&#x6301;&#x9F13;&#x52B1;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x4EBA;&#xFF0C;&#x800C;&#x7CDF;&#x7CD5;&#x7684;&#x4EBA;&#x9645;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x6BD4;&#x6CA1;&#x6709;&#x7684;&#x60C5;&#x51B5;&#x66F4;&#x5DEE;&#x3002;</p><p>&#x5F53;&#x5916;&#x90E8;&#x5C40;&#x52BF;&#x6709;&#x98CE;&#x9669;&#x65F6;&#xFF0C;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x66F4;&#x6709;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x8F6C;&#x5411;&#x6700;&#x4EB2;&#x5BC6;&#x7684;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#xFF0C;&#x4EE5;&#x6EE1;&#x8DB3;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x5BF9;&#x5B89;&#x5168;&#xFF0C;&#x63A5;&#x7EB3;&#x548C;&#x7231;&#x7684;&#x9700;&#x6C42;&#x3002;&#x65B0;&#x51A0;&#xFF0C;&#x7ECF;&#x6D4E;&#x8870;&#x9000;&#x548C;&#x653F;&#x6CBB;&#x52A8;&#x8361;&#x7B49;&#x8FD9;&#x4E9B;&#x4E0D;&#x786E;&#x5B9A;&#x65F6;&#x671F;&#x4E5F;&#x53EF;&#x80FD;&#x5448;&#x73B0;&#x51FA;&#x589E;&#x957F;&#x7684;&#x673A;&#x4F1A;&#xFF0C;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x4F1A;&#x88AB;&#x8FEB;&#x8131;&#x79BB;&#x5E38;&#x89C4;&#x8F68;&#x9053;&#xFF0C;&#x501F;&#x4EE5;&#x91CD;&#x65B0;&#x8BC4;&#x4F30;&#x4EC0;&#x4E48;&#x4E8B;&#x60C5;&#x5BF9;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x6765;&#x8BF4;&#x624D;&#x662F;&#x91CD;&#x8981;&#x7684;&#x3002;&#x5728;&#x5168;&#x7403;&#x4E0D;&#x786E;&#x5B9A;&#x6027;&#x7684;&#x60C5;&#x51B5;&#x4E0B;&#xFF0C;&#x5BF9;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x8FDB;&#x884C;&#x66F4;&#x591A;&#x6295;&#x8D44;&#x662F;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x5B89;&#x5168;&#x3001;&#x5B9E;&#x5728;&#x7684;&#x548C;&#x5065;&#x5EB7;&#x7684;&#x9009;&#x62E9;&#x3002;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x73B0;&#x5728;&#x6BD4;&#x4EE5;&#x5F80;&#x4EFB;&#x4F55;&#x65F6;&#x5019;&#x90FD;&#x9700;&#x8981;&#x7231;&#x3002;</p><p>&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x9700;&#x8981;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x5E2E;&#x52A9;&#xFF0C;&#x800C;&#x4E0D;&#x662F;&#x603B;&#x662F;&#x72EC;&#x81EA;&#x4E00;&#x4EBA;&#x625B;&#x8D77;&#x6240;&#x6709;&#x7684;&#x4E8B;&#xFF0C;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x9700;&#x8981;&#x544A;&#x8BC9;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x81EA;&#x5DF1;&#x6709;&#x591A;&#x7231;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x3002;</p><p>&#x53E6;&#x5916;&#xFF0C;&#x65E0;&#x8BBA;&#x4F55;&#x65F6;&#xFF0C;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x4E5F;&#x9700;&#x8981;&#x4E3A;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x6392;&#x5FE7;&#x89E3;&#x96BE;&#xFF0C;&#x548C;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x5206;&#x4EAB;&#x559C;&#x60A6;&#xFF0C;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x81EA;&#x5DF1;&#x4E5F;&#x8981;&#x4EAB;&#x53D7;&#x8FD9;&#x79CD;&#x6765;&#x81EA;&#x522B;&#x4EBA;&#x7684;&#x7231;&#x3002;</p><p>&#x6CA1;&#x6709;&#x4EBA;&#x6BCF;&#x6B21;&#x90FD;&#x662F;&#x6B63;&#x786E;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x4E5F;&#x9700;&#x8981;&#x6709;&#x5F7C;&#x6B64;&#x7684;&#x7A7A;&#x95F4;&#xFF0C;&#x539F;&#x8C05;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x6216;&#x81EA;&#x5DF1;&#x72AF;&#x7684;&#x5C0F;&#x9519;&#x8BEF;&#xFF0C;&#x5E76;&#x4ECE;&#x4E2D;&#x5438;&#x53D6;&#x6559;&#x8BAD;&#xFF0C;&#x4E89;&#x53D6;&#x5728;&#x4E0B;&#x6B21;&#x505A;&#x7684;&#x66F4;&#x597D;&#x3002;</p><p>&#x4E3A;&#x4E86;&#x5B9E;&#x73B0;&#x66F4;&#x597D;&#x7684;&#x4EB2;&#x5BC6;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#xFF0C;&#x6211;&#x4EEC;&#x5E94;&#x8BE5;&#x4ECE;&#x6BCF;&#x4EF6;&#x5C0F;&#x4E8B;&#x505A;&#x8D77;&#xFF0C;&#x591A;&#x5173;&#x6CE8;&#x4E00;&#x4E0B;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#xFF0C;&#x591A;&#x62BD;&#x51FA;&#x65F6;&#x95F4;&#x548C;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x5446;&#x5728;&#x4E00;&#x8D77;&#xFF0C;&#x8BB0;&#x5F97;&#x4E0D;&#x8981;&#x51B7;&#x843D;&#x4E86;&#x8FD9;&#x4E9B;&#x5BF9;&#x4F60;&#x91CD;&#x8981;&#x7684;&#x4EBA;&#x3002;</p><p>To achieve this, we can start with a simple step: paying <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/attention" target="_blank" rel="noopener">attention</a> to each other again. Eminent relationship researchers John and Julie Gottman have tracked couples for decades, and one of their key findings is that partners make bids for each other&#x2019;s attention. These bids can be small, like sharing an anecdote from the day or a gentle touch on the way past each other. Or they can be big, like asking for help solving a work problem or requesting a weekend away together. These bids go into an emotional savings account and add up to define a relationship&#x2019;s bottom line. Are we reaching out to our partners throughout the day? Are we responding to their bids? Or have we stopped paying attention to each other? Couples who are thriving create and respond to these bids, and these small investments add up and help them overcome harder times. But couples who are struggling tend to ignore them.</p><p>A demanding world makes investing in our relationships&#x2014;taking the time to talk and listen and to create and respond to bids&#x2014;all the more difficult. Whether we are juggling work and family demands or stuck at home in the midst of a quarantine, <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/stress" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stress</a>, lack of sleep, and other outside forces can make it difficult to be the best partner we can be. We&#x2019;re quicker to start a fight over an empty milk carton in the fridge or to see our partner&#x2019;s late night at the desk as an insult.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Love-What Really Matters
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
