<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>衷深学习</title>
  <icon>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/1a78ec769217974f51d40169d81d53e1</icon>
  <subtitle>石晓强的小站</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-02-18T15:54:06.641Z</updated>
  <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>石晓强</name>
    <email>2583551979@qq.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -65</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/18/MY-100-Day-English-65/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/18/MY-100-Day-English-65/</id>
    <published>2021-02-18T02:11:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T15:54:06.641Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/early/2021/01/06/dc20-1721" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status: A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210216115638.png"  alt></p><p><strong>CONCLUSIONS</strong> </p><p>In this study, we estimated the independent effects of BMI and T2D on household income and regional deprivation using a novel multivariable MR technique (8). Our results indicate negative effects of BMI but no effect of diabetes. </p><p>&#x200B;    These findings strengthen the evidence of the <strong>deleterious</strong> (&#x6709;&#x6BD2;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x6709;&#x5BB3;&#x7684;) role of BMI on income and regional deprivation reported in previous observational and one-sample MR studies (1,4&#x2013;6). The potential underlying mechanisms include a lower ability to work, higher absenteeism, higher probability of <strong>musculoskeletal</strong> (&#x808C;&#x8089;&#x9AA8;&#x9ABC;) injuries, and higher <strong>discrimination</strong> (&#x6B67;&#x89C6;), which may lead to poorer career prospects, decreasing labor market participation, and lower income (1). A lower income could in turn affect living standards, leading individuals to self-select into more deprived areas with more affordable housing and food options. </p><p>&#x200B;    Similar to a previous one-sample MR study (5), our results did not show any significant effect of T2D on household income or regional deprivation. In contrast, other studies that did not use a multivariate two-sample MR approach showed a negative effect of diabetes on socioeconomic outcomes (2,3). This result should be object of further studies, aiming at establishing whether this null effect can be replicated or whether it is mainly due to methodological shortcomings in our study. </p><p>&#x200B;    In fact, this study has some methodological limitations. First, despite the fact that genetic characteristics are independent of possible confounders, high BMI or diabetes genetic risk of parents might be an unmeasured confounder, causing a &#x201C;dynastic bias&#x201D; (15). Second, although the relevance assumption of our IVs is satisfied, the <u>explanatory power</u> (&#x89E3;&#x91CA;&#x529B;) of the set of SNPs used in the analysis for both the exposures and the outcomes is limited (10,11). Finally, because the UK Biobank population is a selected one (13), our results might suffer from selection bias. </p><p>&#x200B;    In conclusion, the current study provides evidence of a negative causal effect of higher BMI on income and regional deprivation, controlling for diabetes (&#x5E76;&#x63A7;&#x5236;&#x4E86;&#x7CD6;&#x5C3F;&#x75C5;&#x8FD9;&#x4E2A;&#x53D8;&#x91CF;). In contrast, T2D does not have an effect on these two socioeconomic outcomes. Further studies should investigate this result, using new generations of GWAS with a higher explanatory power and including a more representative population. Furthermore, applied research may help to improve the understanding for the underlying mechanisms and to create targeted strategies to break the negative connection between BMI and socioeconomic outcomes.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -64</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/17/MY-100-Day-English-64/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/17/MY-100-Day-English-64/</id>
    <published>2021-02-17T02:10:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T15:36:31.700Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/early/2021/01/06/dc20-1721" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status: A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210216115638.png"  alt></p><p><strong>RESULTS</strong> </p><p>In total, we included 69 SNPs for BMI and 42 SNPs for T2D, which overlapped at two distinct loci: FTO and TCF7L2 (Supplementary Table 2). Results of the univariable MR analysis indicated that a higher BMI was associated with a lower household income (&#x3B2;=20.092; 95% CI 20.138; 20.047) and with a higher regional deprivation (&#x3B2;=0.051; 95% CI 0.022; 0.079) (Table 1). </p><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210218122036.png"  alt></p><p>Diabetes did not have any effect on the socioeconomic outcomes considered. All analyses, except for BMI on income, presented low to middle levels of <strong>heterogeneity</strong> (&#x5F02;&#x8D28;&#x6027;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0D;&#x5747;&#x4E00;&#x6027;) (I 2 5 0&#x2013;57%), indicating good validity of the instruments. The difference between MR Egger and IVW estimates and a significant MR Egger intercept indicated the presence of horizontal pleiotropy, highlighting the need for multivariable MR analysis. The resulting effects from the multivariable MR analysis (Table 1) revealed that the direct effect of BMI controlling for diabetes was lower than in the univariable setting but still significant for both household income (b 5 20.089; 95% CI 20.13; 20.048) and regional deprivation (b 5 0.049; 95% CI 0.023; 0.075). Again, no effect of diabetes on socioeconomic outcomes could be observed. The results from the MR Egger regression were almost identical to the estimates resulting from the IVW regression, indicating that the multivariable approach successfully accounted for the bias resulting from horizontal pleiotropy in the univariable setting. All results were robust to the use of alternative estimation methods (Supplementary Material 3) and to the exclusion of other potentially pleiotropic SNPs (Supplementary Material 4).</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -63</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/16/MY-100-Day-English-63/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/16/MY-100-Day-English-63/</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T02:26:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T04:17:56.732Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/early/2021/01/06/dc20-1721" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status: A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210216115638.png"  alt></p><p><strong>Data</strong> </p><p>For the associations between SNPs and socioeconomic outcomes, we used publicly available summary-level data from a GWAS of UK Biobank data (12,13), including 464,708 individuals of European ancestry. Our outcomes were household income, defined as the average total household income before tax, and regional deprivation, defined using the Townsend deprivation index (14) (Supplementary Material 1). Regarding the exposures, we used summary-level data on the associations between SNPs and BMI or T2D from published meta-analyses of GWAS (10,11), excluding UK Biobank participants, because independency of data of the SNP-exposure and SNP-outcome association is a key <strong>prerequisite</strong> (&#x5148;&#x51B3;&#x6761;&#x4EF6;) for the validity of the two-sample MR approach (9) (Supplementary Materials 1 and 2).</p><p><strong>Statistical Analysis</strong> </p><p>First, we performed a univariable MR analysis, testing the single effects of BMI and diabetes on the outcomes (8). Second, we estimated two-sample multivariable MR analysis of the effects of BMI and diabetes on the outcomes, using the set of overlapping SNPs as instruments (10,11). We estimated the effects using the inverse-variance weighted (IVW)method (9). Furthermore, we tested their <strong>robustness</strong> (&#x7A33;&#x5065;&#x6027;) against other estimation methods, including median-based (&#x57FA;&#x4E8E;&#x4E2D;&#x503C;&#x7684;&#x65B9;&#x6CD5;), MR Egger, and MR-robust adjusted profile score (RAPS) methods (Supplementary Materials 1 and 3). Moreover, we tested the sensitivity of the results by excluding other potentially pleiotropic SNPs (Supplementary Material 4). In both the univariable and the multivariable analyses, we tested the effects of two exposures on two outcomes. We therefore assumed a conservative Bonferroni-corrected P value for statistical significance of 0.05/4 5 0.0125.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -62</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/15/MY-100-Day-English-62/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/15/MY-100-Day-English-62/</id>
    <published>2021-02-15T02:26:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T15:53:36.929Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/early/2021/01/06/dc20-1721" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status: A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210216115638.png"  alt></p><p>Previous evidence indicates that high BMI and type 2 diabetes (T2D) are associated with poorer labor market prospects, lower productivity, and higher <strong>absenteeism</strong> (&#x65F7;&#x8BFE;) (1&#x2013;6). These disadvantages may accumulate over time and affect income and living circumstances, leading to a selection of individuals in more regionally deprived areas. However, identifying the causal effect of BMI or diabetes on socioeconomic outcomes is challenging, mainly due to intrinsic problems of unmeasured confounding and reverse causation (1&#x2013;3). Earlier approaches focused on the use of instrumental variable (IV) methods, exploiting the disease status of biological parents as IV (1&#x2013;3). Recent studies have used genetic characteristics in one-sample Mendelian randomization (MR) approaches and showed an effect of BMI on socioeconomic status (4&#x2013;6), while no effect of diabetes could be revealed (5). This study aims at estimating the causal effect of BMI and T2D on household income and regional deprivation using a multivariable two-sample MR approach. <u>This approach allows considering the shared genetic components of BMI and diabetes (7) to jointly estimate their causal effects on these socioeconomic outcomes</u> (8).</p><p><strong>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS</strong> </p><p><strong>MR</strong> </p><p>The principle of MR roots in Mendel&#x2019;s laws of inheritance (i.e., the individual genotype is largely independent of external factors and therefore independent of potential confounders). In MR techniques, significant single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) that are associated with the exposure are <strong>exploited</strong> (&#x5229;&#x7528;) as <strong>exogenous</strong> (&#x5916;&#x751F;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x5916;&#x6E90;&#x7684;) genetic variation in the form of IVs (8,9). Genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have shown significant independent associations between several SNPs and BMI or T2D (10,11) but also the presence of distinct signals influencing both conditions (7). While the relevance assumption and exclusion criteria are satisfied for our data (see SupplementaryMaterial 1), this overlap could lead to horizontal pleiotropy that violates the exchangeability (&#x53EF;&#x66FF;&#x6362;&#x6027;) assumption (i.e., the same SNP independently influences multiple phenotypes) and could result in biased estimates (9). Horizontal pleiotropy can be overcome by using multivariable MR methods (i.e., by considering the overlapping instruments directly in the estimation) (8).</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -61</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/14/MY-100-Day-English-61/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/14/MY-100-Day-English-61/</id>
    <published>2021-02-14T02:25:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T15:53:42.850Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/early/2021/01/06/dc20-1721" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status: A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210216115638.png"  alt></p><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p><strong>OBJECTIVE</strong> To assess the independent causal effect of BMI and type 2 diabetes (T2D) on socioeconomic (&#x793E;&#x4F1A;&#x7ECF;&#x6D4E;&#x7684;) outcomes by applying two-sample Mendelian randomization (MR) analysis.</p><p><strong>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS</strong> We performed univariable (&#x5355;&#x53D8;&#x91CF;) and multivariable two-sample MR to jointly (&#x5171;&#x540C;&#x7684;) assess the effect BMI and T2D on socioeconomic outcomes. We used overlapping genome-wide significant single nucleotide polymorphisms for BMI and T2D as instrumental variables. Their causal impact on household income and regional <strong>deprivation</strong> (&#x5265;&#x593A;&#xFF0C;&#x8D2B;&#x56F0;) was assessed using summary-level data from the UK Biobank.</p><p><strong>RESULTS</strong> In the univariable analysis, higher BMI was related to lower income (<u>marginal effect</u> (&#x8FB9;&#x9645;&#x6548;&#x5E94;) of 1-SD increase in BMI [&#x3B2; = &#x2212;0.092; 95% CI &#x2212;0.138; &#x2212;0.047]) and higher deprivation (&#x3B2; = 0.051; 95% CI 0.022; 0.079). In the multivariable MR, the effect of BMI controlling for diabetes was slightly lower for income and deprivation. Diabetes was not associated with these outcomes.</p><p><strong>CONCLUSIONS</strong> High BMI, but not diabetes, shows a causal link with socioeconomic outcomes.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      The Effect of BMI and Type 2 Diabetes on Socioeconomic Status A Two-Sample Multivariable Mendelian Randomization Study
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -60</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/13/MY-100-Day-English-60/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/13/MY-100-Day-English-60/</id>
    <published>2021-02-13T02:25:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T15:53:48.084Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/20210216121635.png"  alt></p><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p><strong>Objective</strong> To determine whether height and body mass index (BMI) have a causal role in five measures of socioeconomic status.</p><p><strong>Design</strong> Mendelian randomisation study to test for causal effects of differences in <strong>stature</strong> (&#x8EAB;&#x6750;&#xFF0C;&#x8EAB;&#x9AD8;) and BMI on five measures of socioeconomic status. Mendelian randomisation <strong>exploits</strong> (&#x5229;&#x7528;) the fact that genotypes are randomly assigned at <strong>conception</strong> (&#x6000;&#x5B55;&#xFF1B;&#x6982;&#x5FF5;) and thus not confounded by non-genetic factors.</p><p><strong>Setting</strong> UK Biobank.</p><p><strong>Participants</strong> 119 669 men and women of British ancestry, aged between 37 and 73 years.</p><p><strong>Main outcome measures</strong> Age completed full time education, degree level education, job class, annual household income, and Townsend deprivation index.</p><p><strong>Results</strong> In the UK Biobank study, shorter stature and higher BMI were observationally associated with several measures of lower socioeconomic status. The associations between shorter stature and lower socioeconomic status tended to be stronger in men, and the associations between higher BMI and lower socioeconomic status tended to be stronger in women. </p><p>For example, a 1 standard deviation (SD) higher BMI was associated with a &#xA3;210 (&#x20AC;276; $300; 95% confidence interval &#xA3;84 to &#xA3;420; P=6&#xD7;10&#x2212;3) lower annual household income in men and a &#xA3;1890 (&#xA3;1680 to &#xA3;2100; P=6&#xD7;10&#x2212;15) lower annual household income in women. Genetic analysis provided evidence that these associations were partly causal.</p><p>BMI&#x9AD8;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x6807;&#x51C6;&#x5DEE;&#x4E0E;&#x7537;&#x751F;&#x5BB6;&#x5EAD;&#x5E74;&#x6536;&#x5165;&#x5C11;210&#x82F1;&#x9551;&#x76F8;&#x5173;&#x8054;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0E;&#x5973;&#x751F;&#x5E74;&#x6536;&#x5165;&#x4F4E;1890&#x82F1;&#x9551;&#x76F8;&#x5173;&#x8054;&#x3002;&#x9057;&#x4F20;&#x5206;&#x6790;&#x8868;&#x660E;&#x8FD9;&#x79CD;&#x5173;&#x8054;&#x662F;&#x5B58;&#x5728;&#x56E0;&#x679C;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x7684;&#x3002;</p><p>A genetically determined 1 SD (6.3 cm) taller stature caused a 0.06 (0.02 to 0.09) year older age of completing full time education (P=0.01), a 1.12 (1.07 to 1.18) times higher odds of working in a skilled profession (P=6&#xD7;10&#x2212;7), and a &#xA3;1130 (&#xA3;680 to &#xA3;1580) higher annual household income (P=4&#xD7;10&#x2212;8). Associations were stronger in men.</p><p>&#x8EAB;&#x9AD8;&#x9AD8;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x6807;&#x51C6;&#x5DEE;&#x5BFC;&#x81F4;&#x591A;0.06&#x7684;&#x6559;&#x80B2;&#x5E74;&#xFF0C;1.12&#x500D;&#x9AD8;&#x7684;&#x51E0;&#x7387;&#x8EAB;&#x5904;&#x9700;&#x8981;&#x6280;&#x80FD;&#x7684;&#x5DE5;&#x4F5C;&#x5C97;&#x4F4D;&#x4E2D;&#xFF0C;&#x5E74;&#x6536;&#x5165;&#x9AD8;1130&#x82F1;&#x9551;&#x3002;&#x8FD9;&#x79CD;&#x5173;&#x8054;&#x5728;&#x7537;&#x751F;&#x4E2D;&#x5173;&#x8054;&#x6BD4;&#x5973;&#x751F;&#x4E2D;&#x5F3A;&#x3002;</p><p>A genetically determined 1 SD higher BMI (4.6 kg/m2) caused a &#xA3;2940 (&#xA3;1680 to &#xA3;4200; P=1&#xD7;10&#x2212;5) lower annual household income and a 0.10 (0.04 to 0.16) SD (P=0.001) higher level of deprivation in women only.</p><p>&#x7531;&#x9057;&#x4F20;&#x51B3;&#x5B9A;&#x7684;BMI&#x9AD8;&#x4E00;&#x4E2A;&#x6807;&#x51C6;&#x5DEE; (4.6 kg/m2) &#xFF0C;&#x5BFC;&#x81F4;2940&#x82F1;&#x9551;&#x7684;&#x5BB6;&#x5EAD;&#x6536;&#x5165;&#x4E0B;&#x964D;&#xFF0C;&#x4EC5;&#x5728;&#x5973;&#x751F;&#x7FA4;&#x4F53;&#x4E2D;&#x9AD8;0.1&#x4E2A;SD&#x7684;&#x5265;&#x593A;&#x6307;&#x6570;&#xFF08;&#x8861;&#x91CF;&#x8D2B;&#x56F0;&#x7A0B;&#x5EA6;&#x7684;&#x6307;&#x6570;&#xFF09;</p><p><strong>Conclusions</strong> These data support evidence that height and BMI play an important partial role in determining several aspects of a person&#x2019;s socioeconomic status, especially women&#x2019;s BMI for income and deprivation and men&#x2019;s height for education, income, and job class. These findings have important social and health implications, supporting evidence that overweight people, especially women, are at a disadvantage and that taller people, especially men, are at an advantage.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Height, body mass index, and socioeconomic status mendelian randomisation study in UK Biobank
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -59</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/12/MY-100-Day-English-59/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/12/MY-100-Day-English-59/</id>
    <published>2021-02-12T02:25:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T15:53:54.141Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/the-secret-to-building-resilience" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Secret to Building Resilience</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_1125019608.jpg"  alt="img"></p><h3 id="Step-2-Plan-how-to-expand-your-network"><a href="#Step-2-Plan-how-to-expand-your-network" class="headerlink" title="Step 2: Plan how to expand your network."></a>Step 2: Plan how to expand your network.</h3><p>Reflecting on the top three resilience needs you indicated, place the names of people or groups that you could invest in to further cultivate sources of resilience. Connections that yield resilience can be <strong>intentionally</strong> (&#x6545;&#x610F;&#x7684;) cultivated in two ways. First, we can broaden existing relationships by, for example, exploring non-work interests with a teammate or strengthening mutually beneficial relationships with influential work colleagues that help us <strong><u>push back</u></strong> (&#x63A8;&#x8FDF;). Second, we can initiate engagement with new groups or people to cultivate important elements of resilience &#x2014; for example spiritual groups that remind us of our purpose, or <strong>affinity</strong> (&#x4EB2;&#x5BC6;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#xFF0C;&#x5438;&#x5F15;&#x529B;) groups that allow us to laugh. Broadening our network helps us develop dimensionality in our lives &#x2014; a rich variety of relationships and connections that help us grow, that can provide perspective on our struggles, and that can offer us a stronger sense of purpose.</p><p>These groups may come from any and all walks of life &#x2014; athletic pursuits, spiritual associations, nonprofit board work, community organizing groups around social, environmental, or political issues, etc. Engaging in nonwork groups (particularly board work, social action, and community organizing groups) helps us develop resilience in our work life as well. Exposure to a diverse group of people allows us to learn different ways of managing, leading, and handling crises, and helps us develop different relational skills such as negotiating with various <strong>stakeholders</strong> (&#x5229;&#x76CA;&#x76F8;&#x5173;&#x8005;). It also helps us cultivate empathy and perspective that we carry back into our work, among other benefits. In summary, meaningful investment in non-work relationships broadens the toolkit one can rely upon to manage setbacks when they arise.</p><p>One critical insight from our interviews is that relying on your network <u><strong>in times of</strong></u> (&#x5728;&#x2026;&#x7684;&#x65F6;&#x5019;&#xFF1B;&#x5728;&#x2026;&#x7684;&#x65F6;&#x671F;) transition <u><strong>matters a great deal</strong></u> (&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x91CD;&#x5927;&#xFF0C;&#x6781;&#x4E3A;&#x91CD;&#x8981;). When people told us stories of significant transitions &#x2014; moves, job losses, role expansions, or family changes &#x2014; they tended to separate into one of two groups. One group tended to lean into the transition and relied on existing relationships to work through the <strong>ambiguity</strong> (&#x542B;&#x7CCA;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0D;&#x660E;&#x786E;) and anxiety they were experiencing. This group also used the transition to reach out to one or two new groups such as a working parents group, a newcomers group, or a work-based coaching circle. In contrast, the second group operated with a <strong>mindset</strong> (&#x5FC3;&#x6001;&#xFF1B;&#x503E;&#x5411;&#xFF1B;&#x4E60;&#x60EF;) that they just needed to absorb the transition and closed in on their circle. They felt overwhelmed and said they would lean into activities when they had time in the future. Over the <strong>ensuing</strong> (&#x56E0;&#x800C;&#x53D1;&#x751F;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x968F;&#x540E;&#x7684;) 18 months, this group became a smaller version of themselves and often <strong>drifted</strong> (&#x6F02;&#x6CCA;&#xFF0C;&#x6F02;&#x6D41;) away from the connections that had been so important to their lives.</p><p>Covid has created a significant transition for us all. The importance of building and maintaining your connections has never been clearer. For most of us, the challenges and setbacks we are experiencing in work and life during this pandemic have been <strong>relentless</strong> (&#x65E0;&#x60C5;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x6B8B;&#x9177;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x4E0D;&#x95F4;&#x65AD;&#x7684;). But you&#x2019;re not alone in this battle. You can build resilience. Start by understanding the critical importance of growing, maintaining, and <u>tapping a diverse network</u> (&#x5229;&#x7528;&#x591A;&#x6837;&#x5316;&#x7684;&#x7F51;&#x7EDC;) to help you <u><strong>ride out</strong></u> (&#x5B89;&#x5168;&#x6E21;&#x8FC7;) the storm.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-The Secret to Building Resilience-5
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -58</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/11/MY-100-Day-English-58/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/11/MY-100-Day-English-58/</id>
    <published>2021-02-11T02:24:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T03:02:06.564Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/the-secret-to-building-resilience" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Secret to Building Resilience</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_1125019608.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>But such a network won&#x2019;t <strong>materialize</strong> (&#x5B9E;&#x73B0;&#xFF0C;&#x6210;&#x578B;&#xFF0C;&#x4F7F;&#x5177;&#x4F53;&#x5316;) overnight. When we talk to people who have shown exceptional resilience, it&#x2019;s clear that they often have cultivated and maintained <strong>authentic</strong> connections that come from many parts of their life &#x2014; not only through work, but through <strong>athletic</strong> (&#x8FD0;&#x52A8;&#x7684;) pursuits, volunteer work, civic (&#x516C;&#x6C11;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x5E02;&#x6C11;&#x7684;) or religious communities, book or dinner clubs, communities of parents they&#x2019;ve met through their children, and so on. Interactions in these spheres provide critical &#x201C;<strong>dimensionality</strong> (&#x7EF4;&#x5EA6;)&#x201D;, broadening their identity and &#x201C;opening the <strong>aperture</strong> (&#x5B54;&#x5F84;&#xFF0C;&#x5149;&#x5708;&#xFF0C;&#x89C6;&#x91CE;)&#x201D; on how they look at their lives. We become more (or less) resilient through our interactions with others.</p><p>Are your relationships broad and deep enough to help support you when you hit setbacks? Here&#x2019;s an exercise to help you think that through.</p><h3 id="Step-1-Identify-your-top-resilience-needs"><a href="#Step-1-Identify-your-top-resilience-needs" class="headerlink" title="Step 1: Identify your top resilience needs."></a><strong>Step 1:</strong> <strong>Identify your top resilience needs</strong>.</h3><p>Below are eight common relational sources of resilience, the same ones we noted above. Our research shows that these sources are not universally or equally important to everyone. For example, some people value laughter, while others prefer empathy. In short, our resilience needs are personal and are shaped by our unique history, personality, and professional/personal <strong>context</strong> (&#x73AF;&#x5883;&#xFF1B;&#x4E0A;&#x4E0B;&#x6587;). But collectively, the relationships we develop are a toolbox that we can turn to in our most difficult times, which we can rely upon to help us navigate day-to-day life challenges.</p><p>Using the framework below, identify the top three sources of resilience that you would <strong><em>most like to strengthen in your life</em></strong>. Make a note of those that are most important for you to work on developing.</p><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/W201215_CROSS_RESILIENCE.png"  alt="img"></p><p>&#x7406;&#x89E3;&#xFF0C;&#x4E86;&#x89E3;&#xFF1A;make sense of</p><p>pushback  vision  perspective</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-The Secret to Building Resilience-4
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -57</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/10/MY-100-Day-English-57/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/10/MY-100-Day-English-57/</id>
    <published>2021-02-10T05:44:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T03:02:01.435Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/the-secret-to-building-resilience" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Secret to Building Resilience</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_1125019608.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p>While, clearly, a portion of Jacob&#x2019;s <strong>fortitude</strong> (&#x575A;&#x97E7;) came from personal strength, our discussion with him revealed a number of ways that relationships <strong>bolstered</strong> (&#x652F;&#x6491;&#x7740;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x52A0;&#x56FA;&#x7684;) his resilience. A <strong>patchwork</strong> (&#x62FC;&#x51D1;&#x800C;&#x6210;) of different people in his network collectively played a critical role in helping Jacob navigate and survive this extraordinary period &#x2014; each offering a different perspective or <strong><u>helping hand</u></strong> (&#x63F4;&#x52A9;&#x4E4B;&#x624B;) <strong><u>in some way</u></strong> (&#x5728;&#x67D0;&#x4E9B;&#x65B9;&#x9762;&#xFF1B;&#x5728;&#x67D0;&#x79CD;&#x7A0B;&#x5EA6;&#x4E0A;). First, his boss was a continual source of input and validation, boosting Jacob&#x2019;s confidence as he faced unprecedented medical and leadership challenges. &#x201C;She always made herself available and these interactions helped me quit worrying endlessly about different decisions.&#x201D; In addition, he <u>tapped into</u> (&#x63A5;&#x8FD1;) the strong working relationship he had with another <u><strong>department head</strong></u> (&#x90E8;&#x95E8;&#x4E3B;&#x7BA1;&#xFF0C;&#x7CFB;&#x4E3B;&#x4EFB;) to <strong>jointly</strong> (&#x5171;&#x540C;&#x5730;) manage surges in workload. The resources he was able to &#x201C;borrow&#x201D; from this colleague enabled him to <strong><u>push back</u></strong> (&#x5411;&#x540E;&#x63A8;&#xFF0C;&#x63A8;&#x8FDF;) on non-essential work, as well as bypass typical <strong>bureaucratic</strong> (&#x5B98;&#x50DA;&#x7684;) <strong>gridlock</strong> (&#x4EA4;&#x901A;&#x5835;&#x585E;, &#x50F5;&#x5C40;) to <strong>secure</strong> (&#x4FDD;&#x62A4;&#xFF0C;&#x83B7;&#x5F97;) resources. &#x201C;At a couple of really important <strong>junctures</strong> (&#x63A5;&#x7F1D;&#xFF1B;&#x8FDE;&#x63A5;&#xFF1B;&#x63A5;&#x5408;), this helped us from getting over-run.&#x201D; And a very strong <u>chief of staff</u> (&#x53C2;&#x8C0B;&#x957F;&#xFF0C;&#x529E;&#x516C;&#x5BA4;&#x4E3B;&#x4EFB;) stepped in and took ownership of several work-streams put in place to help deal with Covid. For Jacob, knowing that this reliable person had those domains in hand &#x201C;took stress from a 10 to an 8 many times.&#x201D; Even his daily <strong>exchanges</strong> (&#x4EA4;&#x6D41;) with his office manager played a critical role &#x2014; she was able to find ways to laugh with him even under this stress. &#x201C;It wasn&#x2019;t <u>gallows humor</u> (&#x5145;&#x6EE1;&#x6028;&#x6068;&#x7684;&#x5E7D;&#x9ED8;&#xFF1B;&#x5316;&#x89E3;&#x4E25;&#x91CD;&#x573A;&#x9762;&#x6216;&#x50F5;&#x5C40;&#x7684;&#x5E7D;&#x9ED8;), but <strong>sarcastic</strong> (&#x6316;&#x82E6;&#x7684;) comments about difficult people or situations that lightened things for us and made us feel on the same team,&#x201D; he recalled.</p><p>Jacob was also lucky in that his home was a critical <strong>refuge</strong> (&#x907F;&#x96BE;&#xFF1B;&#x907F;&#x96BE;&#x6240;) for him through this time. His wife, who also had a medical background, provided an outlet to <strong>vent</strong> (&#x8868;&#x8FBE;&#xFF0C;&#x53D1;&#x6CC4;) that yielded both empathy and possible solutions. His children even played a role that he did not realize until past the early crisis: &#x201C;They were proud of me. They would tell me this, and it was better than anything else to help me <strong><u>buckle down</u></strong> (&#x503E;&#x5168;&#x529B;&#xFF1B;&#x5F00;&#x59CB;&#x8BA4;&#x771F;&#x4ECE;&#x4E8B;) and keep pushing through.&#x201D;</p><p>In short, Jacob shows us that resilience is found not just in having a network of supporters, but in truly connecting with them when you need them most. It&#x2019;s in the <em>actual interactions themselves</em> &#x2014; the conversations that validate your plans, reframe your perspective on a situation, help you laugh and feel <strong>authentic</strong> (&#x771F;&#x5B9E;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x53EF;&#x4FE1;&#x7684;) with others, or just encourage you to <u>get back up</u> (&#x91CD;&#x65B0;&#x7AD9;&#x8D77;&#x6765;) and try again because the battle is a worthy one &#x2014; that we become resilient. Yes, we&#x2019;re all told to build a network to help further our careers, but what&#x2019;s important to understand is how essential these relationships can also be to our day-to-day emotional well-being &#x2014; if we are building these relationships in the right way as we progress through our careers. Relationships may be our most undervalued resources.</p><p>&#x63F4;&#x52A9;&#x4E4B;&#x624B;&#xFF1A;helping hand</p><p>&#x5728;&#x67D0;&#x79CD;&#x7A0B;&#x5EA6;&#x4E0A;&#xFF1A;in some way</p><p>&#x90E8;&#x95E8;&#x4E3B;&#x7BA1;&#xFF0C;&#x7CFB;&#x4E3B;&#x4EFB;&#xFF1A;department head</p><p>&#x503E;&#x5C3D;&#x5168;&#x529B;&#x8BA4;&#x771F;&#x505A;&#x4E8B;&#xFF1A;buckle down</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-The Secret to Building Resilience-3
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -56</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/09/MY-100-Day-English-56/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/09/MY-100-Day-English-56/</id>
    <published>2021-02-09T06:10:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T03:01:57.688Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/the-secret-to-building-resilience" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Secret to Building Resilience</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_1125019608.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><code>resilience&#x4E0D;&#x662F;&#x7EAF;&#x7CB9;&#x662F;&#x4E00;&#x79CD;&#x4E2A;&#x4EBA;&#x7684;&#x7279;&#x5F81;&#xFF0C;&#x5F3A;&#x5927;&#x7684;&#x4EBA;&#x9645;&#x5173;&#x7CFB;&#x548C;&#x7F51;&#x7EDC;&#x4E5F;&#x5728;&#x5F88;&#x5927;&#x7684;&#x7A0B;&#x5EA6;&#x4E0A;&#x4FC3;&#x8FDB;&#x4E86;&#x8FD9;&#x79CD;&#x97E7;&#x6027;</code></p><p><span style="color:red"><strong>The ability to bounce back from setbacks is often described as the difference between successful and unsuccessful people.</strong></span> Resilience has been shown to <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3126102/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">positively influence work satisfaction and engagement</a>, as well as <a href="https://digitalcommons.unl.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?referer=&amp;httpsredir=1&amp;article=1010&amp;context=leadershipfacpub" target="_blank" rel="noopener">overall well-being</a>, and can <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5110375/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lower depression</a> levels. There is even evidence that resilience can help protect us from <a href="https://bpspsychub.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1348/135910707X186994" target="_blank" rel="noopener">physical illness</a>. But resilience, conventional thinking assumes, is something we find within ourselves only when we are tested (&#x7ECF;&#x53D7;&#x8003;&#x9A8C;&#x7684;&#x65F6;&#x5019;) &#x2014; a kind of solitary internal &#x201C;grit&#x201D; that allows those of us who are strong to bounce back.</p><p>But that&#x2019;s not necessarily true. Our research (which is not yet published) shows <u>that resilience is not purely an individual characteristic, but is also heavily enabled by strong relationships and networks</u>. We can nurture and build our resilience through a wide variety of interactions with people in our personal and professional lives. These interactions can help us to shift or push back on work demands and alter the <strong>magnitude</strong> (&#x5927;&#x5C0F;&#xFF1B;&#x91CF;&#x7EA7;) of the challenge we&#x2019;re facing. They can help <strong>crystalize</strong> the meaningful purpose in what we are doing or help us see a path forward to overcome a setback &#x2014; these are the kinds of interactions that motivate us to persist. People in our support systems can provide empathy or simply help us laugh and <strong>bolster</strong> (&#x652F;&#x6301;,&#x652F;&#x6491;) our resilience by shifting perspective and reminding us we are not alone in the fight. In short, resilience is not something we need to find deep down inside ourselves: we can actually become more resilient in the process of connecting with others in our most challenging times.</p><p>Based on in-depth interviews with 150 leaders (five men and five women from 15 different organizations who were considered to be among their &#x201C;most successful&#x201D; leaders), we have defined how connections can help us become more resilient when we encounter (&#x906D;&#x9047;&#xFF1B;&#x9082;&#x9005;&#xFF1B;&#x9047;&#x5230;) major life or professional challenges. A well-developed network of relationships can help us rebound from setbacks by:</p><ul><li>Helping us <em>shift work or manage surges</em></li><li>Helping us to *<u>make sense of</u> (&#x7406;&#x89E3;) people or politics in a given situation*</li><li>Helping us find the confidence to <em>push back</em> and <em>self advocate (&#x4E3B;&#x5F20;&#xFF0C;&#x62E5;&#x62A4;&#xFF0C;&#x5021;&#x5BFC;)</em></li><li>Helping us see *<u>a path forward</u> (&#x524D;&#x8FDB;&#x7684;&#x9053;&#x8DEF;)*</li><li>Providing <em>empathic support so we can release negative emotions</em></li><li>Helping us to <em>laugh at ourselves and the situation</em></li><li>Reminding us of the <em>purpose or meaning</em> in our work</li><li>Broadening us as individuals so that we maintain <em>perspective</em> when setbacks happen</li></ul><p>As Jacob (who was among those we interviewed) learned in what was unquestionably the toughest period of his entire career, resilience is a team sport.</p><p>&#x7406;&#x89E3;&#xFF0C;&#x641E;&#x6E05;&#x695A;&#x2026;&#x7684;&#x610F;&#x601D;: make sense of</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-The Secret to Building Resilience-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -55</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/08/MY-100-Day-English-55/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/08/MY-100-Day-English-55/</id>
    <published>2021-02-08T04:48:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-08T08:56:06.970Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/the-secret-to-building-resilience" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Secret to Building Resilience</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_1125019608.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><strong>Summary.</strong>  <u>The ability to bounce back from setbacks is often described as the difference between successful and unsuccessful people</u>. Resilience has been shown to positively influence work satisfaction and engagement, as well as overall well-being, and can lower depression levels. But resilience isn&#x2019;t just a kind of <strong>solitary</strong> (&#x5B64;&#x72EC;&#x7684;) internal &#x201C;<strong>grit</strong> (&#x7802;&#x783E;&#xFF1B;&#x52C7;&#x6C14;&#xFF0C;&#x51B3;&#x5FC3;)&#x201D; that allows us to bounce back. New research shows that resilience is also heavily enabled by strong relationships and networks. We can nurture and build our resilience through a wide variety of interactions with people in our personal and <u>professional lives</u> (&#x804C;&#x4E1A;&#x751F;&#x6D3B;&#x4E2D;). These interactions can help us to alter the magnitude of the challenge we&#x2019;re facing. They can help <strong>crystalize</strong> (&#x4F7F;&#x7ED3;&#x6676;, &#x4F7F;&#x5177;&#x4F53;&#x5316;) the meaningful purpose in what we are doing or help us see a path forward to overcome a setback &#x2014; these are the kinds of interactions that motivate us to persist. Are your relationships broad and deep enough to help support you when you hit setbacks? Here&#x2019;s an exercise to help you think that through (&#x5E2E;&#x52A9;&#x4F60;&#x601D;&#x8003;&#x6E05;&#x695A;).</p><p>An <strong>anesthesiologist</strong> (&#x9EBB;&#x9189;&#x5E08;) we&#x2019;ll call Jacob used to describe his job as &#x201C;90% <strong>boredom</strong> (&#x538C;&#x5026;&#xFF0C;&#x65E0;&#x804A;), 10% horror.&#x201D; With a few exceptions of challenging surgeries and managing a department of several hundred physicians and nurses, most of the time, Jacob&#x2019;s role was routine. But that was before the Covid-19 pandemic. Since anesthesiology is not a <strong>specialty</strong> (&#x4E13;&#x957F;&#xFF0C;&#x7279;&#x957F;) that can <u><strong>resort to</strong></u> (&#x4F9D;&#x9760;&#xFF0C;&#x6C42;&#x52A9;&#x4E8E;) remote &#x201C;telemedicine (&#x8FDC;&#x7A0B;&#x533B;&#x7597;),&#x201D; Jacob and his team entered an overwhelmed hospital day after day. &#x201C;For two months, I wasn&#x2019;t sleeping at night,&#x201D; he shared with us. &#x201C;I was sending my team into battle with <strong>inadequate</strong> (&#x4E0D;&#x5145;&#x5206;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x4E0D;&#x9002;&#x5F53;&#x7684;) protection, not even really knowing how many of them might get sick.&#x201D; The burden of being responsible for both a team he cared deeply about and the lives of a huge volume of patients affected by the pandemic was <strong>crushing</strong> (&#x60E8;&#x91CD;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x538B;&#x574F;). Routinely putting in 16-hour days, Jacob was having to determine how and when his team would work in these <strong>trying</strong> (&#x4EE4;&#x4EBA;&#x538C;&#x70E6;&#x7684;, &#x5C1D;&#x8BD5;) circumstances. &#x201C;There were nights and weekends when some [colleagues] called me and were crying on the phone. Let&#x2019;s face it, they were scared for their lives.&#x201D; And Jacob was, too.</p><p>But Jacob didn&#x2019;t break. He and his team have held together as they continued to do their work throughout the pandemic. So what allowed Jacob to endure this period of <strong>extraordinary</strong> (&#x975E;&#x51E1;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x7279;&#x522B;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x79BB;&#x5947;&#x7684;) stress? Resilience.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-The Secret to Building Resilience
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -54</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/07/MY-100-Day-English-54/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/07/MY-100-Day-English-54/</id>
    <published>2021-02-07T04:41:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-08T08:32:02.780Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/work-life-balance-is-a-cycle-not-an-achievement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Work-Life Balance Is a Cycle, Not an Achievement</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_-56377641.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><em>Continuous</em></p><h3 id="4-Consider-your-alternatives"><a href="#4-Consider-your-alternatives" class="headerlink" title="4. Consider your alternatives."></a>4. Consider your alternatives.</h3><p><code>&#x8003;&#x8651;&#x66FF;&#x4EE3;&#x9009;&#x9879;</code></p><p>Before jumping into solutions, first reflect on the aspects of your work and life that could be different in order to better align with your priorities. Are there components of your job that you would like to see changed? How much time would you like to spend with your family, or on hobbies? As one respondent illustrated, improving your situation takes time and experimentation:</p><blockquote><p><em>&#x201C;And it has taken me probably up to now, like my son is now two [years old], to get to a point where it&#x2019;s evolved into &#x2018;this is how it works&#x2019; [working more balanced hours], and it has taken that sort of length of time, probably longer than I wanted it to, but it&#x2019;s there now.&#x201D; (Michael, Audits Director)</em></p></blockquote><h3 id="5-Implement-changes"><a href="#5-Implement-changes" class="headerlink" title="5. Implement changes."></a>5. Implement changes.</h3><p><code>&#x5B9E;&#x65BD;&#x6539;&#x53D8;</code></p><p>Finally, once you&#x2019;ve recognized your priorities and carefully considered the options that could help you improve, it&#x2019;s time to take action. That can mean a &#x201C;public&#x201D; change &#x2014; something that <strong>explicitly</strong> (&#x660E;&#x786E;&#x5730;) shifts your colleagues&#x2019; expectations, such as taking on a new role that&#x2019;s designed to be less time-demanding or allows for a compressed-week model &#x2014; or a &#x201C;private&#x201D; change, in which you informally change your work patterns, without necessarily attempting to change your colleagues&#x2019; expectations.</p><p>In our research, we found that both public and private changes can be effective strategies, as long as they&#x2019;re implemented in a sustainable manner. For private changes, that might mean <strong>self-imposing</strong> (&#x81EA;&#x6211;&#x52A0;&#x5F3A;) boundaries (such as choosing not to work on evenings, weekends or during holidays &#x2014; and sticking to that decision), or turning down demands typically associated with your role (such as new projects or travel requests, even when you feel pressure to take them on). For public changes, rather than simply telling your supervisor that you want more <strong><u>time off</u></strong> (&#x4F11;&#x5047;&#xFF1B;&#x8BF7;&#x5047;) or more flexible hours, <strong>securing</strong> (&#x83B7;&#x5F97;&#xFF0C;&#x4FDD;&#x536B;) support from key mentors, partners, and coworkers &#x2014; or even better, formally applying for a new internal position or a flexible working scheme &#x2014; is likely to result in more lasting change.</p><p>Importantly, the five steps outlined above are not a one-time activity, but rather a cycle of continuous re-evaluation and improvement. Especially if you&#x2019;re under the influence of an overpowering (&#x538B;&#x5012;&#x6027;&#x7684;) culture of long work hours, it&#x2019;s easy to slide back into &#x201C;business as usual&#x201D; (whether that&#x2019;s a conscious or unconscious decision). In our interviews, we found that for people to make real changes in their lives, they must continuously remember to pause, connect with their emotions, rethink their priorities, evaluate alternatives, and implement changes &#x2014; throughout their personal and professional lives. </p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-Work-Life Balance Is a Cycle, Not an Achievement-4
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -53</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/06/MY-100-Day-English-53/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/06/MY-100-Day-English-53/</id>
    <published>2021-02-06T04:41:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-08T08:32:26.794Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/work-life-balance-is-a-cycle-not-an-achievement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Work-Life Balance Is a Cycle, Not an Achievement</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_-56377641.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><em>Continuous</em></p><h3 id="2-Pay-attention-to-your-emotions"><a href="#2-Pay-attention-to-your-emotions" class="headerlink" title="2. Pay attention to your emotions."></a>2. Pay attention to your emotions.</h3><p><code>&#x7559;&#x610F;&#x4F60;&#x7684;&#x60C5;&#x7EEA;&#x53D8;&#x5316;</code></p><p>Once you&#x2019;ve increased your awareness of your current situation, examine how that situation makes you feel. Ask yourself, do I feel energized, fulfilled, satisfied? Or do I feel angry, <strong>resentful</strong> (&#x6C14;&#x6124;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x538C;&#x6076;&#x7684;), sad? For example, one respondent (&#x5E94;&#x7B54;&#x8005;&#xFF0C;&#x8C03;&#x67E5;&#x5BF9;&#x8C61;) described his realization that his current work-life balance (or lack thereof) was <strong>engendering</strong> (&#x4EA7;&#x751F;&#xFF0C;&#x9020;&#x6210;) some pretty negative emotions:</p><blockquote><p><em>&#x201C;You feel resentful and bitter that something that fundamentally isn&#x2019;t that important to the essence of life is stripping valuable time and minutes away from you &#x2026; it&#x2019;s <strong>accentuated</strong> (&#x52A0;&#x91CD;) even more when you see someone who has lost their life or someone who has been told here&#x2019;s how much time remains on your clock.&#x201D; (Tobias, Audits Director)</em></p></blockquote><p>A rational understanding of the decisions and priorities driving your life is important, but equally important is <em>emotional</em> reflexivity &#x2014; that is, the capacity to recognize how a situation is making you feel. Awareness of your emotional state is essential in order to determine the changes you want to make in your work and in your life.</p><h3 id="3-Reprioritize-&#x53D8;&#x66F4;&#x4F18;&#x5148;&#x987A;&#x5E8F;"><a href="#3-Reprioritize-&#x53D8;&#x66F4;&#x4F18;&#x5148;&#x987A;&#x5E8F;" class="headerlink" title="3. Reprioritize (&#x53D8;&#x66F4;&#x4F18;&#x5148;&#x987A;&#x5E8F;)."></a>3. Reprioritize (&#x53D8;&#x66F4;&#x4F18;&#x5148;&#x987A;&#x5E8F;).</h3><p>Increasing your cognitive and emotional awareness gives you the tools you need to put things into perspective and determine how your priorities need to be adjusted. Ask yourself: What am I willing to sacrifice, and for how long? If I have been prioritizing work over family, for example, why do I feel that it is important to prioritize my life in this way? Is it really necessary? Is it really inevitable? What regrets do I already have, and what will I regret if I continue along my current path?</p><p>Our priorities often shift faster than our day-to-day time allocation habits. The interviewees that described a more positive work-life balance intentionally reprioritized how they spent their time in a way that <strong>lined up</strong> (&#x5BF9;&#x51C6;&#xFF0C;&#x6392;&#x5217;&#x6574;&#x9F50;) with their true priorities. One participant described how he still saw himself as a professional, but redefined that professional role to be more <strong>inclusive</strong> (&#x5305;&#x542B;) of other valued roles, such as that of parent:</p><blockquote><p><em>&#x201C;The more I really understand what&#x2019;s important in life &#x2014; and it&#x2019;s not really work &#x2014; it&#x2019;s, you know, understanding the relative importance of work. I still get a lot of satisfaction and stuff from work, but it used to be everything to me, and now it&#x2019;s less than half to me.&#x201D; (Dan, Audits Director)</em></p></blockquote><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-Work-Life Balance Is a Cycle, Not an Achievement-3
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -52</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/05/MY-100-Day-English-52/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/05/MY-100-Day-English-52/</id>
    <published>2021-02-05T01:05:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-08T08:38:11.775Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/work-life-balance-is-a-cycle-not-an-achievement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Work-Life Balance Is a Cycle, Not an Achievement</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_-56377641.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><em>Continuous</em></p><h3 id="1-Pause-and-denormalize-&#x4F7F;&#x975E;&#x89C4;&#x8303;&#x5316;&#xFF0C;&#x53CD;&#x5E38;&#x89C4;"><a href="#1-Pause-and-denormalize-&#x4F7F;&#x975E;&#x89C4;&#x8303;&#x5316;&#xFF0C;&#x53CD;&#x5E38;&#x89C4;" class="headerlink" title="1. Pause and denormalize (&#x4F7F;&#x975E;&#x89C4;&#x8303;&#x5316;&#xFF0C;&#x53CD;&#x5E38;&#x89C4;)."></a>1. Pause and denormalize (&#x4F7F;&#x975E;&#x89C4;&#x8303;&#x5316;&#xFF0C;&#x53CD;&#x5E38;&#x89C4;).</h3><p><code>&#x505C;&#x4E0B;&#x811A;&#x6B65;&#x4E0E;&#x53CD;&#x5E38;&#x89C4;&#x5316;</code></p><p>Take a step back and ask yourself: What is currently causing me stress, unbalance, or dissatisfaction? How are these circumstances affecting how I perform and engage with my job? How are they impacting my personal life? What am I prioritizing? What am I sacrificing? What is getting lost? Only after you take a mental pause and acknowledge these factors can you begin to <strong>tackle</strong> (&#x5E94;&#x4ED8;&#xFF0C;&#x5904;&#x7406;) them.</p><p>For instance, after several years of intense focus on her career, Maya, a <u><strong>senior associate</strong></u> (&#x9AD8;&#x7EA7;&#x7ECF;&#x7406;&#xFF0C;&#x9879;&#x76EE;&#x7ECF;&#x7406;) at a law firm, described feeling like she&#x2019;d hit rock bottom. It was only at this point that she was able to recognize the <strong>toll</strong> (&#x4EE3;&#x4EF7;) her overwork had been taking on her family &#x2014; and on her own mental and physical health:</p><blockquote><p>&#x201C;I was working quite long hours &#x2026; it was <u>a horrible sort of period</u> &#x2026; And I think for me, that was the key point. I thought, I am not doing this anymore, this is ridiculous. So, I think <u><strong>from then on</strong></u> (&#x4ECE;&#x90A3;&#x65F6;&#x8D77;), I have taken a real step back.&#x201D;</p></blockquote><p>Similarly, legal partner Kate told us that following the birth of her son, she experienced a major mental shift. She recognized that while the idea of &#x201C;[I] must work, must work, must work&#x201D; had been &#x201C;<strong>indoctrinated</strong> (&#x704C;&#x8F93;&#xFF0C;&#x6559;&#x5BFC;) into [her],&#x201D; she was now aware of the &#x201C;<strong>clash (&#x51B2;&#x7A81;)</strong>&#x201D; between this idea and &#x201C;where [she] was now&#x201D; as a mother. This life-changing event was the <strong>impetus</strong> (&#x52A8;&#x529B;) she needed to take a step back, become aware of the mismatch between her current situation and her personal priorities, and begin to <strong>denormalize</strong> her habit of working long hours.</p><p>Of course, the professionals we talked to all led very busy lives. Many of them explained that they didn&#x2019;t normally have the time or the energy to stop and reflect, and even expressed gratitude for the reflection space that the interview process itself allowed them. But while it&#x2019;s often a major life event &#x2014; such as the birth of a child, or the death of a loved one &#x2014; that <strong>catalyzes</strong> (&#x50AC;&#x5316;&#xFF0C;&#x523A;&#x6FC0;) these realizations, it&#x2019;s possible to take a pause and start rethinking your priorities at any time. And although some professionals may be fine with long work hours, taking the time to think through these questions and acknowledge the <strong>tradeoffs</strong> (&#x6743;&#x8861;) you&#x2019;ve made (whether intentional or not) is helpful for anyone looking to discover alternative ways of working and living.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-Work-Life Balance Is a Cycle, Not an Achievement-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -51</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/04/MY-100-Day-English-51/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/04/MY-100-Day-English-51/</id>
    <published>2021-02-04T01:05:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-08T05:26:46.313Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://hbr.org/2021/01/work-life-balance-is-a-cycle-not-an-achievement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Work-Life Balance Is a Cycle, Not an Achievement</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2021/01/Jan21_29_-56377641.jpg"  alt="img"></p><p><strong>Summary.</strong>  Research has definitively shown that overwork isn&#x2019;t good for employees or their companies &#x2014; and yet, in practice, it can be hard to overcome unhealthy work habits and reach a more sustainable work-life balance. To explore what it takes for busy professionals to make a change for the better, the authors conducted a series of interviews with mid- and senior-level managers at two global firms. They found that while the majority of <strong>respondents</strong> (&#x56DE;&#x7B54;&#x8005;&#xFF0C;&#x8C03;&#x67E5;&#x5BF9;&#x8C61;) assumed working long hours was inevitable, a significant minority of them were able to resist this pressure and achieve a healthier balance through a process of increasing awareness, conscious reprioritizing, and <strong>implementation</strong> (&#x5B9E;&#x73B0;&#xFF1B;&#x5C65;&#x884C;) of public and private changes. The authors go on to emphasize that to achieve lasting change, you must view this process not as a one-time activity, but as a cycle in which you constantly re-evaluate your evolving feelings and priorities, and adjust your work and life choices <strong>accordingly</strong> (&#x4E8E;&#x662F;&#xFF1B;&#x76F8;&#x5E94;&#x5730;&#xFF1B;&#x7167;&#x7740;).</p><p>Despite the <a href="https://hbr.org/2015/08/the-research-is-clear-long-hours-backfire-for-people-and-for-companies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resounding (&#x54CD;&#x4EAE;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x8F70;&#x52A8;&#x7684;) evidence</a> that working long hours can be harmful to both employees and employers, many professionals still struggle to overcome their assumptions &#x2014; and their <strong>deeply-ingrained</strong> (&#x6839;&#x6DF1;&#x8482;&#x56FA;&#x7684;) habits &#x2014; around work hours. What does it take to free yourself from these unhealthy patterns and reach a more sustainable, rewarding work-life balance?</p><p>To explore this question, <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0170840620934064" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we conducted</a> almost 200 <strong>in-depth</strong> (&#x6DF1;&#x5165;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x5F7B;&#x5E95;&#x7684;) interviews with 78 professionals from the London offices of a global law firm and an <u>accounting firm</u> (&#x4F1A;&#x8BA1;&#x4E8B;&#x52A1;&#x6240;). We spoke with an equal number of men and women, and most of the interviewees were between 30 and 50 years old, with at least one dependent child, and in either middle or senior management roles.</p><p>The majority of the interviewees described their jobs as <u><strong>highly demanding</strong></u> (&#x9AD8;&#x8981;&#x6C42;&#x7684;), exhausting, and chaotic, and they seemed to <u>take for granted</u> (&#x8BA4;&#x4E3A;&#x662F;&#x7406;&#x6240;&#x5F53;&#x7136;&#x7684;) that working long hours was necessary for their professional success. However, about 30% of the men and 50% of women in our sample appeared to consciously resist working long hours, describing a variety of strategies they developed for maintaining a healthier work-life balance. While the details of every individual case differed, our study suggested a common mental process that consistently helped this group of professionals to change the way they worked &#x2014; and lived &#x2014; for the better.</p><p>At a high level, our research showed that achieving better balance between professional and personal priorities <u><strong>boils down to</strong></u> (&#x5F52;&#x7ED3;&#x4E3A;) a combination of <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/00187267030568004" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reflexivity</a> (&#x81EA;&#x53CD;&#x6027;)&#x2014; or <strong>questioning</strong> (&#x6000;&#x7591;&#xFF0C;&#x8D28;&#x7591;) assumptions (&#x5047;&#x8BBE;) to increase self-awareness &#x2014; and <strong>intentional</strong> (&#x6545;&#x610F;&#x7684;) role redefinition. Importantly, our research suggests that this is not a <strong>one-time</strong> (&#x4E00;&#x6B21;&#x7684;) fix, but rather, a cycle that we must <u>engage in</u> (&#x53C2;&#x4E0E;) continuously as our circumstances and priorities evolve. This cycle is <u><strong>made up</strong></u> (&#x6784;&#x6210;&#xFF0C;&#x5316;&#x5986;) of five distinct steps:</p><p>&#x6839;&#x6DF1;&#x8482;&#x56FA;&#x7684;&#xFF1A;deeply-ingrained</p><p>&#x5F52;&#x7ED3;&#x4E3A;&#xFF1A;boils down to</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      HBR-Work-Life Balance Is a Cycle, Not an Achievement
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="HBR" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/HBR/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -50</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/03/MY-100-Day-English-50/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/03/MY-100-Day-English-50/</id>
    <published>2021-02-03T01:30:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-03T09:43:07.003Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Artificial intelligence accelerated by light</a></p></blockquote><p>The explosive growth of artificial intelligence calls for rapidly increasing computing power. Two reported photonic (&#x5149;&#x5B50;&#x6676;&#x4F53;) processors could meet these power requirements and revolutionize artificial-intelligence hardware.</p><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-020-03070-1/MediaObjects/41586_2020_3070_Fig1_HTML.png"  alt="Fig. 1"></p><p><em>Continuous</em></p><p>Feldmann and colleagues independently made an integrated photonic processor that performs a convolution involving optical signals that span two dimensions. The device uses optical frequency combs in an &#x2018;in-memory (&#x5185;&#x5B58;)&#x2019; computing architecture that is based on a phase-change material (a material that can switch between an <strong>amorphous</strong> (&#x65E0;&#x5B9A;&#x578B;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x975E;&#x6676;&#x8D28;&#x7684;) phase and a <strong>crystalline</strong> (&#x7ED3;&#x6676;&#x7684;) phase). The authors fully parallelized the input data through wavelength multiplexing and conducted <strong>analogue</strong> (&#x7C7B;&#x4F3C;&#x7269;) matrix&#x2013;vector multiplication using an array of integrated cells of the phase-change material.</p><p>Such a highly parallelized framework can potentially process an entire image in a single step and at high speed. Moreover, in principle, the system can be substantially scaled up using commercial manufacturing procedures and aid <em>in situ</em> machine learning in the near future. Because the convolution process involves passive transmission, the calculations of the photonic processing core can, in theory, be performed at the speed of light and with low power consumption. This ability would be extremely valuable for <strong>energy-intensive</strong> (&#x80FD;&#x6E90;&#x5BC6;&#x96C6;&#x578B;&#x7684;) applications, such as cloud computing.</p><p>Given the challenges facing conventional electronic computing approaches, it is exciting to see the emergence of integrated photonics as a potential <strong>successor</strong> (&#x7EE7;&#x627F;&#x8005;) to achieve <strong>unprecedented</strong> (&#x7A7A;&#x524D;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x65E0;&#x524D;&#x4F8B;&#x7684;) performance for future computing architectures. However, building a practical optical computer will require extensive <strong>interdisciplinary</strong> (&#x8DE8;&#x5B66;&#x79D1;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x8DE8;&#x9886;&#x57DF;&#x7684;) efforts and collaborations between researchers in materials science, photonics, electronics and so on. Although the reported photonic processors have high computing power per unit area and potential <strong>scalability</strong> (&#x53EF;&#x6269;&#x5C55;&#x6027;), the all-optical computing scale (the number of optical artificial neurons) remains small. Moreover, the energy efficiency is limited by the presence of computing elements that <strong>inherently</strong> (&#x5185;&#x5728;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x56FA;&#x6709;&#x7684;) absorb light and because electrical and optical signals frequently need to be <strong>interconverted</strong> (&#x4E92;&#x6362;).</p><p>Another <strong>avenue</strong> (&#x9014;&#x5F84;&#xFF0C;&#x624B;&#x6BB5;&#xFF0C;&#x6797;&#x836B;&#x5927;&#x9053;) of research is the development of advanced nonlinear integrated photonic computing architectures, rather than one- or two-dimensional linear convolutions (&#x4E00;&#x7EF4;&#x6216;&#x8005;&#x4E8C;&#x7EF4;&#x7684;&#x7EBF;&#x6027;&#x5377;&#x79EF;). By integrating electronic circuits and thousands or millions of photonic processors into a suitable architecture, a hybrid optical&#x2013;electronic framework that takes advantage of both photonic and electronic processors could revolutionize AI hardware in the near future. Such hardware would have important applications in areas such as communication, data-centre operation and cloud computing.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Nature-Artificial intelligence accelerated by light-3
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="Nature" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/Nature/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -49</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/02/MY-100-Day-English-49/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/02/MY-100-Day-English-49/</id>
    <published>2021-02-01T16:16:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-03T02:19:48.778Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Artificial intelligence accelerated by light</a></p></blockquote><p>The explosive growth of artificial intelligence calls for rapidly increasing computing power. Two reported photonic (&#x5149;&#x5B50;&#x6676;&#x4F53;) processors could meet these power requirements and revolutionize artificial-intelligence hardware.</p><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-020-03070-1/MediaObjects/41586_2020_3070_Fig1_HTML.png"  alt="Fig. 1"></p><p><em>Continuous</em></p><p>In the past few decades, great success has been attained in optical-fibre communication. However, it remains challenging to use photons for computing, especially at a scale and performance level comparable to those of <strong>state-of-the-art</strong> (&#x6700;&#x5148;&#x8FDB;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x5DF2;&#x7ECF;&#x53D1;&#x5C55;&#x7684;) electronic processors. This difficulty arises from a lack of suitable parallel-computing mechanisms, materials that permit high-speed nonlinear (complex) responses of artificial neurons and scalable photonic devices for integration into computing hardware.</p><p>Fortunately, developments over the past few years in devices called optical frequency combs (&#x5149;&#x5B66;&#x9891;&#x7387;&#x68B3;)<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y#ref-CR9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> brought new opportunities for integrated photonic processors. Optical frequency combs are sets of light sources with emission spectra that consist of thousands or millions of sharp <strong>spectral</strong> (&#x5149;&#x8C31;) lines that are uniformly and <u><strong>closely spaced</strong></u> (&#x5BC6;&#x96C6;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x95F4;&#x8DDD;&#x5C0F;&#x7684;) in frequency. These devices have achieved <strong>substantial</strong> (&#x5927;&#x91CF;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x5B9E;&#x8D28;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x5185;&#x5BB9;&#x5145;&#x5B9E;&#x7684;) success in various fields, such as spectroscopy (&#x5149;&#x8C31;&#x5B66;), optical-clock <strong>metrology</strong> (&#x5EA6;&#x91CF;&#xFF0C;&#x8861;&#x91CF;) and telecommunication, and were recognized with the 2005 Nobel Prize in Physics. Optical frequency combs can be integrated into a computer chip<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y#ref-CR9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> and used as power-efficient energy sources for optical computing. This system is well suited for data <strong>parallelization</strong> (&#x5E76;&#x884C;&#x8BA1;&#x7B97;) by <u>wavelength multiplexing</u> (&#x6CE2;&#x957F;&#x590D;&#x7528;).</p><p>Xu and colleagues used such a <strong>set-up</strong> (&#x8BBE;&#x7F6E;&#xFF0C;&#x88C5;&#x7F6E;) to produce a <strong>versatile</strong> (&#x901A;&#x7528;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x4E07;&#x80FD;&#x7684;) integrated photonic processor. This device performs a type of <u>matrix&#x2013;vector multiplication</u> (&#x77E9;&#x9635;-&#x5411;&#x91CF;&#x4E58;&#x6CD5;) known as a <strong>convolution</strong> (&#x5377;&#x79EF;&#xFF0C;&#x76D8;&#x7ED5;) for image-processing applications. The authors implemented an <strong>ingenious</strong> (&#x6709;&#x72EC;&#x521B;&#x6027;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x673A;&#x7075;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x7CBE;&#x5236;&#x7684;) method to <strong><u>carry out</u></strong> (&#x6267;&#x884C;&#xFF0C;&#x5B9E;&#x73B0;) the convolution. They first used <u><strong>chromatic dispersion</strong></u> (&#x5149;&#x7684;&#x8272;&#x6563;) &#x2014; whereby the speed of transmitted light depends on its wavelength &#x2014; to produce different time delays for wavelength-multiplexed optical signals. They then combined these signals along the dimension associated with the wavelength of the light (&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x6CBF;&#x7740;&#x4E0E;&#x5149;&#x7684;&#x6CE2;&#x957F;&#x76F8;&#x5173;&#x7684;&#x7EF4;&#x5EA6;&#x7EC4;&#x5408;&#x8FD9;&#x4E9B;&#x4FE1;&#x53F7;).</p><p>By fully exploiting the wide range of photon wavelengths, Xu <em>et al.</em> achieved intrinsically parallel computing for different convolution operations. The optical-computing speed was beyond ten trillion (&#x4E07;&#x4EBF;) operations per second using a single processing core and was limited only by the data throughput. Another welcome feature of this work is that the authors identify the entry point of their photonic convolution processor in practical applications. In particular, they suggest that the processor could be used in a hybrid optical&#x2013;electronic framework, such as for <u><em>in situ</em></u> (&#x539F;&#x4F4D;) computations during optical-fibre communications.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Nature-Artificial intelligence accelerated by light-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="Nature" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/Nature/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -48</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/01/MY-100-Day-English-48/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/02/01/MY-100-Day-English-48/</id>
    <published>2021-02-01T14:40:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-01T16:46:14.467Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Artificial intelligence accelerated by light</a></p></blockquote><p>The explosive growth of artificial intelligence calls for rapidly increasing computing power. Two reported photonic (&#x5149;&#x5B50;&#x6676;&#x4F53;) processors could meet these power requirements and revolutionize artificial-intelligence hardware.</p><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-020-03070-1/MediaObjects/41586_2020_3070_Fig1_HTML.png"  alt="Fig. 1"></p><p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is transforming various fields, such as clinical diagnosis, autonomous driving and speech translation. However, the quickly increasing volume of data in modern society poses great challenges for the electronic computing hardware used in AI, <u><strong>in terms of</strong></u> (&#x5728;&#x2026;&#x65B9;&#x9762;) both computing speed and power consumption. Such issues have become a major <strong>bottleneck</strong> (&#x74F6;&#x9888;&#xFF1B;&#x969C;&#x788D;&#x7269;) for AI. Writing in <em>Nature</em>, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-03063-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xu <em>et al.</em></a> and <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-03070-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Feldmann <em>et al.</em></a> report photonic processors that accelerate AI processing by <strong>harnessing</strong> (&#x5229;&#x7528;&#xFF0C;&#x63A7;&#x5236;) the distinctive properties of light. These demonstrations could inspire a <strong>renaissance</strong> (&#x65B0;&#x751F;&#xFF0C;&#x590D;&#x6D3B;) of optical computing (&#x5149;&#x5B66;&#x8BA1;&#x7B97;).</p><p>With the rise of AI, conventional electronic computing approaches are gradually reaching their performance limits and lagging (&#x843D;&#x540E;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x4FDD;&#x6E29;&#x6750;&#x6599;) behind the rapid growth of data available for processing. Among the various types of AI, <u>artificial neural networks</u> (&#x4EBA;&#x5DE5;&#x795E;&#x7ECF;&#x7F51;&#x7EDC;) are widely used for AI tasks because of their excellent performance. These networks perform complex mathematical operations using many layers of interconnected artificial neurons<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y#ref-CR3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a>. The fundamental operation that uses most of the computational resources is called <u>matrix&#x2013;vector multiplication</u> (&#x77E9;&#x9635;&#x5411;&#x91CF;&#x4E58;&#x6CD5;).</p><p>Various efforts have been made to design and implement specific electronic computing systems to accelerate processing in artificial neural networks. In particular, considerable success has been achieved using custom chips known as application-specific <strong><u>integrated circuits</u></strong> (&#x96C6;&#x6210;&#x7535;&#x8DEF;) <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y#ref-CR4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a>, brain-inspired computing<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y#ref-CR5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> and in-memory computing<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y#ref-CR6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a>, <strong>whereby</strong> (&#x51ED;&#x501F;&#xFF0C;&#x901A;&#x8FC7;) processing is performed <em>in situ</em> with an array of memory devices called <strong>memristors</strong> (&#x8BB0;&#x5FC6;&#x7535;&#x963B;&#x5668;).</p><p><strong>Electrons</strong> (&#x7535;&#x5B50;) are the carriers of information in electronic computing, but photons have long been considered an alternative option. Because <strong><u>the spectrum of light</u></strong> (&#x5149;&#x8C31;) covers a wide range of <strong>wavelengths</strong> (&#x6CE2;&#x957F;), photons of many different wavelengths can be multiplexed (transmitted in parallel) and <strong>modulated</strong> (&#x8C03;&#x8282;) (altered in such a way that they can carry information) <strong>simultaneously</strong> (&#x540C;&#x65F6;&#x5730;) without the optical signals interfering with each other. This <strong>propagation</strong> (&#x4F20;&#x64AD;&#xFF1B;&#x7E41;&#x6B96;&#xFF1B;&#x589E;&#x6B96;) of information at the speed of light results in minimal time delays. Moreover, passive transmission (in which no input power is required) aids ultralow power consumption<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y#ref-CR7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a>, and phase modulation (whereby the <strong>quantum-mechanical</strong> (&#x91CF;&#x5B50;&#x529B;&#x5B66;&#x7684;) phases of light waves are varied) enables light to be easily modulated and detected at frequencies greater than 40 <strong>gigahertz</strong> (&#x5343;&#x5146;&#x8D6B;) (ref. 8)<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03572-y#ref-CR8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">^8^</a>.</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Nature-Artificial intelligence accelerated by light
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="Nature" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/Nature/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -47</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/31/MY-100-Day-English-47/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/31/MY-100-Day-English-47/</id>
    <published>2021-01-31T01:26:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-31T15:52:17.799Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.economist.com/leaders/2021/01/23/the-outlook-for-america-looks-grim-but-that-could-quickly-change" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The outlook for America looks grim, but that could quickly change</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/joe%20biden.jpg"  alt></p><p><em>continuous</em></p><p>This will help lower the temperature of American politics, which could open other possibilities. By working with Republicans eager for Congress to get things done, Mr Biden may yet be able to pass an infrastructure bill and something on climate change, as well as his covid-19 package. In textbooks, democracy involves solving problems through compromise and managing conflict in elections. With a president inclined to build a <strong>coalition</strong> (&#x8054;&#x5408;&#xFF0C;&#x7ED3;&#x5408;), a little of that spirit might return to Washington. Voters may even prefer it to 24-hour <strong>partisan</strong> (&#x515A;&#x6D3E;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x6548;&#x5FE0;&#x7684;) <strong>warfare</strong> (&#x6218;&#x4E89;&#xFF0C;&#x51B2;&#x7A81;).</p><p>That is what needs to happen. America faces challenges that require the government to help, not just get out of the way. America has done a worse job of keeping schools open in the past year than any other rich country (see <a href="https://www.economist.com/united-states/2021/01/19/why-america-has-done-such-a-poor-job-of-keeping-schools-open" target="_blank" rel="noopener">article</a>). Enrolments have fallen, suggesting that many children have dropped out of education. Higher death rates for African-Americans and Hispanics are a reminder that health is linked to skin colour. Four years of Donald Trump have <u>hollowed out</u> (&#x6316;&#x7A7A;) institutions and weakened constraints on <strong>malfeasance</strong> (&#x6E0E;&#x804C;&#xFF0C;&#x8FDD;&#x6CD5;&#x884C;&#x4E3A;&#xFF1B;&#x4E0D;&#x6B63;&#x5F53;). His <strong>parting</strong> (&#x79BB;&#x522B;&#xFF0C;&#x5206;&#x5F00;) act was to pardon a doctor convicted of profiting from carrying out unnecessary eye treatment on hundreds of elderly patients. He rescinded his own executive order which would have stopped his administration&#x2019;s officials working as lobbyists.</p><p>The past four years have also created a problem for America abroad. <u><strong>At the back of their minds</strong></u> (&#x5728;&#x4ED6;&#x4EEC;&#x7684;&#x5185;&#x5FC3;&#x6DF1;&#x5904;), foreign leaders know that the forces which brought Mr Trump to office could return with a future president, so any agreements American <strong>diplomats</strong> (&#x5916;&#x4EA4;&#x5B98;) make risk seeming temporary. Mr Biden&#x2019;s foreign policy will also require a series of impossibly hard <strong>trade-offs</strong> (&#x6743;&#x8861;). His team needs the co-operation of the Russian government to sign an extension of the New start treaty on nuclear weapons, which <strong>expires</strong> (&#x5230;&#x671F;) on February 5th. Yet that same government has just locked up Russia&#x2019;s most prominent opposition politician, Alexei Navalny, after first attempting to kill him (see <a href="https://www.economist.com/leaders/2021/01/23/the-world-must-not-accept-the-jailing-of-alexei-navalny" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leader</a>). They need China&#x2019;s co-operation on climate change, even though China is engaged in what the outgoing administration has just labelled as &#x201C;genocide&#x201D; against the Uyghurs in Xinjiang.</p><p><strong>Tricky corners in the Oval Office</strong></p><p>A lot could go wrong. Senate Republicans may oppose everything Mr Biden suggests simply because he is a Democrat. The left of his party may <strong>turn sour</strong> (&#x4EE4;&#x4EBA;&#x5931;&#x671B;&#xFF1B;&#x4E0D;&#x53D7;&#x6B22;&#x8FCE;, &#x53D8;&#x9178;) on him for trying to make deals with Republicans. Politics has been simple during the Trump administration, which more often governed by <strong>inflaming</strong> (&#x6FC0;&#x6012;&#xFF1B;&#x4F7F;&#x71C3;&#x70E7;) <strong>partisan</strong> ( &#x515A;&#x6D3E;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x6548;&#x5FE0;&#x7684;) fights than fixing America&#x2019;s problems. <u>Engaging with reality</u> (&#x878D;&#x5165;&#x73B0;&#x5B9E;) is much harder&#x2014;especially when you are <strong>buffeted</strong> (&#x6253;&#x51FB;) by events.</p><p>To have the best chance of success, Mr Biden should stick to his <strong>folksy</strong> (&#x6709;&#x6C11;&#x95F4;&#x98CE;&#x5473;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x548C;&#x6C14;&#x7684;) brand of <strong>dogged</strong> (&#x987D;&#x5F3A;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x987D;&#x56FA;&#x7684;) <strong>centrism</strong> (&#x6E29;&#x548C;&#x4E3B;&#x4E49;&#xFF0C;&#x4E2D;&#x95F4;&#x8DEF;&#x7EBF;) which is so well suited to the moment. Western <strong>allies</strong> (&#x540C;&#x76DF;&#x56FD;) should be patient and not expect a miraculous overnight transformation. The return of restraint to the White House will be only the first step in a long journey, but it is a necessary one for America&#x2019;s <strong>renewal</strong> (&#x66F4;&#x65B0;&#xFF0C;&#x6062;&#x590D;&#xFF0C;&#x9769;&#x65B0;) (&#x767D;&#x5BAB;&#x6062;&#x590D;&#x514B;&#x5236;&#x5C06;&#x53EA;&#x662F;&#x6F2B;&#x957F;&#x65C5;&#x7A0B;&#x4E2D;&#x7684;&#x7B2C;&#x4E00;&#x6B65;&#xFF0C;&#x4F46;&#x5BF9;&#x4E8E;&#x7F8E;&#x56FD;&#x7684;&#x590D;&#x5174;&#x6765;&#x8BF4;&#xFF0C;&#x8FD9;&#x662F;&#x5FC5;&#x8981;&#x7684;&#x4E00;&#x6B65;).</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      The Economist-The outlook for America looks grim, but that could quickly change-2
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MY 100-Day English -46</title>
    <link href="https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/30/MY-100-Day-English-46/"/>
    <id>https://steven-shixq.github.io/2021/01/30/MY-100-Day-English-46/</id>
    <published>2021-01-29T16:44:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-31T06:53:10.202Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<link rel="stylesheet" class="aplayer-secondary-style-marker" href="\assets\css\APlayer.min.css"><script src="\assets\js\APlayer.min.js" class="aplayer-secondary-script-marker"></script><blockquote><p><a href="https://www.economist.com/leaders/2021/01/23/the-outlook-for-america-looks-grim-but-that-could-quickly-change" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The outlook for America looks grim, but that could quickly change</a></p></blockquote><p><img src="/" class="lazyload" data-src="https://gitee.com/XiaoqiangShi/imagehosts/raw/master/joe%20biden.jpg"  alt></p><p>Joe biden has been dreaming of moving into the White House since at least 1987, when he first ran for president. How those dreams must have differed from the reality this week. The official <strong>toll</strong> (&#x4EE3;&#x4EF7;&#xFF0C;&#x4F24;&#x4EA1;&#x4EBA;&#x6570;) of American deaths from covid-19 has passed 400,000. By the end of his first 100 days it may have passed 500,000. Millions of Americans have lost their jobs. Instead of observing the <strong>triumph</strong> (&#x80DC;&#x5229;&#xFF0C;&#x51EF;&#x65CB;) of democracy in eastern Europe from the Oval Office, as the victor of the election in 1988 did, Mr Biden must <u>contend with</u> (&#x5BF9;&#x4ED8;&#xFF0C;&#x6597;&#x4E89;) democratic <strong>decay</strong> (&#x8870;&#x9000;) at home. It is not an <strong>auspicious</strong> (&#x6709;&#x52A9;&#x4E8E;&#x6210;&#x529F;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x6709;&#x5229;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x5409;&#x7965;&#x7684;) start. Yet, unlikely as it sounds, in the next few months the view from 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue could improve dramatically.</p><p>Mending America starts with getting the virus under control. <strong>Vaccinating</strong> (&#x63A5;&#x79CD;) the population will be a <strong>formidable</strong> (&#x5F3A;&#x5927;&#x7684;&#xFF1B;&#x8270;&#x96BE;&#x7684;) operation that will test the ability of federal, state and local <strong>bureaucracies</strong> (&#x7E41;&#x6587;&#x8925;&#x8282;&#xFF1B;&#x5B98;&#x50DA;&#x653F;&#x6CBB;) to <strong>co-operate</strong> (&#x5408;&#x4F5C;). A <strong>slick</strong> (&#x5149;&#x6ED1;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x806A;&#x660E;&#x7684;) campaign of the type the federal government masterminded (&#x7B56;&#x5212;&#xFF0C;&#x7EC4;&#x7EC7;&#xFF0C;&#x64CD;&#x7EB5;) to <strong>eradicate</strong> (&#x706D;&#x7EDD;&#xFF0C;&#x6839;&#x9664;) <strong>polio</strong> (&#x5C0F;&#x513F;&#x9EBB;&#x75F9;) would save many lives. Yet even an imperfect vaccination programme will make a huge difference by the time spring turns into summer. Warmer weather, and hence longer spent outdoors, will help too. Covid-19 spreads <strong>exponentially</strong> (&#x6307;&#x6570;&#x5730;). But once the number of people each person infects falls below one, it also <strong>dissipates</strong> (&#x6D6A;&#x8D39;&#xFF1B;&#x4F7F;&#x2026;&#x6D88;&#x6563;) exponentially.</p><p>This in turn will help America&#x2019;s economic recovery. Though the labour market is about as depressed as it was when Mr Biden was sworn in as Barack Obama&#x2019;s vice-president in the teeth of the financial crisis, this downturn is very different. Real <u>disposable income</u> (&#x53EF;&#x652F;&#x914D;&#x6536;&#x5165;) probably rose at its fastest rate for two decades in 2020, a measure of the huge stimulus pumped into the economy by the federal government. The banking system looks <strong>sound</strong> (&#x5065;&#x5168;&#xFF0C;&#x58F0;&#x97F3;&#xFF0C;&#x6709;&#x80FD;&#x529B;&#x7684;). And the economic pain is not widespread, but concentrated among workers in businesses that depend on <strong>cramming</strong> (&#x6B7B;&#x8BB0;&#x786C;&#x80CC;&#xFF0C;&#x6076;&#x8865;&#xFF0C;&#x585E;&#x6EE1;) lots of people into confined spaces. Many of them will find their services in demand again from Americans once they emerge from a year of <strong>hibernation</strong> (&#x51AC;&#x7720;&#xFF1B;&#x8FC7;&#x51AC;).</p><p>Taking advantage of how the federal government can borrow at virtually no cost, Mr Biden&#x2019;s team is set on another $1.9trn <strong>fiscal</strong> (&#x8D22;&#x653F;&#x7684;&#xFF0C;&#x56FD;&#x5E93;&#x7684;) stimulus, bringing the total budget support since the pandemic hit to 27% of pre-crisis gdp. He may not be able to get that past <u>the Senate</u> (&#x53C2;&#x8BAE;&#x9662;), nor is it clear the economy needs all of it (see <a href="https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2021/01/19/will-joe-bidens-fiscal-stimulus-overheat-the-american-economy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">article</a>). But even a trimmed-down version of the Biden opening bid&#x2014;more money for vaccine distribution, extending unemployment insurance and expanding child <u>tax credits</u> (&#x514D;&#x7A0E;&#x4F18;&#x60E0;&#x653F;&#x7B56;)&#x2014;would have big effects. The tax-credit change alone could halve (&#x51CF;&#x534A;) child poverty (see <a href="https://www.economist.com/briefing/2021/01/23/after-the-chaos-of-the-trump-era-what-can-joe-biden-hope-to-achieve" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Briefing</a>).</p><p>As for the political crisis that required 25,000 troops on the street at Mr Biden&#x2019;s <strong>inauguration</strong> (&#x5C31;&#x804C;&#x5178;&#x793C;), its causes will not soon fade. The Republican Party that became organised around a principle of loyalty to a man who has no loyalty to anything apart from himself, a dangerous <strong>coddling</strong> (&#x6EBA;&#x7231;) of racist <strong>factions</strong> (&#x6D3E;&#x7CFB;) and the rise of alternative facts: all were decades in the making. But the FBI is watching threats from domestic terrorism. The former president is just a citizen who might run for office again in 2024, assuming Congress does not <strong>bar</strong> (&#x7981;&#x6B62;) him from doing so after his <strong>impeachment trial</strong> (&#x5F39;&#x52BE;&#x5BA1;&#x5224;). And Mr Biden at his inauguration declared his clear support for the rule of law and racial equality&#x2014;which at another time might have sounded like <strong>platitudes</strong> (&#x9648;&#x8BCD;&#x6EE5;&#x8C03;&#xFF1B;&#x5E73;&#x51E1;&#xFF1B;&#x9648;&#x8150;).</p><hr><p><em>See you tomorrow</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      The Economist-The outlook for America looks grim, but that could quickly change
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/categories/English/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="每日外闻" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/%E6%AF%8F%E6%97%A5%E5%A4%96%E9%97%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="My 100-Day English" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/My-100-Day-English/"/>
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="https://steven-shixq.github.io/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
